<body id="b1">
<div id="d1">
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Con Vanh- new destination in Thai Binh</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p2">
<s id="d1p2s1">Part of the Red River Biosphere Reserve which was recognized by UNESCO in 1994, Con Vanh Ecological Tourist Site is a famous destination.</s>
<s id="d1p2s2">Con Vanh a rich mangrove forest, a picturesque landscape, pristine beaches and natural tranquility.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p3">
<s id="d1p3s1">The Con Vanh Ecological Tourist Site is located in Nam Phu commune.</s>
<s id="d1p3s2">Covering nearly 2,000 ha, it’s a relatively flat island, formed by the alluvial deposits built by the river over the years.</s>
<s id="d1p3s3">In the past, people had to row a boat to reach Con Vanh because it is 7 km from the mainland.</s>
<s id="d1p3s4">Today, travelling there is easier thanks to a road connecting the island with the mainland giving visitors a more romantic way through mangroves and casuarinas forests.</s>
<s id="d1p3s5">Con Vanh is bordered by a sandy beach of 6 km.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p4">
<s id="d1p4s1">Ta Hong Nhung is from Nghe An:“I was told that Con Vanh is a beautiful site.</s>
<s id="d1p4s2">When I came here, I found it superb.</s>
<s id="d1p4s3">The beach is clean.</s>
<s id="d1p4s4">The sand is not as white as that of other beaches but it is very smooth.</s>
<s id="d1p4s5">It's nice to swim here”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p5">
<s id="d1p5s1">Ms. Vu Thu Hien is from Quang Ninh province: “Dong Chau, Con Den and Con Vanh are the three popular tourist site in Thai Binh.</s>
<s id="d1p5s2">Beaches here are beautiful, long and sandy.</s>
<s id="d1p5s3">The landscape is imposing.</s>
<s id="d1p5s4">The air is pure and fresh.</s>
<s id="d1p5s5">It’s very relaxing”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p6">
<s id="d1p6s1">Con Vanh has a rich ecosystem.</s>
<s id="d1p6s2">Mangrove forests are inhabited by many rare birds.</s>
<s id="d1p6s3">Brackish marshes are home to more than 200 marine species and 170 species of algae.</s>
<s id="d1p6s4">Tourists can sample various local specialties: shrimp, mussels, crabs and fish.</s>
<s id="d1p6s5">Local people are very hospitable.</s>
<s id="d1p6s6">Ta Thi May, a seller of seafood on the beach:"People here are very open and friendly.</s>
<s id="d1p6s7">That’s why tourists love to come back.</s>
<s id="d1p6s8">When the sea is calm, the water is clear.</s>
<s id="d1p6s9">Each place has its own beauty.</s>
<s id="d1p6s10">There are beaches good for swimming”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p7">
<s id="d1p7s1">In Con Vanh, there are no luxury hotels or restaurants, but clean air and unspoiled nature.</s>
<s id="d1p7s2">To Quoc Huong, Vice President of the Site Management Committee: "The Con Vanh beach stretches 6.8 km.</s>
<s id="d1p7s3">It is beautiful and primitive.</s>
<s id="d1p7s4">As more and more tourists come, the site management committee has to focus on cleaning up the environment.</s>
<s id="d1p7s5">We have also designated safe areas for swimming and created an emergency and rescue service to ensure the safety of tourists.</s>
<s id="d1p7s6">The site remains intact with its forests of mangroves and casuarinas.</s>
<s id="d1p7s7">We will focus on tourism promotion to make Con Vanh an attractive destination.”</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p8">
<s id="d1p8s1">To explore wilderness, enjoy fresh air and picturesque scenery, and meet hospitable people, visit Con Vanh before it becomes a tourist mecca!</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Amateur singing in Kien Giang province</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p2">
<s id="d2p2s1">Kien Giang is an ideal place for those who want peaceful holidays.</s>
<s id="d2p2s2">It has beautiful islands and a primitive beauty.</s>
<s id="d2p2s3">Apart from the spectacular scenery and delicious cuisine, tourists should not miss the traditional amateur singing of Kien Giang.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p3">
<s id="d2p3s1">Amateur singing is usually performed by local farmers who love folk music.</s>
<s id="d2p3s2">With the same lyrics and melody, each performer has his or her way of style.</s>
<s id="d2p3s3">Researchers said it is the open and free life style of the people by the rivers that is the basis of their improvisational singing.</s>
<s id="d2p3s4">Most of the local people are descendants of the reclaimers of the southern land, thus their songs contain sad melodies reflecting nostalgia for home and memories of their origins.</s>
<s id="d2p3s5">Nguyen Thi Thuy, a member of an amateur singing club in My Lam commune, said Kien Giang has 157 clubs with nearly 1,700 members.</s>
<s id="d2p3s6">Thuy said the club was set up to meet the spiritual life of local people: “The club operates once a month and attracts the participation of many local people.</s>
<s id="d2p3s7">It helps preserve the traditional cultural values of this music style.</s>
<s id="d2p3s8">Amateur singing is typical of inhabitants of the villages along zigzagging rivers.</s>
<s id="d2p3s9">It brings pleasure to them, helping them to relax after a hard day of work”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p4">
<s id="d2p4s1">In 2013, amateur singing was recognized by UNESCO as an intangible cultural heritage of humanity.</s>
<s id="d2p4s2">This helps not only to preserve this art genre but also to encourage local amateur singing clubs to develop.</s>
<s id="d2p4s3">The 2016 amateur singing and reformed theatre festival held in Hon Dat district, Kien Giang province saw the participation of 5 troupes with more than 30 local performers.</s>
<s id="d2p4s4">The Nguyen Trung Truc festival, held on 26-28 August of the lunar calendar, welcome millions of visitors.</s>
<s id="d2p4s5">Amateur singing performances at the festivals are always highly appreciated by the audience.</s>
<s id="d2p4s6">La Van Tai, a member of an amateur singing club in Rach Gia city, said: “Our club operates very often.</s>
<s id="d2p4s7">It is a chance for the people to meet and exchange songs featuring social and cultural values”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p5">
<s id="d2p5s1">Amateur singing is a form of entertainment unique for the Mekong River delta.</s>
<s id="d2p5s2">Nguyen Thu Huong is a tourist from Hai Duong province: “Kien Giang province has many tourist attractions.</s>
<s id="d2p5s3">Apart from its beautiful scenery, the amateur singing is the thing that interests tourists”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p6">
<s id="d2p6s1">Amateur singing has existed and developed along with the life of people in Kien Giang.</s>
<s id="d2p6s2">It is an indispensible part of the spiritual life of the people there.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Exploring Ha Tien township in Kien Giang province</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p2">
<s id="d3p2s1">Ha Tien is a small township in Kien Giang province.</s>
<s id="d3p2s2">Its 22 km coastline borders the Gulf of Thailand.</s>
<s id="d3p2s3">Ha Tien boasts magnificent landscapes which attracts lots of tourists.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p3">
<s id="d3p3s1">In the middle of the 17th century, Ha Tien was a deserted region.</s>
<s id="d3p3s2">But from the 18thcentury, it became a busy commercial port.</s>
<s id="d3p3s3">In 1714, Mac Kinh Cuu explored the land and offered it to the Nguyen Lord, who later named the land Ha Tien.</s>
<s id="d3p3s4">At that time, Ha Tien covered the whole of Kien Giang province and some adjacent areas.</s>
<s id="d3p3s5">Local historian Truong Minh Dat said: “The word Ha Tien derives from Ha meaning river and Tien meaning fairy.</s>
<s id="d3p3s6">Ha Tien means a river where fairies come to bathe on the full-moon day”,</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p4">
<s id="d3p4s1">Ha Tien has become famous for several beauty spots including Dong Ho swamp, a place isolated from modern urban life.</s>
<s id="d3p4s2">The swamp is surrounded with a range of coconut trees.</s>
<s id="d3p4s3">Mui Nai village, 5 km from Ha Tien downtown is home to the most beautiful beach in Kien Giang province and attracts visitors because of the peaceful waves and beach that inspires visitors to cover themselves with sand to absorb its minerals into their skin.</s>
<s id="d3p4s4">Not far from Mui Nai are other beautiful spots such as Thach Dong Cave, Chong islet, and Hang pagoda.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p5">
<s id="d3p5s1">About 5 km from Ha Tien, Thach Dong mountain is uniquely shaped.</s>
<s id="d3p5s2">It is 90m above sea level and has a circumference of 45m.</s>
<s id="d3p5s3">Inside the mountain is Tien Son pagoda, which was built of wood in 1790.</s>
<s id="d3p5s4">From the mountain side, visitors shave a panoramic view of Ha Tien township.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p6">
<s id="d3p6s1">With its beautiful, peaceful landscape and rich culture, Ha Tien is a special attraction in the southern region.</s>
<s id="d3p6s2">Dao Thi Nuong, a tourist, says she loves the fresh air and tranquility of Ha Tien: “Ha Tien is also a destination for pilgrims.</s>
<s id="d3p6s3">From Ha Tien, we can go straight to Phu Quoc and Cambodia.</s>
<s id="d3p6s4">These three regions can be incorporated to establish a tourist route of the sea and islands, different from that of other 9 Mekong Delta provinces”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p7">
<s id="d3p7s1">Ha Tien is a meeting place for generations of southerners.</s>
<s id="d3p7s2">Despite the influx of tourism, the lives of the locals remain undisturbed and the town retains its peacefulness.</s>
<s id="d3p7s3">Ms Nuong again: “Ha Tien is different from other tourist places.</s>
<s id="d3p7s4">It has the sea, mountains and estuaries which are the advantages for developing tourism”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p8">
<s id="d3p8s1">The number of tourists to Ha Tien has increased.</s>
<s id="d3p8s2">With its unspoiled nature, rich culture and hospitable people, Ha Tien is undoubtedly a popular tourist destination in southern Vietnam.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d4">
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">Kien Giang, a destination of National Tourism Year 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p2">
<s id="d4p2s1">Kien Giang province in southwestern Vietnam is one of the best places to explore the Mekong River Delta.</s>
<s id="d4p2s2">Blessed by nature, Kien Giang is home to the beautiful scenery of Ha Tien and Phu Quoc island and historically famous spots like Chong islet, Chem islet, Phu Tu islet, Mui Nai beach, and U Minh forest.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p3">
<s id="d4p3s1">Kien Giang province has greater tourist potential than most of the other Mekong Delta provinces.</s>
<s id="d4p3s2">It has become a popular destination for tourists who want to experience historical, cultural, ecological, and marine tourism.</s>
<s id="d4p3s3">This year, the province is hosting the National Tourism Year 2016 with the theme “Phu Quoc- Mekong River Delta- Exploring the Southern Land”.</s>
<s id="d4p3s4">Tourist activities scheduled throughout this year will to promote tourism potential, advantages and products of Kien Giang and nearby provinces.</s>
<s id="d4p3s5">Tran Chi Dung is Director of Kien Giang’s Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism: “This year, we want to attract more foreign tourists.</s>
<s id="d4p3s6">We’re creating more tours to boost local tourism”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p4">
<s id="d4p4s1">Kien Giang is one of Vietnam’s 28 coastal cities and provinces.</s>
<s id="d4p4s2">Its sea covers more than 63,000 square kilometers and its coast is about 200 km.</s>
<s id="d4p4s3">The province has 143 islands, 43 of them inhabited.</s>
<s id="d4p4s4">These islands and their beautiful beaches represent a great potential for ecological and marine tourism.</s>
<s id="d4p4s5">Phu Quoc is a popular destination.</s>
<s id="d4p4s6">Its famous beaches include Truong, Dai, and Hon Thom.</s>
<s id="d4p4s7">Iris Bijlisma is a tourist from the Netherlands: “This is really rare on Earth.</s>
<s id="d4p4s8">I think I have never seen such a beautiful place”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p5">
<s id="d4p5s1">Phu Quoc island has some primal forests with a rich system of fauna and flora.</s>
<s id="d4p5s2">The forests with their multiple streams and lakes provide fresh water for the residents.</s>
<s id="d4p5s3">The wild natural forests and romantic sea give Phu Quoc an impressive beauty.</s>
<s id="d4p5s4">Huynh Quang Hung, Deputy Chairman of the Phu Quoc People’s Committee, says there are many projects to upgrade Phu Quoc’s tourism infrastructure.</s>
<s id="d4p5s5">Once they are completed, Phu Quoc will be able to accommodate more tourists and host major national events.</s>
<s id="d4p5s6">Hung said: “We hope that the number of visitors to Phu Quoc will increase sharply this year because of the activities we have organized for National Tourism Year.</s>
<s id="d4p5s7">Many new luxury resorts open this year”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p6">
<s id="d4p6s1">Kien Giang province has many national historical relics and scenic spots including Hang pagoda, Nguyen Trung Truc Communal House in Rach Gia, the Mui Nai relic site, Thach Dong Cave and the Phu Quoc Church.</s>
<s id="d4p6s2">U Minh Thuong National Park in Kien Giang province was recognized this year as the 8th Ramsar Site in Vietnam and the 2,228th Ramsar Site in the world.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">Da Lat- A city of flowers</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p2">
<s id="d5p2s1">Da Lat city in the central highlands province of Lam Dong is called with different names due to its romantic beauty such as “Little Paris”, “City of Pine Forests”, “Land of Mist”... Da Lat’s flowers, lakes and waterfalls attract tourists near and far.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p3">
<s id="d5p3s1">In recent years, Da Lat has been known as the city of Flower Festival.</s>
<s id="d5p3s2">Since it was organized for the first time in 2005, the biennial festival has attracted a large number of tourists.</s>
<s id="d5p3s3">During the 5-day Da Lat Flower Festival held early this month, more than 500,000 tourists came to Da Lat.</s>
<s id="d5p3s4">Chairman of Da Lat Municipal People’s Committee Vo Ngoc Hiep said the Da Lat inspired visitors for its romantic beauty, charm and peace.</s>
<s id="d5p3s5">Hiep said in addition to promoting the beauty of Da Lat, the Flower Festival introduced the visitors to the city’s floriculture and other local specialties.</s>
<s id="d5p3s6">Hiep said:“The festival honors the work of horticulturists who perpetuate the iconic art of the city.</s>
<s id="d5p3s7">The festival created an opportunity to promote Da Lat tourism potential illustrated in flowers, tea, and coffee.</s>
<s id="d5p3s8">Promoting tourism will boost the city’s economic growth”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p4">
<s id="d5p4s1">Nestled at 1,500 meters above sea level, Da Lat is quiet and pretty all year with mild climate and temperatures oscillating between 15 and 24 degrees.</s>
<s id="d5p4s2">In Da Lat, the climate changes along the day enabling tourists to experience 4 seasons a day.</s>
<s id="d5p4s3">Da Lat embraces typical natural and cultural features of the Central Highlands.</s>
<s id="d5p4s4">Nguyen Van Huong, former Director of the Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism of Lam Dong province says Da Lat authorities and people hope to promote Da Lat as a City of Flower Festival: “By planting flowers and trees around the city and in every house, especially in tourist places, we want to create a unique beauty for the city.</s>
<s id="d5p4s5">We want to encourage everyone in the city to engage in planting trees and flowers in front of houses, offices and tourist places’</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p5">
<s id="d5p5s1">The Da Lat Flower Festival mobilized the participation of local authorities, enterprises, and the public.</s>
<s id="d5p5s2">Dang Bao Vinh is a florist in Thai Phien horticulture village: “There are three horticultural villages in Da Lat: Ha Dong, Van Thanh and Thai Phien.</s>
<s id="d5p5s3">Each of them has its own beauty.</s>
<s id="d5p5s4">Van Thanh village specializes in planting roses.</s>
<s id="d5p5s5">Thai Phien village grows varieties of chrysanthemums”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p6">
<s id="d5p6s1">In addition to its famous chrysanthemums, Thai Phien also offers eustomas and lilies.</s>
<s id="d5p6s2">320 out of 400 hectares of horticulture land are devoted to greenhouses.</s>
<s id="d5p6s3">Thai Phien is the largest horticulture village in Da Lat.</s>
<s id="d5p6s4">Horticulturists have fully taken advantage of technological advances and installed lighting systems and latest generation of watering.</s>
<s id="d5p6s5">Visiting Van Thanh village, tourists are introduced to horticulture methods and flower harvest.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p7">
<s id="d5p7s1">Feel free to visit the greenhouses and ask for exploring a wide variety of flowers.</s>
<s id="d5p7s2">There you can also experience a working day of a horticulturist.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">Visiting Son La</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p2">
<s id="d6p2s1">Located 300 km northwest of Hanoi, Son La province has become a popular tourist destination in recent years because of its various ethnicities, festivals, historical relics and scenic spots.</s>
<s id="d6p2s2">Son La Museum, the Son La Hydro Power Plant, and hot springs in Mong villages, and peach blossoms, apricot and bauhinia flowers inspire tourists near and far.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p3">
<s id="d6p3s1">There are more than 100 historical and cultural relics in Son La of which Son La prison and Son La museum are the most popular.</s>
<s id="d6p3s2">Classified as a national relic in 1962, Son La prison is perched atop Khau Ca hill.</s>
<s id="d6p3s3">Covering an area of 500 m2, Son La prison was built in 1908 by the French colonialists to imprison Vietnamese communists.</s>
<s id="d6p3s4">Known as hell on earth, its cells were built with solid stones and its high walls were covered with barbed wires and broken glass.</s>
<s id="d6p3s5">Despite the barbaric tortures, Vietnamese communist soldiers turned their cells hell into a place to communicate Vietnam’s resolution.</s>
<s id="d6p3s6">The prison has recently been renovated and become a tourist mecca in the northwestern region.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p4">
<s id="d6p4s1">Son La Museum was also built in 1908 by the French.</s>
<s id="d6p4s2">There, distinctive cultures of 12 local ethnic minority groups in the province can be discovered through thousands of pre-history artifacts.</s>
<s id="d6p4s3">Collections of 1,000 books, documents, epics, and folk tales and songs of the Thai and Dao ethnicities are kept at the museum.</s>
<s id="d6p4s4">Nguyen Hai Duong is a guide at the museum: “Covering 14,000 square kilometers, Son La province has 12 ethnic communities, 55% of them are Thai minorities.</s>
<s id="d6p4s5">These are ancient books of the Thai in Son La who have valuable expertise in paper-making from bamboo fiber and other plants.</s>
<s id="d6p4s6">Their books are divided into three main categories: literature, history and belief”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p5">
<s id="d6p5s1">The Son La Hydro Power Plant is also an attractive destination in the city.</s>
<s id="d6p5s2">Surrounded by a verdant forest, Son La Reservoir impresses visitors with its incomparable beauty.</s>
<s id="d6p5s3">Hoang Lan, a tourist from Bac Giang province, shares her emotions: “This is the first time I visit the lake.</s>
<s id="d6p5s4">Nestled in the heart of magnificent nature, it is an ideal place to relax.</s>
<s id="d6p5s5">I would like to come back to discover more about local people’s life”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p6">
<s id="d6p6s1">Hidden in a mountain range, Mong village in Hua La commune, 6km from the center of Son La, is also a tourist destination.</s>
<s id="d6p6s2">Nguyen Hong Thang, a tour guide from Hanoi said:“In Mong village, tourists relax in hot springs and enjoy Thai cuisine.</s>
<s id="d6p6s3">Water in hot springs here can be used as a medical therapy or a drink.</s>
<s id="d6p6s4">After having a bathe, you can stay in guest houses and savor delicious Thai dishes”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p7">
<s id="d6p7s1">Seeing is believing.</s>
<s id="d6p7s2">Go and explore the wide nature by yourself!</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d7">
<p id="d7p1">
<s id="d7p1s1">A day in Moc Chau</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p2">
<s id="d7p2s1">About 200 km from Hanoi, there is a paradise where you can enjoy fresh air and unspoiled vistas.</s>
<s id="d7p2s2">Join us on a tour of Moc Chau plateau today.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p3">
<s id="d7p3s1">Waking up in a container bungalow in the middle of a green tea field surrounded by a panorama peaceful and green is a great experience, isn’t it?</s>
<s id="d7p3s2">Pham Thanh Tam had this experience recently at the ecotourism site of Moc Chau Village.</s>
<s id="d7p3s3">She said: "I love the fresh morning air in Moc Chau.</s>
<s id="d7p3s4">There is no pollution.</s>
<s id="d7p3s5">Stress and fatigue disappear immediately when you wake up in a completely quiet environment.</s>
<s id="d7p3s6">Breathe clean fresh air, walk between tea bushes, pick buds and taste a cup of tea you prepared yourself.</s>
<s id="d7p3s7">What is better?”</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p4">
<s id="d7p4s1">Leaving the tea hills, you arrive in the village of Ang in Dong Sang commune, Moc Chau district, where pine trees are mirrored in lakes covering about 5 hectares.</s>
<s id="d7p4s2">It’s a paradise for anybody looking for serenity and some beautiful photo opts.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p5">
<s id="d7p5s1">Ang village also attracts visitors who want to explore the unique architecture of houses on stilts, traditional customs and the delicious local cuisine.</s>
<s id="d7p5s2">Vu Mai Khanh is with the Khanh Sinh travel agency: "Our tours promote ecotourism and cultural tourism.</s>
<s id="d7p5s3">We offer tours of relaxation and discovery of local life.</s>
<s id="d7p5s4">These programs allow you to better understand the customs of ethnic minorities living in Moc Chau, the Thai, Mong and others and participate in their songs and dances, including the pole dance, a cultural specialty of the Thai”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p6">
<s id="d7p6s1">In the afternoon, you can walk along a path past mustard flower meadows to visit the Moc Chau farm.</s>
<s id="d7p6s2">Feel free to feed the cows and try your hand at milking.</s>
<s id="d7p6s3">Moc Chau milk is one of the local specialties.</s>
<s id="d7p6s4">Phung Luu Ly is Head of the Culture Division of Moc Chau District: "There are many agricultural products in Moc Chau that tourists can buy as gifts.</s>
<s id="d7p6s5">They are dairy products, green tea, organic fruits and vegetables and you will not be disappointed with their quality.</s>
<s id="d7p6s6">Plums are the iconic fruit of Moc Chau and you will find in the market plum jam, plum wine, and plum syrup.</s>
<s id="d7p6s7">Plum pickings are organized by tour operators during the harvest”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p7">
<s id="d7p7s1">At nightfall, Moc Chau is covered with a fine mist canvas.</s>
<s id="d7p7s2">It's time to join the dances and songs of ethnic minorities.</s>
<s id="d7p7s3">When you leave this wonderland, be sure to bring back some of the local products.</s>
<s id="d7p7s4">They are sure to delight your pals.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d8">
<p id="d8p1">
<s id="d8p1s1">Peaceful Tha village</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p2">
<s id="d8p2s1">Quiet, authentic, picturesque – Tha village is well known among tourists for its charm and peaceful beauty.</s>
<s id="d8p2s2">Located just 2km from Ha Giang, Tha village stands out for its stilt houses, green bamboo groves and lush rice fields.</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p3">
<s id="d8p3s1">Tha village offers a gentle beauty far from the urban hubbub.</s>
<s id="d8p3s2">The murmur of limpid streams and a flirting wind in the palms welcome you at the village entrance.</s>
<s id="d8p3s3">Then you enter a mysteriously region submerged all year round in a mist, a lush forest floor, where centuries-old values are still present.</s>
<s id="d8p3s4">Here you will come across no trace of modernity, no multi-storey buildings, and no vehicles.</s>
<s id="d8p3s5">Nguyen Van Nhuong lives in the village: "I prefer the wooden houses on stilts to concrete housing.</s>
<s id="d8p3s6">Building a house on stilts costs about 300 million VND but it's worth it because it is very comfortable and airy throughout the year.</s>
<s id="d8p3s7">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p4">
<s id="d8p4s1">Here in the village you can take an actual breath of fresh air and enjoy the warm hospitality of the people.</s>
<s id="d8p4s2">The Tay people are very warm and welcoming.</s>
<s id="d8p4s3">If a stranger invites you to drink a cup of tea or offers her prettiest smile, do not be surprised.</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p5">
<s id="d8p5s1">Tay people still weave brocade products like bags, scarves, skirts, and pants.</s>
<s id="d8p5s2">For a closer experience of Tay life, spend a night with the locals.</s>
<s id="d8p5s3">In addition to a taste of their corn alcohol, you will have the chance to savor their many culinary specialties: fish with fermented bamboo shoots, chicken salad, grilled pork with bamboo and wild vegetables.</s>
<s id="d8p5s4">The Tay cook very well.</s>
<s id="d8p5s5">Mai Thi Chung lives in Tha village: “Tourists are impressed by our hospitality and the customs we fiercely preserve over time.</s>
<s id="d8p5s6">We offer our best recipes to tourists.</s>
<s id="d8p5s7">We grill meat on the pan - our best dishes served at Tay parties.</s>
<s id="d8p5s8">These dishes are prepared using lots of special spices, such as cardamom, basil, pepper, and shrimp paste”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p6">
<s id="d8p6s1">After dinner, tourists can experience Then singing, the intangible heritage all generations of Tay perpetuate.</s>
<s id="d8p6s2">A singer improvises lyrics of his song while playing a kind of guitar called a Tinh other while artists perform graceful dances.</s>
<s id="d8p6s3">Everything is in harmony like a painting of life in paradise.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d9">
<p id="d9p1">
<s id="d9p1s1">Hue- a romantic city</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p2">
<s id="d9p2s1">From 1558 to 1945, Hue was the imperial capital city of 9 Nguyen Lords, the Tay Son regime and 13 Nguyen dynasties.</s>
<s id="d9p2s2">During those 4 centuries, Hue became an extensive complex of unique architectural and cultural relics.</s>
<s id="d9p2s3">In 1993, the Hue imperial complex was recognized by UNESCO as a World Cultural Heritage Site.</s>
<s id="d9p2s4">The city has become a mecca of Vietnamese tourism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p3">
<s id="d9p3s1">On the northern bank of the Huong river in the middle of the city, the magnificent imperial citadel emerges, exhibiting the power of the Nguyen dynasty.</s>
<s id="d9p3s2">The citadel’s royal palaces, monuments and beautiful landscaping retain their imperial solemnity.</s>
<s id="d9p3s3">The Hue imperial city comprises the Imperial Citadel and the Purple Forbidden City which are surrounded by wide moats.</s>
<s id="d9p3s4">Several buildings were the headquarters of the monarchy and shrines dedicated to kings.</s>
<s id="d9p3s5">The Forbidden Purple City was reserved exclusively for the royal family and concubines.</s>
<s id="d9p3s6">Only eunuchs could enter.</s>
<s id="d9p3s7">The Imperial Citadel’s design was inspired by Oriental philosophy and Vietnamese tradition.</s>
<s id="d9p3s8">All the structures were built around a main axis.</s>
<s id="d9p3s9">The citadel has four main gates, the south door (Ngo Mon) was exclusively reserved for the emperor.</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p4">
<s id="d9p4s1">When you're in Hue, you should also visit the majestic tombs of the Nguyen Kings that lie west of the Imperial Citadel.</s>
<s id="d9p4s2">Located on hills, along the Perfume River, these tombs are typical of Vietnamese architecture, but each reflects the personality and taste of the Emperor.</s>
<s id="d9p4s3">A large part of Hue’s attractiveness is owed to its beautiful Perfume River and Ngu Binh mountain.</s>
<s id="d9p4s4">Nguyen Xuan Hoa is a Hue resident: “The Perfume River is a natural wonder of Hue city.</s>
<s id="d9p4s5">It has rare a romantic beauty.</s>
<s id="d9p4s6">Its green waters meander across the plains, through forests and villages like a silk band before entering the Tam Giang Lagoon".</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p5">
<s id="d9p5s1">Touring the Perfume River by boat is a wonderful experience.</s>
<s id="d9p5s2">You will enjoy the beautiful sights of the city while listening to royal court music and local folk songs.</s>
<s id="d9p5s3">Truong Tien Bridge over the Perfume River is another iconic landmark of Hue.</s>
<s id="d9p5s4">Built between 1897 and 1899, it was one of the first bridges built by the French in Indochina.</s>
<s id="d9p5s5">This beautiful bridge and the Perfume River have been a great source of inspiration for poets and songwriters.</s>
<s id="d9p5s6">Phan Thuan An has researched Hue culture for several years: "For Hue people, Truong Tien Bridge is the primary architectural site of the city and the most beautiful one.</s>
<s id="d9p5s7">The bridge is strongly imprinted in Hue people’s hearts”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p6">
<s id="d9p6s1">Today, the Hue imperial city is also known as a festival city because of its biennial festival which attracts top Vietnamese and foreign performing artists.</s>
<s id="d9p6s2">Authentic architecture, romantic landscapes, and delicate gastronomy make Hue city worth a visit!</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d10">
<p id="d10p1">
<s id="d10p1s1">Bai Dinh pagoda- a tourist destination</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p2">
<s id="d10p2s1">Located in Ninh Binh province, 95 km south of Hanoi, Bai Dinh pagoda has become a popular tourist destination in recent years.</s>
<s id="d10p2s2">The pagoda complex holds several Vietnamese records.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p3">
<s id="d10p3s1">The ancient Bai Dinh pagoda sits 187m above sea level on top of Dinh Mountain.</s>
<s id="d10p3s2">Dating back over a thousand years, it is oriented towards the west and flanked by two caves.</s>
<s id="d10p3s3">The pagoda nestles into one cave, which is not uncommon among old pagodas in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d10p3s4">To get to the pagoda, you have to climb 300 steps.</s>
<s id="d10p3s5">Do Ngoc Anh is a tour guide: "There’s a cave called Enlightened Cave.</s>
<s id="d10p3s6">King Le Thanh Tong engraved ideograms there praising the beauty of the site.</s>
<s id="d10p3s7">The ceiling of the cave forms the solid roof of the pagoda which is dedicated to the Buddha and the Mother Goddess.</s>
<s id="d10p3s8">The altar in the cave is decorated with traditional Buddha statues”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p4">
<s id="d10p4s1">At the bottom of Enlightened Cave is a large exit which offers a great view of a distant green valley.</s>
<s id="d10p4s2">About 1 km from Bai Dinh pagoda is the complex of a new pagoda.</s>
<s id="d10p4s3">The new pagoda sits on Ba Dau hillside, overlooking Dam lake and the Hoang Long River.</s>
<s id="d10p4s4">500 Arhat statues flank the two paths that lead from the main gate to the shrine.</s>
<s id="d10p4s5">These paths which are about 1,700m long symbolize the Arhats’ path to Buddhism.</s>
<s id="d10p4s6">They are the longest Arhat paths in Asia.</s>
<s id="d10p4s7">Do Ngoc Anh: "The statues of Arhats were carved from blue stone by the artisans of Ninh Binh province.</s>
<s id="d10p4s8">Each statue is between 2 and 2.5 meters tall and weighs 2 to 2.5 ton.</s>
<s id="d10p4s9">They are placed on both sides of the path to guide the common people to the light of Buddhism.</s>
<s id="d10p4s10">The statues have different forms and different expressions reflecting all human moods: joy, anger, satisfaction, frustration.</s>
<s id="d10p4s11">At the foot of each statue is the name of the Arhat”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p5">
<s id="d10p5s1">The new Bai Dinh pagoda is a giant complex that extends from the main entrance to the sanctuary of Shakyamuni Buddha, the bell tower and the shrine to Kwan Yi, Buddhism’s Lady of Mercy.</s>
<s id="d10p5s2">The bell tower is built on three levels.</s>
<s id="d10p5s3">Octagonal in shape, it houses a 36-ton bronze bell which is the largest in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d10p5s4">Just below the bell is a 70-ton bronze drum.</s>
<s id="d10p5s5">Local people believe that where they can still hear the sound of the bell, they are under the blessing of the Buddha.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p6">
<s id="d10p6s1">The bronze statues of Kwan Yi and Shakyamuni Buddha are also the biggest ones in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d10p6s2">The sanctuary of the past, present and future Buddha houses three huge statues of the three temporal forms of the Buddha.</s>
<s id="d10p6s3">Vu Anh Quan, a tourist from Dalat, is impressed by their size: “I had already seen those statues on TV and I knew they were enormous.</s>
<s id="d10p6s4">But the reality is far more spectacular.</s>
<s id="d10p6s5">These statues are gold showing their majestic and splendid side.</s>
<s id="d10p6s6">I am not surprised to learn that they hold the record for Vietnam’s largest statues of the Buddha, past, present, and future”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p7">
<s id="d10p7s1">The 6th day of the first lunar month is the main day of the pilgrimage feast of Bai Dinh pagoda.</s>
<s id="d10p7s2">Tens of thousands of pilgrims flock to the pagoda to pay homage to the Buddha and visit this great site.</s>
<s id="d10p7s3">Lai Ngoc Nga is a pilgrim: "I make a pilgrimage to Bai Dinh pagoda every year.</s>
<s id="d10p7s4">This is a sacred place and we do not feel tired even after walking for many kilometers.</s>
<s id="d10p7s5">I always pray for health and luck for my family”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p8">
<s id="d10p8s1">Bai Dinh is a major attraction of Ninh Binh province, along with the Hoa Lu ancient capital, the Tam Coc-Bich Dong caves and Cuc Phuong National Park.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d11">
<p id="d11p1">
<s id="d11p1s1">Tam Coc-Bich Dong’s charming scenery</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p2">
<s id="d11p2s1">Located 120 km from Hanoi, Tam Coc-Bich Dong is part of the Hoa Lu limestone mountain range.</s>
<s id="d11p2s2">For hundreds of years, the place has preserved the primitive beauty that has attracted countless visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p3">
<s id="d11p3s1">The Tam Coc complex includes Tam Coc and Bich Dong, which are situated in Van Lam village, Hoa Lu district, Ninh Binh province.</s>
<s id="d11p3s2">Recognized as a special national heritage, Tam Coc is often called ‘Ha Long Bay on the land’ for its system of limestone grottoes and historical relics from the Tran dynasty in the 13th and 14thcentury.</s>
<s id="d11p3s3">To reach Tam Coc, you must board a small boat at the wharf and get rowed up the sinuous Ngo Dong River past Xuyen Thuy cave and pockets of rice fields.</s>
<s id="d11p3s4">Do Thi Nu, a local boat pilot, talked to us about Tam Coc’s history: “In Chinese, ‘Tam’ means three and ‘Coc’ means cave, so ‘Tam Coc’ means three caves.</s>
<s id="d11p3s5">In Vietnamese, it is called ‘Ba hang’.</s>
<s id="d11p3s6">Hang Ca is the first cave, ‘hang Hai’ is the second cave, and ‘hang Ba’ is the third cave.</s>
<s id="d11p3s7">It takes 2 hours to visit all three caves.”</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p4">
<s id="d11p4s1">Tam Coc is charmingly beautiful in any season.</s>
<s id="d11p4s2">In spring, bright green rice fields spread along the river banks, turning into silky yellow beds in the fourth lunar month.</s>
<s id="d11p4s3">In the summer while traveling on the Ngo Dong River, visitors will enjoy an enticing lotus fragrance while listening to the locals recounting legends about each cliff or mountain in the shape of a tortoise or dragon head.</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p5">
<s id="d11p5s1">There are particularly interesting rock formations, and schools of fish swimming in crystal clear water, but undoubtedly the most impressive features of Tam Coc are the caves, according to tour guide Nguyen Xuan Nguyen: “Hang Ca is the first cave and the largest of the 3.</s>
<s id="d11p5s2">It is 127 meters long and its mouth is 20 meters wide.</s>
<s id="d11p5s3">Many stalactites hang down from the ceiling, some of which look like clouds and some of which drip water all day and are compared to a mother’s breast.</s>
<s id="d11p5s4">The cave looks very dark from the outside, but the further you go into it, the brighter it is.”</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p6">
<s id="d11p6s1">The beauty of Tam Coc is the beauty of the 3 caves with the Ngo Dong River running through them.</s>
<s id="d11p6s2">The second cave, Hang Giua, which is about 10 minutes from the first cave, has a length of 60 meters and a multitude of flat, horizontal stalactites.</s>
<s id="d11p6s3">The third and final cave, Hang Cuoi, is the smallest.</s>
<s id="d11p6s4">It is about 50 meters in length and is only 100 meters from the second cave.</s>
<s id="d11p6s5">Its geology suggests this place was under the sea millions of years ago.</s>
<s id="d11p6s6">The land emerged gradually over centuries and waves eroded the limestone mountains to form grottoes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p7">
<s id="d11p7s1">After the 2-hour excursion returns you to Tam Coc wharf and go an additional 2 km to Bich Dong, considered the second most beautiful cave in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d11p7s2">The Bich Dong area consists of a cave and a pagoda built on a limestone hill in 1428 under King Le Thai To.</s>
<s id="d11p7s3">Ms.</s>
<s id="d11p7s4">Nguyen again: “Bich Dong pagoda is composed of 3 structures: Ha Pagoda (lower pagoda), Trung Pagoda (Middle pagoda), and Thuong Pagoda (upper pagoda).</s>
<s id="d11p7s5">In 1740, King Le Canh Hung named the pagoda ‘Bach ngoc thach son dong’ which means pagoda made of beautiful stones like a sapphire in a remote place.</s>
<s id="d11p7s6">‘Bich Dong’ means “green grotto”, a name given by Nguyen Nghiem, the father of the great poet Nguyen Du, in 1773.”</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p8">
<s id="d11p8s1">After praying to Buddha in Bich Dong Pagoda, visitors climb 21 stone steps to Toi cave (Dark cave) whose stalactites are shaped like fairies, errand-boys, hovering dragons, swimming tortoises, elephants, and tigers.</s>
<s id="d11p8s2">40 more steps take you to go to the Upper Pagoda, from where you can enjoy the best views of Bich Dong.</s>
<s id="d11p8s3">The view has strongly impressed foreigners like Monttie Binotto from Switzerland.</s>
<s id="d11p8s4">“This is my first time visiting this place, which is known for its cultural and historical tradition.</s>
<s id="d11p8s5">Tam Coc-Bich Dong is favored by nature with friendly people and charming landscapes.</s>
<s id="d11p8s6">I want to stay here for two or three days to fully explore it.</s>
<s id="d11p8s7">I’m impressed by the smiles of boat drivers who can row the boats with their legs.</s>
<s id="d11p8s8">I don’t think I can see these things anywhere else.”</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d12">
<p id="d12p1">
<s id="d12p1s1">Hanoi gates</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p2">
<s id="d12p2s1">Hanoi once had five gates which strongly embodied its historical developments.</s>
<s id="d12p2s2">The beauty of these gates features in several songs about Hanoi.</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p3">
<s id="d12p3s1">According to historical records, there was a wall with gates surrounding the Thang Long citadel.</s>
<s id="d12p3s2">The gates were square and were under strict surveillance.</s>
<s id="d12p3s3">They were open during the day and closed at night.</s>
<s id="d12p3s4">In King Le Hien Tong’s reign in the 18thcentury, there were 16 square gates, but by the early 20th century, there were only 5 gates: Cau Giay, Cau Den, Cho Dua, Dong Mac and Quan Chuong.</s>
<s id="d12p3s5">Some gates were pulled down because of war damage, but their names lived on as the names of districts or streets: Cau Giay district, O Dong Mac ward, O Cau Den ward and O Cho Dua ward.</s>
<s id="d12p3s6">Today, only the Quan Chuong gate survives as a proper "square gate”.</s>
<s id="d12p3s7">Quan Chuong gate on Hang Chieu street, Hoan Kiem district, was part of the wall east of the ancient Thang Long citadel.</s>
<s id="d12p3s8">Covered with moss, the gate and part of the wall have survived the ravages of time.</s>
<s id="d12p3s9">On the gate there is a sign that says " Dong Ha gate” but local people prefer to call it "Quan Chuong Gate." Historian Duong Trung Quoc told VOV: "Quan Chuong is the only entrance to the city that retains its original architecture.</s>
<s id="d12p3s10">There is a stele dating back to the Nguyen Dynasty in 19th century, which states that surveillance should be strict without disturbing the life of the people.</s>
<s id="d12p3s11">Why was the gate named Quan Chuong?</s>
<s id="d12p3s12">It might be the name of a chief guard, who was so loved by the locals that they gave histitle to the entrance gate he guarded”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p4">
<s id="d12p4s1">Other historical sources say people called the gate Quan Chuong which means chief guard, to honor the Chief guard who led a hundred soldiers in a brave fight against the French in 1873, when they attacked Hanoi for the first time through this gate.</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p5">
<s id="d12p5s1">Quan Chuong gate exhibits a typical architecture of the Nguyen Dynasty.</s>
<s id="d12p5s2">It consists of two levels, the lower level has three arched doorways and the upper level is covered by 4 roofs decorated with a motif of hexagonal or quadrilateral asterisks.</s>
<s id="d12p5s3">The guards were stationed on the upper level.</s>
<s id="d12p5s4">Today, Quan Chuong gate exists as a page of history at the heart of Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d12p5s5">Truong Van Khanh lives near Quan Chuong gate: "We are proud to live in the neighborhood of Quan Chuong gate which has existed for centuries.</s>
<s id="d12p5s6">We hope it will be restored and preserved.</s>
<s id="d12p5s7">It is a witness of Vietnamese culture and tradition of struggle”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p6">
<s id="d12p6s1">Quan Chuong gate was restored in 1804 and again in 1817, during the reign of King Gia Long.</s>
<s id="d12p6s2">In 1994, it was officially recognized as a historic relic site.</s>
<s id="d12p6s3">In 2010, it was restored once again.</s>
<s id="d12p6s4">For Hanoians, Quan Chuong gate is not just a relic of the ancient Thang Long capital but a proud symbol of the modern capital city.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d13">
<p id="d13p1">
<s id="d13p1s1">Visiting Yen Tu pagoda</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p2">
<s id="d13p2s1">The Yen Tu historical site stretches 20 km along Phuong Dong and Yen Cong communes in Uong Bi town of Quang Ninh province.</s>
<s id="d13p2s2">Nestled in the magnificent landscape, Yen Tu mountain is famous for the Bronze pagoda, which sits 1,068 m above sea level.</s>
<s id="d13p2s3">This tourist complex comprises pagodas, temples, towers and perennial forest.</s>
<s id="d13p2s4">Today Discovery Vietnam takes you on a tour of Yen Tu.</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p3">
<s id="d13p3s1">In spring and summer many pilgrims go to Yen Tu to pay homage to Buddha.</s>
<s id="d13p3s2">Yen Tu, nestled in the middle of ancient pine trees is a special place, enjoying a deep stillness that allows visitors to forget about their daily cares.</s>
<s id="d13p3s3">Yen Tu is where several Venerable monks of the Ly and Tran dynasties including Hien Quang, Dao Van and the Most Venerable Tran Nhan Tong and Tran Thanh Tong, practiced Buddhism.</s>
<s id="d13p3s4">After ceding his throne to his son, King Tran Nhan Tong (1258-1308) retired to lead a religious life as a hermit.</s>
<s id="d13p3s5">He founded the Truc Lam Zen sect and this place became the largest Vietnamese center of Buddhism.</s>
<s id="d13p3s6">The Most Venerable Thich Tue Phuc, Deputy Manager of the Truc Lam Yen Tu pagoda, says: “Yen Tu pagoda is closely associated with Truc Lam Zen.</s>
<s id="d13p3s7">In the 14th century, King Tran Nhan Tong, 3rd King of the Tran Dynasty, gave the throne to his son Anh Tong.</s>
<s id="d13p3s8">6 years later, at the age of 41, Tong moved to Yen Tu, where he founded the current Truc Lam Zen sect, a Buddhist sect that is purely Vietnamese”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p4">
<s id="d13p4s1">The Venerable Thich Tue Phuc says that in the summer, Yen Tu attracts not only pilgrims but also students who want to learn Buddhism:“Zen Buddhism is a branch whose main practice is meditation.</s>
<s id="d13p4s2">During their summer vacation, students are sent here to discover Buddhism, while perfecting their morality to become good citizens”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p5">
<s id="d13p5s1">Formerly, to reach the summit, there was no choice but to climb the stairs and steep paths for two hours, which requires a good deal of motivation.</s>
<s id="d13p5s2">Today, pilgrims can take a cable car up to the pagoda in less than an hour.</s>
<s id="d13p5s3">Le Trong Thanh, Deputy Director of the Tung Lam Cable Car Company, says: “On the weekend, the number of visitors increases sharply.</s>
<s id="d13p5s4">Our company tries to ensure the best services for visitors, guiding them to pagodas and temples”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p6">
<s id="d13p6s1">Many tourists prefer to walk up the mountain to enjoy the surrounding landscape.</s>
<s id="d13p6s2">From the Giai Oan (Clearing Unjust Charges) pagoda, pilgrims follow the stream to get to Yen Tu mountain.</s>
<s id="d13p6s3">The long road is dotted with places of worship like Hoa Hien Pagoda, Ngoa Van temple, Mot Mai (One Roof) pagoda, Bao Sai pagoda, and Vân Tien pagoda.</s>
<s id="d13p6s4">Bach Hop, a pilgrim, says: “When we reached the Bronze pagoda, it was 5 o’clock in the morning.</s>
<s id="d13p6s5">It was dark but we felt good.</s>
<s id="d13p6s6">Yen Tu is beautiful, clean, tranquil and peaceful”.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d14">
<p id="d14p1">
<s id="d14p1s1">Ha Long Bay Cruises</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p2">
<s id="d14p2s1">The beauty of Ha Long Bay, which has been twice recognized by UNESCO as a world natural heritage site, always changes over the time.</s>
<s id="d14p2s2">Visiting Ha Long Bay at any time of the year, visitors are always amazed with its attraction.</s>
<s id="d14p2s3">Today’s Discovery Vietnam takes you on a tour of the Bay on the Golden Lotus cruise.</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p3">
<s id="d14p3s1">On board the Golden Lotus cruise are tourists from the US, Australia, Spain, Sweden and Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d14p3s2">Leaving from Bai Chay port, the cruise takes them around the bay.</s>
<s id="d14p3s3">The beauty of the natural setting in the Bay blends with the blue sky and the cool breeze from the sea comforting its visitors.</s>
<s id="d14p3s4">Nguyen The Huu, a guide of the Khanh Sinh International Tourism Company, says: “During the one-day tour, tourists visit the Thien Cung (Heaven) and Dau Go (Wood Hidden) grottoes and then go to Ba Hang (Three Caves) fishing village for kayaking.</s>
<s id="d14p3s5">Then the tourists visit the Cho Da, Dinh Huong and Ga Choi islets and dock at Ha Long.</s>
<s id="d14p3s6">On the two-day tour, tourists have more time for sightseeing and to relax on the cruise.</s>
<s id="d14p3s7">The tour programs are diverse to give our tourists choices.</s>
<s id="d14p3s8">Our company focuses on service quality and the safety of customers.</s>
<s id="d14p3s9">We always try to refresh our tours and develop new services for our customers”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p4">
<s id="d14p4s1">Visiting Ha Long Bay by cruise, tourists can enjoy the complete view of the unique natural setting.</s>
<s id="d14p4s2">Sitting on the boat, enjoying a cool juice and gazing around at the scenery, with the thousands of islets of different sizes and shapes is the perfect choice.</s>
<s id="d14p4s3">John, a tourist from Australia, was visiting Ha Long for the first time.</s>
<s id="d14p4s4">He said that the natural setting was unbelievable and that it was much more enjoyable to relax it on a cruise.</s>
<s id="d14p4s5">John said: "It's all inspiring, tranquil, eagles above, fish below, beautiful scenery, and incredible.</s>
<s id="d14p4s6">The caves are beautiful.</s>
<s id="d14p4s7">I thought they were little caves but they were real caves.</s>
<s id="d14p4s8">They are amazing".</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p5">
<s id="d14p5s1">The most interesting and exciting moment is when the cruise docks at the fishing village and the tourists are free to go kayaking.</s>
<s id="d14p5s2">With assistance from the guide, all of us, even those who can’t swim, can find kayaking easy and interesting.</s>
<s id="d14p5s3">Each kayak accommodates 2 tourists.</s>
<s id="d14p5s4">Once they are in control of oars, they all are excited by kayaking.</s>
<s id="d14p5s5">John and his friend Tania are very happy with the whole experience.</s>
<s id="d14p5s6">John says: "We can stay here forever, go around and around.</s>
<s id="d14p5s7">I really love the fishing village and the water as well as the nature and the human habitats.</s>
<s id="d14p5s8">You know it's amazing when a man fishes in the nature, finds the way, sorts of things coming to your mind, it's really good.</s>
<s id="d14p5s9">While we're in the water, I want to stay here longer because it's actually great, a great experience.</s>
<s id="d14p5s10">I've never done that before.</s>
<s id="d14p5s11">It's so easy to get around, I was scared at first, but once I was in there, got the feeling, I could get around, up to the mountains.</s>
<s id="d14p5s12">Look right up, you see the cliffs right above you.</s>
<s id="d14p5s13">It was beautiful.</s>
<s id="d14p5s14">I'd love to do that again."</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p6">
<s id="d14p6s1">In the afternoon, tourists had another unique experience.</s>
<s id="d14p6s2">They were taught how to make spring rolls, a traditional Vietnamese dish.</s>
<s id="d14p6s3">Mixing together all the ingredients: pork, vermicelli, wood ears, carrot, seasoning, eggs and wrapping in the rice papers is an exciting experience for many tourists.</s>
<s id="d14p6s4">Efarault, a French tourist, says: "If I can come to Vietnam to make some cooking.</s>
<s id="d14p6s5">It's a good idea.</s>
<s id="d14p6s6">It is fun for everybody to meet around the table, try to prepare the dinner well.</s>
<s id="d14p6s7">It's fun.</s>
<s id="d14p6s8">We meet people, share with people and have a nice dinner together.</s>
<s id="d14p6s9">It's a good idea to do that".</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p7">
<s id="d14p7s1">When the night falls, the sea glitters with the light from all the boats making Ha Long Bay even more miraculous and beautiful.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d15">
<p id="d15p1">
<s id="d15p1s1">Con Son - Kiep Bac: Museum of Vietnamese belief and culture</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p2">
<s id="d15p2s1">Con Son-Kiep Bac relic site in Hai Duong province has several historical and cultural relics reflecting Buddhism and Confucianism and national heroes of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d15p2s2">Located 80 km from Hanoi, the complex is a destination to explore Vietnam’s history, culture, and religion.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p3">
<s id="d15p3s1">Con Son pagoda was built in the 10th century and was expanded in the 13th century during the Tran dynasty.</s>
<s id="d15p3s2">In 1329, Venerable Monk Phap Loan, second founder of Lam Zen Sect upgraded the pagoda.</s>
<s id="d15p3s3">His successor, Huyen Quang expanded the pagoda, taught Buddhism, printed Buddhist sutras, cast Buddha statues and developed Con Son into one of the three principal centers of Buddhist Truc Lam Zen.</s>
<s id="d15p3s4">Le Duy Manh is Deputy Head of the Con Son - Kiep Bac Relic Management Committee: "Con Son, Yen Tu and Quynh Lam are the three centers of the Truc Lam Zen sect.</s>
<s id="d15p3s5">Con Son pagoda was chaired by the three founders of the sect.</s>
<s id="d15p3s6">Venerable Monk Huyen Quang stayed in Con Son pagoda all his life.</s>
<s id="d15p3s7">He died on the 23rd day of the first lunar month in 1334.</s>
<s id="d15p3s8">His death anniversary is commemorated by the Con Son Spring Festival”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p4">
<s id="d15p4s1">Con Pagoda embodies the royal architectural style distinguished by a half-moon lake and a three-door temple gate in the front.</s>
<s id="d15p4s2">A path leads to the bell tower before reaching the main sanctuary, behind which is a lotus-shaped tower and the memorial house dedicated to the founders of the Truc Lam Zen Sect.</s>
<s id="d15p4s3">In 1962, the pagoda was recognized as a national heritage site.</s>
<s id="d15p4s4">Near Con Son pagoda is Kiep Bac temple and a temple dedicated to the Confucian teacher Chu Van An.Con Son-Kiep Bac relic site still preserves documents, worshipping rituals, and traditional festivals.</s>
<s id="d15p4s5">There are also four stone steles dating back to the 13th century.</s>
<s id="d15p4s6">One of them is the famous stele called “Thanh Hu Cave” which is recognized as a "national treasure".</s>
<s id="d15p4s7">It was a gift King Tran Due Tong presented to mandarin Tran Nguyen Dan in 1369.</s>
<s id="d15p4s8">Le Duy Manh again: "The Con Son Pagoda features a traditional sculptural style that honors four sacred animals: dragon, unicorn, tortoise and phoenix and four sacred plants: apricot, pine, chrysanthemum, and bamboo.</s>
<s id="d15p4s9">There are also sculptures of other animal species like crab, fish, and deer.</s>
<s id="d15p4s10">All animals bow before the Buddha showing that all species and people are equal and are educated by Buddha to become good”.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d16">
<p id="d16p1">
<s id="d16p1s1">Hai Tac (Pirate) archipelago- a new tourist destination</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p2">
<s id="d16p2s1">Hai Tac, literally translated as “Pirate” archipelago, 30 km from Ha Tien township, is a new tourist attraction in Kien Giang province.</s>
<s id="d16p2s2">The pristine natural landscapes of this place are amazingly beautiful.</s>
<s id="d16p2s3">In recent years, Ha Tien authorities have invested in Hai Tac archipelago to make it an even more attractive.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p3">
<s id="d16p3s1">Hai Tac archipelago comprises 16 islands.</s>
<s id="d16p3s2">Tre Lon islet sits at the center of the archipelago.</s>
<s id="d16p3s3">The locals subsist on fishing and aquaculture.</s>
<s id="d16p3s4">70 households are engaged in cage fishing.</s>
<s id="d16p3s5">The sea here between Ha Tien-Rach Gia Bay and Thailand Bay is calm and unpolluted making it favorable for both aquaculture and tourism.</s>
<s id="d16p3s6">Hong Xuan Than says local people are friendly and hospitable: “We always welcome visitors and show them our work.</s>
<s id="d16p3s7">Tourism has generated income for us”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p4">
<s id="d16p4s1">The place intrigues tourists with its “Pirate” name, its white sand beaches, and its turquoise water.</s>
<s id="d16p4s2">Nguyen Thanh Sang is a tourist from An Giang: "My friends told me about this unspoiled archipelago.</s>
<s id="d16p4s3">Its name inspires me to go and explore it.</s>
<s id="d16p4s4">It’s a raw gem.</s>
<s id="d16p4s5">I slept in a rudimentary hut by the sea and was delighted”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p5">
<s id="d16p5s1">The island attracted 30,000 visitors in 2015 earning nearly 400,000 USD.</s>
<s id="d16p5s2">Tang Hong Phuoc, Chairman of the Tien Hai Communal People’s Committee, said that while the island has tourist potential, its facilities are inadequate.</s>
<s id="d16p5s3">Kien Giang provincial authorities have invested in upgrading the infrastructure on a number of islands in the archipelago to boost their tourism potential.</s>
<s id="d16p5s4">Mr.</s>
<s id="d16p5s5">Phuoc says: “Tien Hai commune has great tourism potential.</s>
<s id="d16p5s6">With enough investments like Vinpearl’s, local tourism will grow dramatically”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p6">
<s id="d16p6s1">This year, a number of big projects to upgrade local infrastructure will be undertaken: a communal administrative center, markets, a concentrated residential area, wharves, an ecological tourism site, and a waste treatment plant.</s>
<s id="d16p6s2">The commune is expected to be on the national power grid by 2017.</s>
<s id="d16p6s3">Efforts like those could make Hai Tac archipelago a new hot spot.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d17">
<p id="d17p1">
<s id="d17p1s1">Da Lat night market</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p2">
<s id="d17p2s1">When the sun goes down, Da Lat city in Lam Dong province is lit up by the bright lights of shops, restaurants and hotels.</s>
<s id="d17p2s2">In the cool night air, you should dress warmly to wander around the small streets visiting the night market and exploring Da Lat's culture and street life.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p3">
<s id="d17p3s1">In the daytime, Da Lat charms visitors with its colorful flowers, green pine forests, beautiful lakes and fresh highlands air.</s>
<s id="d17p3s2">Tourists often make side trips to outlying areas to see flower villages, mountains and magnificent waterfalls.</s>
<s id="d17p3s3">When the sun sets, it's time to relax and warm up with local food bought at the night market one of the most popular local attractions.</s>
<s id="d17p3s4">Most of the customers in the market are tourists seeking local specialties like wool products, vegetables, or fruits and sampling the local food.</s>
<s id="d17p3s5">Ha Diem My is visiting Da Lat with her family: “I like the night market in Da Lat because I find it uniquely represents the city.</s>
<s id="d17p3s6">Here I can buy local products as souvenirs like woolen products and vegetables like cabbages, carrots, and potatoes which are cheap and fresh”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p4">
<s id="d17p4s1">Pham Bich Duy from Ho Chi Minh City says: “This is the 4th time I have visited the market.</s>
<s id="d17p4s2">Every time I come here, I feel inspired.</s>
<s id="d17p4s3">I have bought clothes, hats, wool products, socks, and key holders.</s>
<s id="d17p4s4">I've also bought local specialties like dried fruits and fruit juice”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p5">
<s id="d17p5s1">Though it is in the highlands, Da Lat is famous for its seafood.</s>
<s id="d17p5s2">Seafood dishes in Da lat are varied affordable, and delicious.</s>
<s id="d17p5s3">Nguyen Duc Tinh from Vinh Phuc province says: “Da Lat's night market offers a wide range of hot pots which are very well seasoned and accompanied by fresh vegetables.</s>
<s id="d17p5s4">The temperature in Da Lat is moderate, the barbeque dishes are very tasty and the local wines are very special and varied”</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p6">
<s id="d17p6s1">Tourists like the market because the items on sale are affordable and the traders are hospitable.</s>
<s id="d17p6s2">Local authorities have created favorable conditions for traders to do their business.</s>
<s id="d17p6s3">Le Thi Hong Nhung owns a shop by the market in Nguyen Thi Minh Khai street: “Local authorities always support and encourage local traders to diversify and improve the quality of their products.</s>
<s id="d17p6s4">I sell local specialties including fruits, vegetables, dried fruits, tea, coffee, and artichokes.</s>
<s id="d17p6s5">They are all locally made.</s>
<s id="d17p6s6">At night, the market is very busy”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p7">
<s id="d17p7s1">Many tourists agree that no tour of Da Lat is complete without exploring the night market and its street food stalls.</s>
<s id="d17p7s2">While tourists in Sai Gon and Hanoi usually go to restaurants to sample the local cuisine, in Da Lat, it's the open food stalls in the central market where visitors find something hot to eat to warm themselves up while they observe the street activity.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d18">
<p id="d18p1">
<s id="d18p1s1">Visiting Cu Lan village, Lam Dong province</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p2">
<s id="d18p2s1">Cu Lan is a peaceful village of the K’Ho ethnicity in Lam Dong province.</s>
<s id="d18p2s2">Tiny stilt houses, pure air, and warmhearted people attract tourists to the village.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p3">
<s id="d18p3s1">Cu Lan village is named after a local plant species that flourishes between the rows of pine trees.</s>
<s id="d18p3s2">Cu Lan is also the Vietnamese word for a sloth that lives near the village.</s>
<s id="d18p3s3">Cu Lan village is nestled in a forest at the foot of Lang Biang mountain in Lac Duong district, 20km from Dalat.</s>
<s id="d18p3s4">Here, the K'ho, one of the 54 ethnic groups of Vietnam, live in stilt houses that lean against the steep slope.</s>
<s id="d18p3s5">Impressed by the region, Van Tuan Anh wrote a song about the village which established it as an ecotourism village.</s>
<s id="d18p3s6">Doan Truong Son is a tour guide with the Viettravel Company:“Each of us has our own impression of the name of the village.</s>
<s id="d18p3s7">For me, the name of the village expresses its pure beauty.</s>
<s id="d18p3s8">This village demonstrates the harmony between man and nature.</s>
<s id="d18p3s9">It’s a destination for anyone who wants to escape the dust and noise of the city”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p4">
<s id="d18p4s1">Some visitors like to walk along the small paths connecting the small thatched-roof houses.</s>
<s id="d18p4s2">Others prefer to venture over rush bamboo bridges to meadows of purple, violet, and yellow daylilies.</s>
<s id="d18p4s3">Others choose to take a jeep to explore the hillside roads.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p5">
<s id="d18p5s1">Trinh Thi Ngot from Ho Chi Minh City says: “Driving a jeep here is really sensational.</s>
<s id="d18p5s2">The slopes are incredibly dangerous and before today I had never tried.</s>
<s id="d18p5s3">It's really impressive”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p6">
<s id="d18p6s1">Cu Lan village offers numerous activities: kite flying, hiking, boat rowing, fishing, picnicking, folk games and gong performances.</s>
<s id="d18p6s2">There's even an art gallery.</s>
<s id="d18p6s3">Minh Lân from Radio and Television of Lam Dong says: “After travelling particularly winding roads, we arrive in this romantic village.</s>
<s id="d18p6s4">Don’t miss the small open-air market in Duoc hamlet or the exhibits of Vietnamese and foreign artists”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p7">
<s id="d18p7s1">The village’s rows of houses on wooden stilts are reflected by a large lake as if in a a mirror.</s>
<s id="d18p7s2">On holidays, boat races are held.</s>
<s id="d18p7s3">At night, glowing lanterns give the village an air of mystery.</s>
<s id="d18p7s4">Songwriter Van Tuan Anh says: "Tourists are increasingly demanding.</s>
<s id="d18p7s5">They want to discover a vibrant culture.</s>
<s id="d18p7s6">Cu Lan village has preserved its identity.</s>
<s id="d18p7s7">Tourists really enjoy visiting small houses with domestic animals and vegetable gardens around the house.</s>
<s id="d18p7s8">When night falls, we gather around the fire and dance to the rhythm of gongs.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p8">
<s id="d18p8s1">No one forgets a visit to Cu Lan, one of the most fascinating villages in the Central Highlands.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d19">
<p id="d19p1">
<s id="d19p1s1">Tours of high-tech agriculture in Da Lat</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p2">
<s id="d19p2s1">Da Lat inspires tourists for with its picturesque landscapes, cool climate, unique architecture and especially its beautiful flowers.</s>
<s id="d19p2s2">Flower gardens that use high-tech cultivation methods often surprise visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p3">
<s id="d19p3s1">In recent years Da Lat gardeners have used automation, information technology, new material technology, bio-technology, and high-tech varieties to grow flowers.</s>
<s id="d19p3s2">In a short time, a model of high-tech agricultural production has proliferated, boosting local revenues.</s>
<s id="d19p3s3">Local households and enterprises now combine agricultural production with tourism.</s>
<s id="d19p3s4">Nguyen Thi Nguyen is Director of Lam Dong Provincial Department of Culture, Sports, and Tourism: “Lam Dong province has invested in high-tech agricultural production.</s>
<s id="d19p3s5">Tourism and high-tech agriculture are our strengths.</s>
<s id="d19p3s6">We want to boost high-tech agriculture to generate higher incomes for local farmers and create new tourist attraction in the province”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p4">
<s id="d19p4s1">The flower villages of Ha Dong, Thai Phien and Van Thanh are the most popular tourist destinations.</s>
<s id="d19p4s2">Here tourists can observe farmers planting and harvesting their flowers.</s>
<s id="d19p4s3">Nguyen Van Dan owns a 3000-square-meter flower garden in Ha Dong village where he grows chrysanthemums and carnations.</s>
<s id="d19p4s4">Dan said: “Previously, we just sold flowers.</s>
<s id="d19p4s5">Since we started welcoming tourists to our garden in 2012, our flowers have become better known in the market.</s>
<s id="d19p4s6">In the beginning, it was difficult for us to communicate with tourists but gradually we learned how to talk about our flowers and demonstrate how we grow them”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p5">
<s id="d19p5s1">Agricultural tourism has drawn many tourists to Da Lat.</s>
<s id="d19p5s2">Tourists can visit 400 ha of strawberry gardens, taste sweet strawberries and buy some as gifts for their friends.</s>
<s id="d19p5s3">Nguyen Thanh Sang is a tourist from Bac Lieu province: “Da Lat’s tourist attractions are diverse and interesting.</s>
<s id="d19p5s4">I visited the Biofresh company and its strawberry garden.</s>
<s id="d19p5s5">It was a very interesting experience”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p6">
<s id="d19p6s1">Da Lat welcomed more than 3 million visitors in 2010 and 5.1 million last year.</s>
<s id="d19p6s2">The number of visitors to Da Lat increases 10 to 12% annually.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d20">
<p id="d20p1">
<s id="d20p1s1">Visiting Son La</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p2">
<s id="d20p2s1">Located 300 km northwest of Hanoi, Son La province has become a popular tourist destination in recent years because of its various ethnicities, festivals, historical relics and scenic spots.</s>
<s id="d20p2s2">Son La Museum, the Son La Hydro Power Plant, and hot springs in Mong villages, and peach blossoms, apricot and bauhinia flowers inspire tourists near and far.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p3">
<s id="d20p3s1">There are more than 100 historical and cultural relics in Son La of which Son La prison and Son La museum are the most popular.</s>
<s id="d20p3s2">Classified as a national relic in 1962, Son La prison is perched atop Khau Ca hill.</s>
<s id="d20p3s3">Covering an area of 500 m2, Son La prison was built in 1908 by the French colonialists to imprison Vietnamese communists.</s>
<s id="d20p3s4">Known as hell on earth, its cells were built with solid stones and its high walls were covered with barbed wires and broken glass.</s>
<s id="d20p3s5">Despite the barbaric tortures, Vietnamese communist soldiers turned their cells hell into a place to communicate Vietnam’s resolution.</s>
<s id="d20p3s6">The prison has recently been renovated and become a tourist mecca in the northwestern region.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p4">
<s id="d20p4s1">Son La Museum was also built in 1908 by the French.</s>
<s id="d20p4s2">There, distinctive cultures of 12 local ethnic minority groups in the province can be discovered through thousands of pre-history artifacts.</s>
<s id="d20p4s3">Collections of 1,000 books, documents, epics, and folk tales and songs of the Thai and Dao ethnicities are kept at the museum.</s>
<s id="d20p4s4">Nguyen Hai Duong is a guide at the museum: “Covering 14,000 square kilometers, Son La province has 12 ethnic communities, 55% of them are Thai minorities.</s>
<s id="d20p4s5">These are ancient books of the Thai in Son La who have valuable expertise in paper-making from bamboo fiber and other plants.</s>
<s id="d20p4s6">Their books are divided into three main categories: literature, history and belief”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p5">
<s id="d20p5s1">The Son La Hydro Power Plant is also an attractive destination in the city.</s>
<s id="d20p5s2">Surrounded by a verdant forest, Son La Reservoir impresses visitors with its incomparable beauty.</s>
<s id="d20p5s3">Hoang Lan, a tourist from Bac Giang province, shares her emotions: “This is the first time I visit the lake.</s>
<s id="d20p5s4">Nestled in the heart of magnificent nature, it is an ideal place to relax.</s>
<s id="d20p5s5">I would like to come back to discover more about local people’s life”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p6">
<s id="d20p6s1">Hidden in a mountain range, Mong village in Hua La commune, 6km from the center of Son La, is also a tourist destination.</s>
<s id="d20p6s2">Nguyen Hong Thang, a tour guide from Hanoi said:“In Mong village, tourists relax in hot springs and enjoy Thai cuisine.</s>
<s id="d20p6s3">Water in hot springs here can be used as a medical therapy or a drink.</s>
<s id="d20p6s4">After having a bathe, you can stay in guest houses and savor delicious Thai dishes”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p7">
<s id="d20p7s1">Seeing is believing.</s>
<s id="d20p7s2">Go and explore the wide nature by yourself!</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d21">
<p id="d21p1">
<s id="d21p1s1">Unique architecture of Dong Van</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p2">
<s id="d21p2s1">The charm of Ha Giang is not limited to its beautiful fields of buckwheat flowers, its breathtaking roads, and authentic ethnic markets.</s>
<s id="d21p2s2">Ha Giang province is also home to amazing architectural treasures.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p3">
<s id="d21p3s1">After following the highway 4C for about 160 km from the center of Ha Giang, you will arrive at Dong Van township where you should not miss a tour of the old town.</s>
<s id="d21p3s2">Perched at 1,600 meters, Dong Van township was home to Tay, Hoa, and Mong ethnicities in the early 20th century.</s>
<s id="d21p3s3">In 1920, the old township was renovated by the French, who brought new construction materials and Western architecture.</s>
<s id="d21p3s4">Laterite houses with stone columns and decorated with red lanterns blend harmoniously with traditional clay buildings.</s>
<s id="d21p3s5">Most of these houses belong to the Luong Huy family.</s>
<s id="d21p3s6">Luong Huy Ngo of the Tay ethnic group says these houses are still in good condition:"The houses of this type are very comfortable.</s>
<s id="d21p3s7">It is cool in summer and warm in winter.</s>
<s id="d21p3s8">The wall thickness can be up to 85 cm.</s>
<s id="d21p3s9">The wall part near the door is thinner, 65 cm.</s>
<s id="d21p3s10">To build such a house, it takes about one month with the help of six people divided into two teams.</s>
<s id="d21p3s11">One team is responsible for carpentry and the other for masonry.</s>
<s id="d21p3s12">The first team erects the wooden columns.</s>
<s id="d21p3s13">Today, it is impossible to use only heartwood as in the past, so newer columns are less resistant.</s>
<s id="d21p3s14">The second team prepares a kind of mixing clay”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p4">
<s id="d21p4s1">Located a hundred kilometers from the old quarter, the residence of Vuong, formerly named "Mong King Castle" is a major attraction in the region.</s>
<s id="d21p4s2">The residence, which covers nearly 1,200 square meters, is surrounded by majestic mountains.</s>
<s id="d21p4s3">It was designed by Vuong Chinh Duc, from a wealthy and powerful Mong family, who controlled the whole Dong Van region.</s>
<s id="d21p4s4">Vuong Thi Cho is a fourth-generation descendant:"The wages paid to architects and workmen to build the house were equivalent to 150 billion VND.</s>
<s id="d21p4s5">The materials were all from Dong Van.</s>
<s id="d21p4s6">You see, these two stone columns symbolize the poppy fruits.</s>
<s id="d21p4s7">The workers rubbed the stone columns with silver to give them a silver color.</s>
<s id="d21p4s8">Each column is worth about 900 million VND.</s>
<s id="d21p4s9">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p5">
<s id="d21p5s1">Besides the main building, the residence includes several houses for guests, as well as living rooms, a heating room, and an indoor stone pool for bathing baths in goat milk.</s>
<s id="d21p5s2">The owner constructed his residence as a fortress with tall fortified stone walls.</s>
<s id="d21p5s3">The three rooms of the main building are surmounted by stone blockhouses.</s>
<s id="d21p5s4">At the back, there is a large stone basin to collect rain water.</s>
<s id="d21p5s5">Ms.</s>
<s id="d21p5s6">Cho says:"Since Dong Van Karst Park was recognized by UNESCO, more tourists visit the residence.</s>
<s id="d21p5s7">Each month, we welcome about 3,000 visitors and on public holidays, about 1,000 tourists a day.</s>
<s id="d21p5s8">From September, there are more foreigners arriving”</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p6">
<s id="d21p6s1">The original appearance of the Vuong residence and the old town of Dong Van district has resisted the ravages of time.</s>
<s id="d21p6s2">Their cultural authenticity seduces tourists without a doubt.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d22">
<p id="d22p1">
<s id="d22p1s1">Ha Giang is appealing with beautiful buckwheat flowers</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p2">
<s id="d22p2s1">In late October, photo enthusiasts flock to Ha Giang province where the hills boast a beautiful white gown tinged with pink - the emblematic color of buckwheat flowers.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p3">
<s id="d22p3s1">The history of buckwheat flowers is as old as the generations of the Mong ethnic minority group in Ha Giang.</s>
<s id="d22p3s2">It is said that in ancient times, a famine devastated villages.</s>
<s id="d22p3s3">Since the land was barren, local people went in search of food.</s>
<s id="d22p3s4">One day, an extraordinary fragrance appealed to the peasants.</s>
<s id="d22p3s5">Among the rocks, they discovered small white pink flowers whose nuts tasted as subtle as rice and corn.</s>
<s id="d22p3s6">Since then, the Mong have used the buckwheat flowers’ nuts as staples like maize and rice.</s>
<s id="d22p3s7">Local people also make buckwheat cakes and wine.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p4">
<s id="d22p4s1">Buckwheat flowers bloom from October to November.</s>
<s id="d22p4s2">Visitors will see rocky plateau decorated with buckwheat forests that extend over the Quan Ba ​​Dong Van, Yen Minh and Meo Vac mountain districts.</s>
<s id="d22p4s3">The pure beauty of the flower dazzles nature lovers.</s>
<s id="d22p4s4">Mai Huong is a tourist from Hanoi:“I’m very impressed with the landscapes of Ha Giang and its people.</s>
<s id="d22p4s5">They live here, in difficult conditions, trapped in the mountains and barren lands.</s>
<s id="d22p4s6">Here, even though the conditions are arduous, beauty is everywhere.</s>
<s id="d22p4s7">The meadows covered with buckwheat flowers are beautiful.</s>
<s id="d22p4s8">Everyone is impressed by this wonderful landscape”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p5">
<s id="d22p5s1">Yet this incredible beauty has completely fallen into oblivion.</s>
<s id="d22p5s2">It was not until social networks began to show off this beautiful landscape to tourists.</s>
<s id="d22p5s3">There are indeed photos posted on Facebook that have made buckwheat flowers of Ha Giang known to young people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p6">
<s id="d22p6s1">In order to promote the tourism potential of the region, Ha Giang authorities decided to increase the buckwheat fields to attract more visitors as possible.</s>
<s id="d22p6s2">A festival will be launched next November to honor the beauty of buckwheat flowers and promote the charm of the limestone plateaus.</s>
<s id="d22p6s3">Nguyen Van Tai is Director of VietSense Travel: "We are among the first companies to have launched tours to Ha Giang.</s>
<s id="d22p6s4">Everything is ready to welcome visitors in November and December.</s>
<s id="d22p6s5">The buckwheat blossom festival is a unique tourist feature for Ha Giang.</s>
<s id="d22p6s6">The festival will help increase the number of tourists”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p7">
<s id="d22p7s1">The Buckwheat flower festival will take place in four districts of Dong Van, Quan Ba, Yen Minh and Meo Vac in the northern mountain province of Ha Giang from November 13-15.</s>
<s id="d22p7s2">Go and discover this unique destination for yourself.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d23">
<p id="d23p1">
<s id="d23p1s1">Quang Tri battlefield</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p2">
<s id="d23p2s1">Quang Tri province attracts visitors not only because of its beautiful landscape and delicious food but also its historical relic sites.</s>
<s id="d23p2s2">The visitors come to the province to express their gratitude and show their respect to fallen soldiers.</s>
<s id="d23p2s3">Quang Tri citadel, Highway 9 Cemetery, and Truong Son National Martyrs’ Cemetery are the popular destinations.</s>
<s id="d23p2s4">Dinh Thieu reports.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p3">
<s id="d23p3s1">War veteran Pham Xuan Thanh of Lang Son province often visits his fallen comrades in Quang Tri province in July.</s>
<s id="d23p3s2">Thanh was among the last people to leave Quang Tri province after the 81-day campaign to defend the citadel in 1972.</s>
<s id="d23p3s3">Thanh says Quang Tri was the battlefield where many of his comrades died.</s>
<s id="d23p3s4">When he visits his fallen comrades, Thanh often brings soil and water from his home village to sprinkle on the soldiers’ graves and into the Thach Han River.</s>
<s id="d23p3s5">Thanh says by doing so, he brings the homeland to the war martyrs:“Today, I come here to visit my comrades and release flowers in memory of them.</s>
<s id="d23p3s6">I’m very moved every time I come here.</s>
<s id="d23p3s7">I always remember my comrades and local people who died in this river during the war.</s>
<s id="d23p3s8">We are now the winners and we are grateful to the fallen people”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p4">
<s id="d23p4s1">In Quang Tri province, there are 72 cemeteries accommodating nearly 650,000 war martyrs.</s>
<s id="d23p4s2">The National Highway 9 Cemetery and the National Truong Son Cemetery are located in this province.</s>
<s id="d23p4s3">All communes in the province have martyrs’ cemeteries, some of them have as many as 4.</s>
<s id="d23p4s4">Quang Tri citadel and the Thach Han River are considered an unmarked grave where thousands of young people fell during the war.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p5">
<s id="d23p5s1">These days, war martyrs’ cemeteries in Quang Tri province receive a lot of visitors who come to pay their respects to fallen soldiers.</s>
<s id="d23p5s2">Ms.</s>
<s id="d23p5s3">Nguyen Thi Hanh burst into tears when she visited Truong Son cemetery and Quang Tri citadel for the first time:“I’m very moved and full of pity for the fallen soldiers.</s>
<s id="d23p5s4">Their bravery is unimaginable.</s>
<s id="d23p5s5">I’m very grateful to the fallen soldiers”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p6">
<s id="d23p6s1">People in Quang Tri have two occasions for showing gratitude: at the full-moon day in the lunar July when they express their gratitude to their ancestors and on July 27th, when they show their gratitude to fallen soldiers.</s>
<s id="d23p6s2">In July Quang Tri also celebrates the Highway 9- Khe Sanh victory and the battle to defend Quang Tri citadel in July 1972.</s>
<s id="d23p6s3">To mark the occasion, memorial and relic sites, and compassionate houses are upgraded and gifts are presented to social beneficiaries.</s>
<s id="d23p6s4">This year Quang Tri province inaugurated the Cua Viet Victory Monument built with 30 billion VND donated by social organizations, businesses and private donors.</s>
<s id="d23p6s5">In the “Sacred Homeland” program, commercial banks donated 100 billion VND to commemorative activities in Quang Tri province.</s>
<s id="d23p6s6">Nguyen Duc Huong is Vice President of Lien Viet Post Bank’s Executive Committee: “We are thankful to the sacrifices of fallen soldiers.</s>
<s id="d23p6s7">Whatever we do or how much we do, we can never repay to their and their families’ great sacrifice.</s>
<s id="d23p6s8">We call on the younger generation to do their best to deserve our predecessors’ sacrifices”.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d24">
<p id="d24p1">
<s id="d24p1s1">Nha Ruong- Ancient houses in Hoi Ky village, Quang Tri province</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p2">
<s id="d24p2s1">Hoi Ky ancient village in Hai Chanh commune, Hai Lang district, Quang Tri province is located by the O Lau river.</s>
<s id="d24p2s2">The village is more than 500 years old.</s>
<s id="d24p2s3">Visitors to the village are amazed at the numerous ancient wooden houses known as Nha Ruong, religious establishments, and the peaceful lives of the local people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p3">
<s id="d24p3s1">Along road to Hoi Ky village are temples, pagodas and clan worship houses which boast unique architectural styles.</s>
<s id="d24p3s2">But visitors are most amazed at the centuries-old wooden houses nestled in large gardens along O Lau River.</s>
<s id="d24p3s3">These houses, which belong to the Duong family clan are comprised of 5 or 7 rooms and wing rooms and are made of thick solid wood.</s>
<s id="d24p3s4">Their columns and doors are engraved with dragons, unicorns, phoenixes and other delicate patterns.</s>
<s id="d24p3s5">In each house, there are lacquered boards with parallel sentences teaching children to do good.</s>
<s id="d24p3s6">Doors between rooms are beautifully decorated.</s>
<s id="d24p3s7">The room in the middle is used to worship the ancestors while its two neighboring rooms serve living and bed rooms.</s>
<s id="d24p3s8">Of the other two wing rooms, the one on the west is for boys and the one on the east is for girls.</s>
<s id="d24p3s9">There’s also an entresol in the house that contains rice and other home objects.</s>
<s id="d24p3s10">Duong Van Cho is a local in Hoi Ky village: “Among the 20 ancient houses in the village, 6 have 3 main rooms and 2 wing rooms.</s>
<s id="d24p3s11">They are about 100 years old.</s>
<s id="d24p3s12">Local people have restored their houses and all want to maintain their identity”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p4">
<s id="d24p4s1">Depending on the size of the house, each roof has between 10,000 and 20,000 brick tiles made of clay.</s>
<s id="d24p4s2">The tiles are rectangular, thin, flat and can produce a bell sound when they are knocked.</s>
<s id="d24p4s3">This way of tiling makes the house cool in summer and warm in winter.</s>
<s id="d24p4s4">Walls of the house are made of lime and wood hammered bricks.</s>
<s id="d24p4s5">Every house is surrounded by trimmed green tree fences.</s>
<s id="d24p4s6">Doctor Le Vinh An is of the Advisory Committee for Hue Ancient Capital Preservation: “Hoi Ky ancient village still retains its values.</s>
<s id="d24p4s7">The village was founded in the 15th century but its houses are between 100 and 150 years old.</s>
<s id="d24p4s8">The landscape in the village is beautiful with a river zigzagging around the village, small lanes, wharves, and a communal yard.</s>
<s id="d24p4s9">These are typical characteristics of rural Vietnam”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p5">
<s id="d24p5s1">Mr. Duong Van Manh’s house which is comprised of 3 main rooms and 2 wing rooms and a roof with 10,000 tiles is the most typical.</s>
<s id="d24p5s2">Named “Happiness convergence”, the house is situated in the middle of a large garden.</s>
<s id="d24p5s3">Built in 1889, the house is sustained with 48 jackfruit wooden columns.</s>
<s id="d24p5s4">Built in 1931, Ms Duong Thi Huong’s house has one main room and 2 wing rooms and covers about 60 square meters.</s>
<s id="d24p5s5">Inside the house, there’s a lacquered board saying “4 generations living in the same house”.</s>
<s id="d24p5s6">According to traditional beliefs, a house with 4 generations living together is a happy house.</s>
<s id="d24p5s7">Most of the houses in Hoi Ky hang a lacquered board with the word “Peace” on it.</s>
<s id="d24p5s8">Nguyen Thanh Nam is from Quang Nam province: “The architecture of the houses is outstanding.</s>
<s id="d24p5s9">Their structures are also sustainable because they all have solid columns.</s>
<s id="d24p5s10">The roof of the house is low helping to protect the house from strong winds”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p6">
<s id="d24p6s1">The locals in Hoi Ky are proud of their houses which stand firm and retain their traditional values despite of war and climate devastation.</s>
<s id="d24p6s2">These houses have great historical, cultural and architectural values, according to Kitani Kenta, an expert from the UNESCO’s World Heritage Institute at Japan’s Waseda University.</s>
<s id="d24p6s3">Kitani Kenta says the ancient wooden houses of Hoi Ky are wonderful, sophisticated and skillfully built.</s>
<s id="d24p6s4">These outstanding features need to be promoted’.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d25">
<p id="d25p1">
<s id="d25p1s1">The Red Dao ethnic group in Ta Phin</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p2">
<s id="d25p2s1">Located ten kilometers from Sa Pa town, Ta Phin village is a popular destination for tourists.</s>
<s id="d25p2s2">The village is famous for traditional medical remedies of wild leaves made by local Red Dao people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p3">
<s id="d25p3s1">In Sapa, tourists can rent a motorbike to go to Ta Phin.</s>
<s id="d25p3s2">The road is flanded by rice terraces and sloping rice fields on the hillsides.</s>
<s id="d25p3s3">The first stop is the monastery of Ta Phin, or rather its remains.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p4">
<s id="d25p4s1">Many tourists like to stay in the homes of local people to experience the way Red Dao people live.</s>
<s id="d25p4s2">In a wooden house, tourists help the hosts cook.</s>
<s id="d25p4s3">In the morning, they go together to the nearby forest to look for medicinal plants and visit the village.</s>
<s id="d25p4s4">In the evening, families and tourists sit around the fireplace chatting.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p5">
<s id="d25p5s1">Dang Thai An and his children come from Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d25p5s2">They spent three days with Ms.</s>
<s id="d25p5s3">Phan Man May’s family.</s>
<s id="d25p5s4">An says he is enjoying this experience very much.</s>
<s id="d25p5s5">This is the first time he has taken a trip without hotel or restaurant:“It’s very interesting to live with the locals.</s>
<s id="d25p5s6">We eat, sleep and go to the field with the host family members.</s>
<s id="d25p5s7">We cook with them and have a bath using medicinal herbs like local Red Dao people.</s>
<s id="d25p5s8">They prepare a large pot of medicinal plants for us.</s>
<s id="d25p5s9">We are very interested in their tradition.</s>
<s id="d25p5s10">We go up the mountain and visit Ms May’s relatives.</s>
<s id="d25p5s11">It is really interesting”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p6">
<s id="d25p6s1">Dang Thai Vinh, Mr.</s>
<s id="d25p6s2">An’s son has visited Sa Pa a couple of times.</s>
<s id="d25p6s3">This time, he wants to introduce his family members to other interesting things about Sa Pa besides Ham Rong mountain, Cau May Street and Silver Waterfall.</s>
<s id="d25p6s4">Vinh said:“I don’t want my family members to stay in the center of Sapa town because here the air is pure and good for health.</s>
<s id="d25p6s5">And above all, we have the opportunity to mix with Red Dao people to learn their culture, their customs and even their language”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p7">
<s id="d25p7s1">For a long time, on the last day of the year, Dao people has taken a bath with medicinal plants they pick from the nearby forest to welcome the New Year.</s>
<s id="d25p7s2">Having a bath with medicinal plants has become a tourist attraction in Ta Phin.</s>
<s id="d25p7s3">In a barrel of hot water, they put up to 120 different kinds of leaves.</s>
<s id="d25p7s4">Phan Man May says having a bath with medicinal plants is very good for health:“These leaves are picked in the forest.</s>
<s id="d25p7s5">When there is not enough, we have to buy them in the market.</s>
<s id="d25p7s6">Having a bath with medicinal plants, all our tiredness accumulated during the day is washed out.</s>
<s id="d25p7s7">It will make you feel relaxed and help you sleep well.</s>
<s id="d25p7s8">Tourists like it a lot.</s>
<s id="d25p7s9">In summer, it's easy to boil water, while in winter it takes us three hours”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p8">
<s id="d25p8s1">Adding medicinal leaves to the boiling pot, Dang Thai Vinh says he and his family members all feel relaxed after having bath with medicinal plants: "This solution of the Dao people is great for health.</s>
<s id="d25p8s2">We had to walk 13 km to get here but after taking a shower with the water, we all feel perfectly relaxed”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p9">
<s id="d25p9s1">Staying in a wooden house nestled in the mist, chatting over a wood fire, having a shower with wild leaves- these unique customs and traditions of the Red Dao people give visitors to Ta Phin some beautiful memories.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d26">
<p id="d26p1">
<s id="d26p1s1">Van Long Wetland Nature Reserve</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p2">
<s id="d26p2s1">Van Long Wetland Nature Reserve covers more than 3,000 hectares in Gia Vien district, Ninh Binh province.</s>
<s id="d26p2s2">This is a beautiful site that holds two national records for having the most Delacour's langurs and for being the largest unspoiled landscape in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d26p2s3">Van Long Nature Reserve is a popular eco-tourism destination.</s>
<s id="d26p2s4">Van Long is the largest wetland nature reserve in northern Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d26p2s5">On small bamboo boats, tourists travel through high reeds along small streams at the foot of the mountains to admire the reserve’s magnificent landscape.</s>
<s id="d26p2s6">Van Long is the most beautiful in the summer when the lotus flowers blossom.</s>
<s id="d26p2s7">Under the water, algae and other aquatic plants sway along with the rhythm of the oars.</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p3">
<s id="d26p3s1">Van Long is nicknamed “a bay without waves" because the water is as calm as a giant mirror reflecting mountains and clouds.</s>
<s id="d26p3s2">The reserve has a thousand caves, each with its own legend.</s>
<s id="d26p3s3">Do Thi Theu is a boat rower:“From here, one can clearly see rough lines on the cliff from the top to the foot of the mountain which look like marks left by the claws of a cat.</s>
<s id="d26p3s4">This cliff is listed in the book of Vietnam Records as "the largest stone mass”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p4">
<s id="d26p4s1">Cua Chua mountain in Van Long is a place where explorers and researchers have discovered centuries-old drawings.</s>
<s id="d26p4s2">Tran Xuan Quang is Head of the Reserve Management Committee: “On the cliff of Mount Cua Chua, scientists have discovered drawings.</s>
<s id="d26p4s3">Normally, they are not very clear, but when you pour water on them, you see drawings of men and women and ideograms.</s>
<s id="d26p4s4">It is a puzzle archaeologists are trying to figure out”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p5">
<s id="d26p5s1">Nature lovers will not be disappointed by Van Long.</s>
<s id="d26p5s2">The fauna and flora in Van Long typify the ecosystems of limestone mountains and Red River Delta wetlands.</s>
<s id="d26p5s3">The park has 39 fauna species and 722 flora species, many of which are listed in the Red Book of endangered species.</s>
<s id="d26p5s4">A hundred bird species live there.</s>
<s id="d26p5s5">At dusk flocks of birds head towards marshes and rice fields in search of food.</s>
<s id="d26p5s6">But the real star of Van Long is the Delacour’s langur, one of the most endangered primates in the world.</s>
<s id="d26p5s7">There are 40 Delacour’s langurs in Van Long.</s>
<s id="d26p5s8">Tran Xuan Quang again: "Van Long has biggest population of the Delacour’s langurs in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d26p5s9">You can see them on the mountains with your naked eye.</s>
<s id="d26p5s10">Even while sitting on the boat, you can see them.</s>
<s id="d26p5s11">The largest group of Delacour’s langurs lives on Hoang Quyen mountain.</s>
<s id="d26p5s12">In the early morning and in the afternoon, you can see monkeys eating or playing”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p6">
<s id="d26p6s1">The Dutch government, the Global Environment Facility (GEF) and the Cuc Phuong Rescue Center for Rare and Precious Primates are involved in preserving the endangered animal species in Van Long.</s>
<s id="d26p6s2">Van Long Wetland Nature Reserve receives a large number of foreign every year, most of them from Europe or South Korea.</s>
<s id="d26p6s3">Between May and September is the best season to explore the reserve.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d27">
<p id="d27p1">
<s id="d27p1s1">Phat Diem Cathedral</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p2">
<s id="d27p2s1">Covering nearly 22 ha in Kim Son district, Ninh Binh province, Phat Diem Cathedral is a popular destination.</s>
<s id="d27p2s2">Built in the 19th century, it differs from other monuments because of its stone chapel, which is a very successful marriage between eastern and western architecture.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p3">
<s id="d27p3s1">Along the way from Ninh Binh city to Phat Diem Cathedral, there are dozens of churches.</s>
<s id="d27p3s2">But, Phat Diem is the most remarkable because of its unique architecture.</s>
<s id="d27p3s3">It was built at the initiative of Father Pierre Luc Tran, known as Father Six for 34 years from 1865 to 1899.</s>
<s id="d27p3s4">This priest built a large cathedral surrounded by five chapels, plus a campanile, a pond and three manmade stone mountains.</s>
<s id="d27p3s5">The whole constitutes an original set which Western Gothic architecture blends perfectly with that of traditional Vietnamese pagodas.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p4">
<s id="d27p4s1">If we approach the cathedral from the south, we see a pond in the middle of which there is a statue of Jesus opening his arms wide.</s>
<s id="d27p4s2">Just behind it is a stone bell tower whose roof is curved like those on pagodas and communal houses.</s>
<s id="d27p4s3">The stone bell tower is built on 3 levels of large stone slabs and has 3 entries.</s>
<s id="d27p4s4">The first level, the largest, is made of square blue stones.</s>
<s id="d27p4s5">It has 3 rooms with ceiling vaults, each has with stone bed.</s>
<s id="d27p4s6">Do Thi Ngoc Anh is a tour guide:"The high arch symbolizes "round heaven" and the bottom stone bed symbolizes "the square earth", which perfectly matches the design of the Oriental concept of harmony between heaven and earth, between yin and yang.</s>
<s id="d27p4s7">The second level has a large drum and the third has a 1.4m high bell.</s>
<s id="d27p4s8">Cast in 1890, this bell weighs nearly 2 tons.</s>
<s id="d27p4s9">Unlike other church bells that contain a pendulum, Phat Diem’s bell contains a wooden stick that helps the bell be heard 10km away”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p5">
<s id="d27p5s1">After crossing the campanile, we look up to admire the front of the Great Cathedral, which is the heart of the Phat Diem architectural ensemble.</s>
<s id="d27p5s2">It was built in 1891 with the official name of "Cathedral of Our Lady Queen of the Rosary".</s>
<s id="d27p5s3">Supported by 52 pillars in 6 rows, it includes 9 bays that celebrate the East-West architectural combination.</s>
<s id="d27p5s4">The entrance is exactly like a Gothic church with its raised ceiling, but the columns are carved with typical oriental motifs, including Vietnamese.</s>
<s id="d27p5s5">Do Ngoc Hung is an architecture student:"I am very impressed by the altar of God.</s>
<s id="d27p5s6">The wooden walls are intricately carved and gilded.</s>
<s id="d27p5s7">The altar itself is in stone.</s>
<s id="d27p5s8">The carvings are superb.</s>
<s id="d27p5s9">I heard that the altar is made of 6 stone slabs in the basement housing the tombs of six bishops”</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p6">
<s id="d27p6s1">But the most precious jewel of the architectural ensemble of Phat Diem is the Chapel of the Immaculate Heart of Mary, which some call "the stone church." Do Thi Ngoc Anh told us:"This chapel is almost entirely built of stone, blue stone extracted from Mount Nhoi in Thanh Hoa province.</s>
<s id="d27p6s2">Outside, there are two towers, one of which carries a relief showing the pierced heart of Mary which symbolizes the immaculacy”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p7">
<s id="d27p7s1">The altar of Mary is made of stone.</s>
<s id="d27p7s2">Vietnamese artisans carved various motifs on the stone including phoenix, lotus, pine, chrysanthemums, bamboo, and plum blossoms.</s>
<s id="d27p7s3">At Phat Diem, mass is held in the main cathedral.</s>
<s id="d27p7s4">The surrounding chapels are dedicated to 4 different saints.</s>
<s id="d27p7s5">The chapel of St.</s>
<s id="d27p7s6">Joseph was built in 1899.</s>
<s id="d27p7s7">Its furnishings are made entirely of solid wood.</s>
<s id="d27p7s8">The quintessence of the ancient tradition of Vietnamese wood carving converges here.</s>
<s id="d27p7s9">Do Thi Ngoc Anh again: "South of the main cathedral is the Saint Roch chapel which was built in 1895.</s>
<s id="d27p7s10">The altar is a monolith.</s>
<s id="d27p7s11">To the west is the St.</s>
<s id="d27p7s12">Joseph Chapel, built in 1896 entirely of iron wood.</s>
<s id="d27p7s13">To the north of this chapel is the Saint Pierre Chapel, which was built in 1896.</s>
<s id="d27p7s14">The columns are made of jackfruit wood and are elaborately sculpted”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p8">
<s id="d27p8s1">Phat Diem Cathedral is a place of prayer and also a popular destination for researchers and tourists.</s>
<s id="d27p8s2">Dustin is from Canada: "It's beautiful.</s>
<s id="d27p8s3">It's unbelievable that this church was built in the 19th century by the Vietnamese.</s>
<s id="d27p8s4">It is typically Vietnamese and completely different from any I have had the opportunity to see.</s>
<s id="d27p8s5">Every detail reflects a perfect symbiosis between stone, wood, East and West".</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p9">
<s id="d27p9s1">The vagaries of the weather have not damaged the famous architectural ensemble, but mosses have made it more charming.</s>
<s id="d27p9s2">Behind every relief, every stone lurks something mysterious and sacred waiting to be revealed to visitors.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d28">
<p id="d28p1">
<s id="d28p1s1">Ninh Binh- the land of ancient capital</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p2">
<s id="d28p2s1">More than 90 km south of Hanoi, Ninh Binh is a province with rich tourist potential.</s>
<s id="d28p2s2">The splendid natural scenery of Trang An, Tam Coc and Bich Dong, the stone cathedral of Phat Diem, and the forest of Cuc Phuong are among the attractions of this beautiful land which was the capital of Vietnam a thousand years ago.</s>
<s id="d28p2s3">Ninh Binh has all the typical topography of northern Vietnam-mountain areas, foothills, coastal areas and low-lying plains.</s>
<s id="d28p2s4">Its diverse natural conditions favor countless plant and animal species, many of which are in the Red Book of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d28p2s5">There are four large forests: Cuc Phuong, Van Long, Hoa Lu and Kim Son which together form a large biosphere reserve.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p3">
<s id="d28p3s1">Ninh Binh is surrounded by mountains of limestone as strong as a fortress wall.</s>
<s id="d28p3s2">It is probably for this reason that the Dinh, Le and Ly dynasties choose Ninh Binh for their capitals from 968 to 1010.</s>
<s id="d28p3s3">Hoa Lu, the capital was called "the capital built of stone" by local people.</s>
<s id="d28p3s4">Located at the center, Hoa Lu holds the remnants of wars against foreign invaders and a multitude of temples, shrines, and pagodas.</s>
<s id="d28p3s5">More than a thousand years ago, in these valleys covered by reeds Dinh Bo Linh led a popular uprising that wiped out 12 army troops.</s>
<s id="d28p3s6">In 968, he ascended the throne and set his capital at Hoa Lu.</s>
<s id="d28p3s7">Six kings succeeded each other from 968 to 1009 in Hoa Lu.</s>
<s id="d28p3s8">In 1010, King Ly Thai To decided to move the capital to Thang Long, which today is called Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d28p3s9">Do Ngoc Anh is a tour guide:"The temples dedicated to the Dinh and Le kings have architectural and sculptural features of the 17th century.</s>
<s id="d28p3s10">The display objects dating from a thousand years ago.</s>
<s id="d28p3s11">There are pieces of earthenware bowls which were used at banquets given by the kings of the Dinh dynasty in honor of their victorious troops.</s>
<s id="d28p3s12">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p4">
<s id="d28p4s1">In the Trang An complex are the Trang An ecological site which has been named a World Heritage site, and Tam Coc-Bich Dong which is often called "Ha Long Bay on land." The Sao Khe River, which winds through the mountains, is the only thoroughfare in this area and the only means of transportation is a boat.</s>
<s id="d28p4s2">Limestone hills, valleys and streams alternate, creating a picturesque landscape.</s>
<s id="d28p4s3">Caves mesmerize tourists with their stalactites and stalagmites.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p5">
<s id="d28p5s1">Bai Dinh pagoda, also in The rang An complex, is like a book of Buddhist architecture which holds several national records.</s>
<s id="d28p5s2">It is actually two pagodas: the ancient Bai Dinh pagoda and Bai Dinh pagoda complex- the largest pagoda in Southeast Asia.</s>
<s id="d28p5s3">The pagoda is built on a historic site where more than one thousand years ago, Dinh Bo Linh’s insurgent troops gathered before and after each battle.</s>
<s id="d28p5s4">Do Ngoc Anh again:"Spring time between the first and third lunar month is the best time to visit Trang An.</s>
<s id="d28p5s5">Then, the weather is neither too cold nor too hot.</s>
<s id="d28p5s6">This is the season of pilgrimage.</s>
<s id="d28p5s7">In Trang An, tourists and pilgrims can enjoy the scenery and visit the pagoda to pray for good luck”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p6">
<s id="d28p6s1">In Ninh Binh province, many villages have retained their traditional crafts: Van Lam embroidery, Kim Son mat weaving, Ninh Van stone carving, Phuc Loc carpentry and Van Long basketry.</s>
<s id="d28p6s2">A visit to Ninh Binh province will provide you with many unforgettable memories.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d29">
<p id="d29p1">
<s id="d29p1s1">Museum of Ho Chi Minh Trail</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p2">
<s id="d29p2s1">Known as the "Ho Chi Minh trail", the supply route through the Truong Son mountain range is a legend of the Vietnamese resistance.</s>
<s id="d29p2s2">This story is now told in the "Museum of the Ho Chi Minh Trail”.</s>
<s id="d29p2s3">Poet Pham Tien Duat poet, a Truong Son veteran, wrote in the museum’s guest book: "We cannot lock up a mountain range in a house.</s>
<s id="d29p2s4">But the Museum of the Ho Chi Minh trail contains all the diamonds and precious minerals in this mountain range".</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p3">
<s id="d29p3s1">Located 16 km west of downtown Hanoi, the Museum of the Ho Chi Minh Trail boasts a contemporary architectural style.</s>
<s id="d29p3s2">It was inaugurated on April 10, 1999, on the 40th anniversary of Brigade 559, whose members built the legendary Truong Son trail crossing.</s>
<s id="d29p3s3">Director of the Museum Colonel Ngan Chai says the museum has a dual purpose: to preserve and display objects used by the Vietnamese troops who fought on this trail and to commemorate the solidarity between the Vietnamese, Laotians and Cambodians involved in the struggle: "The Ho Chi Minh Trail Museum is a continuation of the old Truong Son Museum which was established in 1968.</s>
<s id="d29p3s4">At that time, the museum’s staff were cadres and soldiers responsible for political and ideological education.</s>
<s id="d29p3s5">Their work helped galvanize the troops during the war".</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p4">
<s id="d29p4s1">Walking through the museum, you will learn about the Ho Chi Minh Trail, the route of strategic supply for anti-American resistance.</s>
<s id="d29p4s2">The museum covers ​​17,000 square meters and has three levels of exhibits on an area of 28,000 square meters.</s>
<s id="d29p4s3">At the entrance is a bronze sculpture representing the military corps which fought in the Truong Son mountain range.</s>
<s id="d29p4s4">Showrooms reproduce the chronological history of the Ho Chi Minh trail from the time when soldiers carried ammunition on their backs to the opening of paved roads in what the Western press called at the time "the labyrinth jungle”.</s>
<s id="d29p4s5">Colonel Ngan Chai said: "In 1995, our museum changed its name to the "National Museum of the Ho Chi Minh Trail”.</s>
<s id="d29p4s6">The museum inherited all the archives and all the artifacts of the Truong Son Museum.</s>
<s id="d29p4s7">We now have 20,000 objects.</s>
<s id="d29p4s8">Because the exhibition space can accommodate only 2000 objects, we organize regular exhibits to introduce all of our objects to the public.</s>
<s id="d29p4s9">We also organize mobile exhibits.</s>
<s id="d29p4s10">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p5">
<s id="d29p5s1">The Museum of the Ho Chi Minh trail fascinates visitors with its lively and creatively depiction of the exploits of the Vietnamese army.</s>
<s id="d29p5s2">In particular, the museum has a replica of a covered road, known as a K road, that was involved in the laser war.</s>
<s id="d29p5s3">Colonel Ngan Chai says it reflects the creativity of Vietnamese soldiers: "These covered roads were constructed in the shade of the jungle.</s>
<s id="d29p5s4">At the time, our troops often moved at night.</s>
<s id="d29p5s5">The US Air Force used lasers to detect Vietnamese military movements.</s>
<s id="d29p5s6">This is why the Truong Son soldiers had the idea of creating these covered roads to allow their vehicles to move during the day.</s>
<s id="d29p5s7">They bent branches of large trees or planted new trees and hung them with orchids to cover the roads.</s>
<s id="d29p5s8">In total, they created 3,000 km of covered roads.</s>
<s id="d29p5s9">This method had never been used before and was unprecedented in the history of war.</s>
<s id="d29p5s10">It enabled Vietnamese soldiers to transport ammunition to the southern front”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p6">
<s id="d29p6s1">The Museum of the Ho Chi Minh Trail is Vietnam’s third most visited museum, welcoming tens of thousands of Vietnamese and foreign visitors each year.</s>
<s id="d29p6s2">Colonel Nguyen Hai Binh is Head of the Display and Communications Department of the Museum: "Veterans, students and foreign tourists express their impression and sentiments for Truong Son soldiers.</s>
<s id="d29p6s3">Before coming here, many have read about Truong Son but visiting the museum brings them face to face with a legend.</s>
<s id="d29p6s4">For foreign tourists, Truong Son is not only a legend, it is also a subject of study.</s>
<s id="d29p6s5">They want to see all of our items".</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p7">
<s id="d29p7s1">These precious objects are closely associated with Vietnamese history and provide some excellent historical education for younger generations.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d30">
<p id="d30p1">
<s id="d30p1s1">Hanoi Opera House</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p2">
<s id="d30p2s1">Located in the heart of the capital city of Hanoi, Hanoi Opera House is only a prominent example of French architecture but also a venue that frequently hosts major events.</s>
<s id="d30p2s2">The Opera House is a tourist attraction and the pride of Hanoi.</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p3">
<s id="d30p3s1">The Opera House is located at No 1 Trang Tien Street, close to the Restored Sword Lake.</s>
<s id="d30p3s2">It was once described by Japanese architects as the most beautiful architectural site in Southeast Asia.</s>
<s id="d30p3s3">It resembles a sumptuous palace of colonnades and arches.</s>
<s id="d30p3s4">Strongly inspired by the Garnier Opera House in Paris, this building was built between 1901 and 1911 with the help of two French engineers Travary and Savelon.</s>
<s id="d30p3s5">The Opera House’s theater, stairs, lobby and entrance door embody the European architectural style of the early 20th century.</s>
<s id="d30p3s6">The building has an area of 2,600 m2, a length of 87m, a width of 30m and a height of 34m.</s>
<s id="d30p3s7">The large front veranda overlooks the August Revolution square.</s>
<s id="d30p3s8">In the 870-seat concert hall, the seats are covered with leather or velvet.</s>
<s id="d30p3s9">The second and third levels have private boxes for VIP guests and families.</s>
<s id="d30p3s10">At the rear of theater, there are administrative rooms, dressing rooms, rehearsal hall, a library and meeting rooms.</s>
<s id="d30p3s11">Near the main hall on the first floor is the prestigious hall of mirrors for meetings and cocktails.</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p4">
<s id="d30p4s1">The Hanoi Opera House was renovated in 1997 to host the Francophone summit held in Vietnam for the first time.</s>
<s id="d30p4s2">Architect Hoang Dao Kinh aided the restoration work: "Of all the architectural works in Vietnam, none has as beautiful and sophisticated zinc decoration zinc as the Hanoi Opera House.</s>
<s id="d30p4s3">Needless to say, the restoration was very difficult.</s>
<s id="d30p4s4">We called for tenders from French companies, but their prices were very high at that time costing several millions of dollars.</s>
<s id="d30p4s5">So we decided to use Vietnamese artisans.</s>
<s id="d30p4s6">They were extremely competent.</s>
<s id="d30p4s7">They created molds of 7-8 levels to restore the zinc decorations at a cost 4 or 5 times lower than that proposed by the French.</s>
<s id="d30p4s8">When French experts came to visit the Opera House after restoration, they all expressed their admiration for the Vietnamese artisans”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p5">
<s id="d30p5s1">Another challenge for the artisans was to restore the roof of the Opera House using stones from Lai Chau province instead of imported tiles.</s>
<s id="d30p5s2">With its restoration, the Opera House regained its extravagant beauty.</s>
<s id="d30p5s3">It is now a tourist attraction and a venue for concerts and art performances.</s>
<s id="d30p5s4">Nguyen Cong Cuong is a tourist: "I’m very impressed with the French architectural style of the Hanoi Opera House.</s>
<s id="d30p5s5">It is located on a beautiful square surrounded by other French architectural sites but it is the most impressive".</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p6">
<s id="d30p6s1">For the Vietnamese, the Hanoi Opera House and August Revolution Square are historic relics.</s>
<s id="d30p6s2">On August 19, 1945, Hanoians gathered in the square for a huge rally and then headed to the Palace of the Special Envoy of the King to seize power.</s>
<s id="d30p6s3">Today, the Hanoi Opera House is also a venue for conferences and important meetings.</s>
<s id="d30p6s4">It is part of Hanoi’s previous architectural heritage.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d31">
<p id="d31p1">
<s id="d31p1s1">Doing farm work in rural Hoi An</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p2">
<s id="d31p2s1">3 km from Hoi An, Tra Que village offers tourists a chance to stand in the shoes of a Vietnamese peasant, wearing a traditional conical hat and grow vegetables.</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p3">
<s id="d31p3s1">You can ride a bike from Hoi An to Tra Que village.</s>
<s id="d31p3s2">For the past ten years, the villagers have been welcoming foreign tourists who come to experience farming work.</s>
<s id="d31p3s3">Tra Que village which is famous for herbs grown with clean technology, is now a popular destination for tourists.</s>
<s id="d31p3s4">Do Thi Thanh is a farmer in Tra Que: “Tra Que herbs are aromatic with small leaves.</s>
<s id="d31p3s5">It takes us about 20 days to grow and harvest them.</s>
<s id="d31p3s6">I grow vegetables for wholesale.</s>
<s id="d31p3s7">I have been growing vegetables for more than 20 years.</s>
<s id="d31p3s8">Herbs are often used with chicken rice, salads, mussels and eggs.</s>
<s id="d31p3s9">Tourists come here to see and experience farm work.</s>
<s id="d31p3s10">We teach them how to plough the soil, apply fertilizer and water the vegetables.</s>
<s id="d31p3s11">Normally, it takes one hour to prepare the soil for a vegetable patch.</s>
<s id="d31p3s12">The tourists are very excited and happy.</s>
<s id="d31p3s13">They like doing this job”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p4">
<s id="d31p4s1">The village has a hundred families who grow mainly vegetables and herbs.</s>
<s id="d31p4s2">Le Thi Binh is a local farmer: “We never use chemicals, only water from the river to water the vegetables.</s>
<s id="d31p4s3">Vegetables and herbs grown here are very aromatic”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p5">
<s id="d31p5s1">Here, any villager can be your tour guide.</s>
<s id="d31p5s2">All are hospitable and welcome you with open arms and a smile.</s>
<s id="d31p5s3">Farmers in their field are always at your disposal.</s>
<s id="d31p5s4">Farmer Ho Xuan Thanh explains why herbs from his village are so famous:"The herbs grown here have a particular scent that cannot be found anywhere else.</s>
<s id="d31p5s5">The plants are small but packed with essential oils.</s>
<s id="d31p5s6">Our village definitely has special climatic and geological conditions.</s>
<s id="d31p5s7">Also, we used no fertilizer but freshwater algae.</s>
<s id="d31p5s8">The same varieties grown elsewhere do not have the same scent.</s>
<s id="d31p5s9">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p6">
<s id="d31p6s1">Tra Que village is not included in package tours, but it’s still a popular destination for Hoi An tourists.</s>
<s id="d31p6s2">Vuong Hoang is Director of the Cu Lao Cham Tour Company: “Most tourists enjoy this tour because it’s a new experience for them.</s>
<s id="d31p6s3">The vegetable village is an attraction for them.</s>
<s id="d31p6s4">They’re willing to spend 40 to 50 USD to be a farmer.</s>
<s id="d31p6s5">Vegetables here are naturally grown with algae so they have a special scent”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p7">
<s id="d31p7s1">Since 2004, Quang Nam provincial authorities have upgraded the village’s infrastructure and registered trade marks for Tra Que herbs to attract more tourists and protect the 400-year-old village.</s>
<s id="d31p7s2">It's been over ten years that the locals have been benefiting from this type of community tourism.</s>
<s id="d31p7s3">A visitor named Beth has just finished her work day in the field.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d32">
<p id="d32p1">
<s id="d32p1s1">My Son Sanctuary: an attractive destination</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p2">
<s id="d32p2s1">My Son Sanctuary has been named by touropia.com as one of the 10 most attractive destinations in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d32p2s2">The site was listed as a World Heritage by UNESCO in 1999 and is an outstanding example of the architecture of the Champa kingdom.</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p3">
<s id="d32p3s1">The scorching heat of summer doesn’t keep visitors from walking around My Son to admire the beauty of the temple.</s>
<s id="d32p3s2">The cool air inside the temple and the sound of cicadas singing outside the temple inspire the tourists.</s>
<s id="d32p3s3">Although many towers have been damaged, what remains is enough to amaze visitors, said one German tourist:“This is the first time I’ve come here.</s>
<s id="d32p3s4">I’m very happy because the temples here are beautiful.</s>
<s id="d32p3s5">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p4">
<s id="d32p4s1">With 70 buildings of brick and stone built between the fourth and thirteenth centuries, My Son was once the religious and political capital of the kingdom of Champa and the burial place of kings and monks.</s>
<s id="d32p4s2">In My Son, the object of worship is the linga, an upright stone and classic representation of Shiva.</s>
<s id="d32p4s3">The temple worships Bhardresvara, founder of the King Amaravati region near the end of the fourth century.</s>
<s id="d32p4s4">The main component is a tower honoring the divinity of the king.</s>
<s id="d32p4s5">It is surrounded by other smaller towers.</s>
<s id="d32p4s6">The pyramid-shaped towers symbolize Mount Meru, a mythical summit in Hinduism.</s>
<s id="d32p4s7">The architectural diversity of the place shows the talent of the Cham artisans who sculptured the towers with very expressive figures.</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p5">
<s id="d32p5s1">Today My Son has thirty brick towers, although most of them are in ruins.</s>
<s id="d32p5s2">This shrine is considered a museum where you can discover the culture of the Kingdom of Champa.</s>
<s id="d32p5s3">Architectural and sculptural works are mirrors of the minds of the Cham people, enabling us to understand their conception of the universe, life and death.</s>
<s id="d32p5s4">The sanctuary of My Son has been damaged by erosion and war.</s>
<s id="d32p5s5">But the site has been reborn from its ashes to boast a unique beauty that attracts tourists from around the world.</s>
<s id="d32p5s6">Dat Chu, who lives in Ninh Thuan, told VOV: "I’m very moved to visit the temple because it is here that I found my home.</s>
<s id="d32p5s7">The site has become a heritage.</s>
<s id="d32p5s8">Champa culture is mysterious, diverse and original.</s>
<s id="d32p5s9">Scientists have not finished unraveling all the secrets hidden in every brick and stone”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p6">
<s id="d32p6s1">In 2013, after 14 years of restoration, the public was allowed to visit temple G, one of the most important buildings at the site.</s>
<s id="d32p6s2">More than 60 objects from the temple were discovered and restored.</s>
<s id="d32p6s3">Federico, an Italian archaeologist who participated in the restoration of the temple between 2004 and 2005, said: "Before participating in this project, I read a lot about Champa culture.</s>
<s id="d32p6s4">But seeing the temples with my own eyes, it is superb!</s>
<s id="d32p6s5">The restored work is beautiful.</s>
<s id="d32p6s6">It's like a miracle”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p7">
<s id="d32p7s1">The My Son Sanctuary is a must-see in central Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d32p7s2">Just as picturesque as the famous temples of Angkor in Cambodia, the Bagan in Myanmar, or the Borobudur in Indonesia, My Son Sanctuary is a witness to the history of the Champa Kingdom and a World Heritage.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d33">
<p id="d33p1">
<s id="d33p1s1">Pha Din pass- path for artilleries to enter Dien Bien Phu battlefield</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p2">
<s id="d33p2s1">Pha Din pass, which is 32 km long, is the gateway to Dien Bien province.</s>
<s id="d33p2s2">Its highest peak is 1,648 meters above sea level.</s>
<s id="d33p2s3">60 years ago, Pha Din pass was the place from which soldiers pulled the artillery up the mountain to the Dien Bien Phu battlefield.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p3">
<s id="d33p3s1">The terrain of Pha Din pass now is not as difficult as before though there are still 8 sharp zigzag bends along the road.</s>
<s id="d33p3s2">Works has been done to lower the altitude of the pass and the width of the road has been expanded making it easier to go through it.</s>
<s id="d33p3s3">Pha Din pass becomes picturesque with green scenery dotted with the bamboo houses of the Thai ethnic minority people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p4">
<s id="d33p4s1">60 years ago, Pha Din pass was part of the pipeline supplying ammunitions and food to the Dien Bien Phu battlefield.</s>
<s id="d33p4s2">It was where 8,000 young volunteers, militia and workers carried ammunition and rice up the mountain everyday.</s>
<s id="d33p4s3">It was the place where ground forces and artillerymen marched through to Dien Bien Phu, whose secret name then was Tran Dinh.</s>
<s id="d33p4s4">Composer Hoang Van, who composed the song “Artillery pulling chant”, still remembers the marches through Pha Din pass 60 years ago: “Before entering Muong Thanh field, we had to go through a long zigzag pass on which some soldiers drove cars while other soldiers and laborers carried or pushed bicycles carrying supplies to the front.</s>
<s id="d33p4s5">The supply line began in late 1953.</s>
<s id="d33p4s6">The pass was dozens of kilometers and winding while French planes continuously dropped bombs destroying cars, trucks and bicycles carrying rice.</s>
<s id="d33p4s7">At that time, we had to be careful to avoid enemy bombings.</s>
<s id="d33p4s8">After that, we had to pull artillery up the mountain.</s>
<s id="d33p4s9">All these experiences inspired me to compose the song “Artillery pulling chant”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p5">
<s id="d33p5s1">Pha Din pass was the most difficult section in the journey of moving the artillery.</s>
<s id="d33p5s2">After Pha Din pass, the soldiers had to pull their weapons over many slopes, abysses and high peaks to move toward Him Lam base, Doc Lap hill, A1 hill and the De Castries tunnel.</s>
<s id="d33p5s3">The Dien Bien soldiers’ efforts to haul their weaponry are unimaginable.</s>
<s id="d33p5s4">Composer Hoang Van again: “As we hauled our ammunitions, dozens of people were arranged at each end of it.</s>
<s id="d33p5s5">At one end, some people pulled the artillery and at the other end, some people pushed it.</s>
<s id="d33p5s6">We used a winch and put a roller inside to pull the artillery.</s>
<s id="d33p5s7">Every time we heaved, we elevated the artillery on the roller, so that it could a step.</s>
<s id="d33p5s8">Once the enemy dropped a bomb and broke the winch, and our supplies rolled down the abyss.</s>
<s id="d33p5s9">Our hero To Vinh Dien then plunged under the artillery to save it”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p6">
<s id="d33p6s1">It is now about dozens of kilometers from Pha Din pass to Dien Bien city.</s>
<s id="d33p6s2">But during the Dien Bien Phu campaign, the length of the road was not calculated by kilometers but by the hardship that the soldiers suffered.There were different roads for carrying supplies to carry artilleries to the battlefield.</s>
<s id="d33p6s3">Some roads were used for just a few hours for artilleries to go through and then hidden by the forest as if they had never existed.</s>
<s id="d33p6s4">There was a special section of the road that was 15 km long and built within 20 hours running distance from Na Nham forest to Ngheu hamlet.</s>
<s id="d33p6s5">On that road, Vietnamese soldiers manually pulled 2.4-ton artilleries, 75 mm canons and 120 mm mortars through difficult mountains, deep abysses and enemy bombs to join the opening battle of the Dien Bien Phu campaign on March 13, 1954.</s>
<s id="d33p6s6">Pham Duc Cu was a former artilleryman at Dien Bien Phu: “Our condition was very harsh.</s>
<s id="d33p6s7">When we were 15 to 18 km from Dien Bien Phu, we had to pull the artillery manually.</s>
<s id="d33p6s8">It was the most difficult section of the road.</s>
<s id="d33p6s9">The Dien Bien artillerymen must have been made of bronze bodies and iron feet.</s>
<s id="d33p6s10">We will never forget the winding roads and slopes in Bay Toi, U Mau, Suoi Ngua and Voi Phuc, where we pulled 2.4-ton artilleries up to the battlefield”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p7">
<s id="d33p7s1">A monument to the memory of hero To Vinh Dien and his artillery platoon was erected 20 km from Dien Bien.</s>
<s id="d33p7s2">The monument reminds younger generations of Vietnam’s glorious history and the heroic soldiers of Dien Bien Phu.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d34">
<p id="d34p1">
<s id="d34p1s1">Kinh Bac- cradle of Great Viet civilization</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p2">
<s id="d34p2s1">Bac Ninh province is often referred to as the Kinh Bac- Northern region.</s>
<s id="d34p2s2">The name is associated with a land with a long history and ancient culture.</s>
<s id="d34p2s3">Previously, Kinh Bac consisted of Bac Giang province and Dong Anh and Long Bien districts of Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d34p2s4">The region is associated with several legends and is considered the cradle of the great Viet civilization.</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p3">
<s id="d34p3s1">Located in the center of the Red River Delta, Kinh Bac is blessed with fertile land, beautiful landscapes and favorable conditions for economic and cultural exchanges with other localities throughout the country.</s>
<s id="d34p3s2">Since the early years before Christ, the region was one of the cradles of the wet rice civilization and the founding place of the Great Viet civilization.</s>
<s id="d34p3s3">It is home to several relics, pagodas, towers, temples and stupas which were built under several feudal regimes.</s>
<s id="d34p3s4">Kinh Bac is also famous nationwide for its folk festivals, especially Quan Ho folk singing, which was recognized by UNESCO as an intangible cultural heritage of humanity.</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p4">
<s id="d34p4s1">Kinh Bac inspires visitors with its cultural and historical vestiges.</s>
<s id="d34p4s2">Dinh Bang village in Tu Son district is home to the stupas of 8 Kings of the Ly dynasties, Co Phap temple and Do temple, which worships 8 Kings of the Ly Dynasty from the 11th to the 13thcentury.</s>
<s id="d34p4s3">Nguyen Thac Kim is from the Management Board of Do Temple Relic: “The Ly dynasty built a unified monarchy, a unified country, and a unified government.</s>
<s id="d34p4s4">The Le dynasty also set up social, economic and cultural establishments contributing to the development of Vietnamese culture and civilization and the army.</s>
<s id="d34p4s5">During peacetime, people cultivated crops.</s>
<s id="d34p4s6">In wartime, they served as soldiers.</s>
<s id="d34p4s7">With such policies, the Ly dynasty developed a strong economy and successfully defended the nation”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p5">
<s id="d34p5s1">King Duong Vuong’s stupa and the Temple of Lac Long Quan and Au Co in A Lu village, Thuan Thanh district are also popular destinations.</s>
<s id="d34p5s2">The Luy Lau ancient citadel with market streets, temples and tower pagodas shows that this area used to be a political, economic, trade, Buddhism and Confucianism center of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d34p5s3">Thuan Thanh is also the home of various traditional crafts and folk arts such as the folk paintings of Dong Ho village, the Ca Tru singing of Thanh Tuong village, and water puppetry of Bui Xa village.</s>
<s id="d34p5s4">There are many relics in Thuan Thanh that are closely associated with the history and development of Buddhism in Vietnam including Dau pagoda and But Thap pagoda, which has several Buddha statues and valuable antiques reflecting Vietnamese people’s creativity in architecture and sculpture.</s>
<s id="d34p5s5">Nguyen Huu Nam is a cultural officer in Thuan Thanh:“But Thap is one of Bac Ninh’s most ancient pagodas.</s>
<s id="d34p5s6">There are several architectural structures and sculptured works typical of the 17th century in the pagoda.</s>
<s id="d34p5s7">They include the wooden statue of Bodhisattva Kuan-yin of a thousand eyes and hands and Bao Nghiem stone-sculpture tower, known as Pen Tower.</s>
<s id="d34p5s8">But Thap pagoda is one of the few that retains its ancient style.</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p6">
<s id="d34p6s1">Kinh Bac was the center of national defense and cultural development during Vietnam’s feudal regimes.</s>
<s id="d34p6s2">There is also the Bac Ninh Temple of Literature which honors more than 600 laureates of Bac Ninh, one third of the laureates nationwide under the feudal regimes.</s>
<s id="d34p6s3">Kinh Bac civilization is also reflected in the tradition, customs and lifestyle of the local people.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d35">
<p id="d35p1">
<s id="d35p1s1">Nam Yet- a coconut island</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p2">
<s id="d35p2s1">Located in the north of the Truong Sa (Spratley) Archipelago, in Khanh Hoa province, Nam Yet island is called the “Coconut island”.</s>
<s id="d35p2s2">From afar, the island is like a blue silk strait with ranges of coconut trees.</s>
<s id="d35p2s3">Today, Discovery Vietnam takes you on a tour of the island.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p3">
<s id="d35p3s1">With a width of about 200m and a length of 600m, Nam Yet island is oval-shaped.</s>
<s id="d35p3s2">Trees typical of Truong Sa archipelago are planted on Nam Yet island but coconuts are the most numerous.</s>
<s id="d35p3s3">Colonel Phan Van Dich, Deputy Head of the Logistics Department of Brigade 146, who has worked on the island for nearly 30 years, says that the soil on Nam Yet island is good for growing coconut trees: "When we arrived on the island, coconut trees were already there.</s>
<s id="d35p3s4">The elders told us that those coconut trees came from the mainland.</s>
<s id="d35p3s5">They are becoming more numerous as Nam Yet now grows seedlings to plant on other islands of the archipelago”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p4">
<s id="d35p4s1">It is difficult to count the number of coconut trees growing on the island but it is certain that the care given to these plants is an art that takes time and work.</s>
<s id="d35p4s2">Colonel Nguyen Van Tam, a Political Commissar of Group 1 on the island says that Nam Yet is paying closer attention to growing coconuts.</s>
<s id="d35p4s3">Dry and stunted coconuts will be nursed and when they are 30 cm high, will be transplanted to a garden.</s>
<s id="d35p4s4">Coconuts here are planted at 2 times: in the spring and whenever soldiers leave the island, because they want to plant a coconut tree as a souvenir.</s>
<s id="d35p4s5">Tam says:“I ​​was stationed on the island twice and I planted six coconuts.</s>
<s id="d35p4s6">Our team has planted another 14 coconut trees.</s>
<s id="d35p4s7">It takes time and efforts to grow coconuts even if the tree does not require much watering.</s>
<s id="d35p4s8">When the plants are large, we must remove dead leaves and place on top of the coconut a small packet of salt to make it produce more fruit and prevent disease.</s>
<s id="d35p4s9">"</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p5">
<s id="d35p5s1">Coconut trees are resistant to the harsh climate on the island.</s>
<s id="d35p5s2">They produce fruit throughout the year and particularly during the dry season.</s>
<s id="d35p5s3">A tree can provide 2 to 4 clusters coconuts.</s>
<s id="d35p5s4">Colonel Bui Van Thanh, Political Commissar of Group 3 on Nam Yet island, says: "Our group has planted nearly a hundred coconuts, of which 50 are already yielding fruit.</s>
<s id="d35p5s5">We reap the fruit only on special occasions such as Tet or during visits by people from the mainland.</s>
<s id="d35p5s6">We never count them but coconuts are numerous.</s>
<s id="d35p5s7">In recent years, the coconut trees gave many fruits thanks to good care”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p6">
<s id="d35p6s1">Products made from coconut trees are popular on the island.</s>
<s id="d35p6s2">The leaves are used to cover vegetable gardens and animal shelters.</s>
<s id="d35p6s3">Dried coconuts are used to scoop water.</s>
<s id="d35p6s4">Some skilled soldiers even embed shells to make nice gifts for their family and friends.</s>
<s id="d35p6s5">Colonel Tran Dinh Hoa is the Political Commissar on Nam Yet island: “We take good care of the coconut trees because they provide water and food for our soldiers.</s>
<s id="d35p6s6">Coconuts make the island green and they are strong enough to withstand the harsh conditions on the island.</s>
<s id="d35p6s7">Coconut trees are a symbol of Vietnam, representing Vietnam’s national sovereignty”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p7">
<s id="d35p7s1">Coconut trees stand majestically to protect the island from waves like the soldiers who spare no effort to defend national sovereignty.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d36">
<p id="d36p1">
<s id="d36p1s1">My Son Sanctuary: A unique and majestic heritage of humanity</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p2">
<s id="d36p2s1">Located in the central province of Quang Nam, 69 km southwest of Danang, the My Son Sanctuary is nestled in a closed valley.</s>
<s id="d36p2s2">With 70 towers embodying the historic, cultural, architectural and artistic values of Champa civilization, My Son is comparable to the most famous heritages in Southeast Asia including Borobudur of Indonesia, Pagan of Myanmar, and Angkor Wat of Cambodia.</s>
<s id="d36p2s3">My Son was recognized as a World Cultural Heritage Site by UNESCO in 1999.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p3">
<s id="d36p3s1">Built in the 4th century, My Son was once the religious and political capital of the Champa Kingdom and the burial place of kings and monks.</s>
<s id="d36p3s2">Architect Kazimiers Kwiakowski, who has studied My Son architecture for several years, says that from the 4th to the 13th century Cham people built this magnificent architectural work with their souls and hearts.</s>
<s id="d36p3s3">He describes the museum as a special sculpture museum of humanity.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p4">
<s id="d36p4s1">Within a radius of 2 km, towers and tombs in My Son reflect architectural influences of Indian religion.</s>
<s id="d36p4s2">There is one main tower in the middle and several smaller towers surrounding.</s>
<s id="d36p4s3">The main tower worships the Linga or Shiva statue.</s>
<s id="d36p4s4">In front of each tower, there is a place to arrange offerings and conduct ceremonial rituals.</s>
<s id="d36p4s5">All towers have a pyramidal roof and face east to receive sunlight.</s>
<s id="d36p4s6">Many towers are decorated with genie statues and beautiful patterns.</s>
<s id="d36p4s7">Huynh Tan Lap is Vice-President of the My Son Relic Management Committee."Hinduism is the religion practiced here.</s>
<s id="d36p4s8">The religion worships three main gods in the abstract form of the Linga and Yoni, which symbolize Yin and Yang.</s>
<s id="d36p4s9">In the Sanscrit language, Linga and Yoni represent masculinity and femininity.</s>
<s id="d36p4s10">The religion reflects the idea that there is Yin and Yang in the universe.</s>
<s id="d36p4s11">The Linga and Yoni are the main worshiping objects in the main temple."</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p5">
<s id="d36p5s1">Most of the towers are built of brick with a sophisticated technique.</s>
<s id="d36p5s2">Stone pillars are decorated with bas-reliefs of sandstone depicting scenes from Hindu mythology.</s>
<s id="d36p5s3">These are delicate and expressive sculptures reflecting the Champa arts.</s>
<s id="d36p5s4">Dat Chu, a Cham in Ninh Thuan says:"Champa culture is diverse and rich.</s>
<s id="d36p5s5">Researchers never finish discovering the secrets of Champa culture hidden in every brick and stone.</s>
<s id="d36p5s6">Not only me but all the Cham in Ninh Thuan are very proud”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p6">
<s id="d36p6s1">The architecture of My Son is the quintessence of Champa culture and arts.Wu Shang is a Chinese tourist: "I ​​went to Hue, Da Nang, Hoi An and My Son because there are only a few world cultural heritage sites left.</s>
<s id="d36p6s2">I have visited several shrines in the world but I must say that My Son is particularly well preserved."</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p7">
<s id="d36p7s1">My Son is known as a beautiful cultural treasure of the ancient Cham people and a lively architectural museum of the aesthetics of humanity.</s>
<s id="d36p7s2">Despite ravages of war and time, My Son Sanctuary stands as a witness to the history of the ancient Champa, and is an important part of the world’s cultural heritage.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d37">
<p id="d37p1">
<s id="d37p1s1">Hoi An in the eyes of foreigners</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p2">
<s id="d37p2s1">Hoi An ancient town with it mossy houses, wooden bridges and ancient wells dating back 3 centuries is always a magic magnet for both Vietnamese and foreign tourists Reputed to be the most charming town in Vietnam, Hoi An has become a key destination for foreign tourists passing through central Vietnam.</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p3">
<s id="d37p3s1">The first thing that strikes visitors upon arriving in Hoi An is the feeling of returning to the 16th century because of its ancient architecture, peacefulness and hospitality.</s>
<s id="d37p3s2">There are no horns.</s>
<s id="d37p3s3">Motorbikes are banned from 8:00 to 11:00, from 14h to 16h30 and from 18 h to 21 h.</s>
<s id="d37p3s4">This makes the city more peaceful and beautiful at meal time.</s>
<s id="d37p3s5">Mara Landoni, an Italian architect, thinks Hoi An is most beautiful in the morning: “I like walking around the town in the early morning when the street is not crowded.</s>
<s id="d37p3s6">I like to see people opening their shops.</s>
<s id="d37p3s7">It’s the best moment for me ".</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p4">
<s id="d37p4s1">In the morning, Hoi An seduces you with cobblestones, mossy houses and flowering bougainvillea.</s>
<s id="d37p4s2">Kiara is another Italian tourist.</s>
<s id="d37p4s3">She visited Hoi An after hearing about this magical place: “I think it’s very beautiful and amazing.</s>
<s id="d37p4s4">I like the architecture of the old town.</s>
<s id="d37p4s5">I like local people.</s>
<s id="d37p4s6">They are very friendly”.</s>
<s id="d37p4s7">Kiara’s impressions are shared by her son Francesco, who spent an unforgettable few days in this ancient Vietnamese town: “It’s very nice.</s>
<s id="d37p4s8">I like the lanterns lights and many things.</s>
<s id="d37p4s9">I like all the places including pagodas.</s>
<s id="d37p4s10">Our guide show us many interesting things”</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p5">
<s id="d37p5s1">If Hoi An is fairly quiet during the day, in the evening, it comes alive and sparkles in the lights of lanterns.</s>
<s id="d37p5s2">Tourists usually prefer Hoi An at night.</s>
<s id="d37p5s3">Sandra is a Latvian tourist: “It’s very pretty and calm.</s>
<s id="d37p5s4">At night, Hoi An is quite different.</s>
<s id="d37p5s5">The streets are lit by the light of candles and lanterns.</s>
<s id="d37p5s6">It is absolutely beautiful.</s>
<s id="d37p5s7">" Every street corner and house is decorated with colorful lanterns made by the local people.</s>
<s id="d37p5s8">Walking along the small lanes, listening to the sounds of wooden windchimes, melodious music on the street corners, and chanting on the Hoai river, visitors grow more and more enamored with Hoi An.</s>
<s id="d37p5s9">Nguyen Su is Secretary of the Hoi An Municipal Party Committee: “In the ancient streets at night, you have the feeling that everything is moving more slowly.</s>
<s id="d37p5s10">Walking around the streets, smelling the fragrance of aloe wood and listening to the unhurried sounds around you make you feel more relaxed.</s>
<s id="d37p5s11">The ancient town is like a stage play”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p6">
<s id="d37p6s1">Full moon nights are particularly conducive to exploring Hoi An.</s>
<s id="d37p6s2">When night falls, the town lights its lamps and is filled with delicious odors.</s>
<s id="d37p6s3">Hoi An is a place full of surprises and magic whose subtle gastronomy, textiles and decorations inspire tourists to return again and again.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d38">
<p id="d38p1">
<s id="d38p1s1">Lantern street in HCM City</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p2">
<s id="d38p2s1">Storeowners on Cho Lon Street, also known as lantern street, in District 5 of Ho Chi Minh City are busily preparing to welcome hundreds of visitors and shoppers during the upcoming Mid-Autumn Festival.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p3">
<s id="d38p3s1">Every year on the last days of the July lunar calendar Cho Lon Street alights with lanterns to welcome them.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p4">
<s id="d38p4s1">With only two weeks left to prepare there is little time for these storeowners to spare in getting ready.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p5">
<s id="d38p5s1">On the street there are nearly 100 stores selling all types of specialized lanterns.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p6">
<s id="d38p6s1">Pumpkin lanterns made of paper attract the attention of many.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p7">
<s id="d38p7s1">This year there are fewer battery-powered lanterns with Chinese music than in previous years, as shoppers prefer those made in Vietnam out of bamboo.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p8">
<s id="d38p8s1">Children prefer lanterns with animal collections.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p9">
<s id="d38p9s1">Traditional colourful star-shaped lanterns are always popular.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p10">
<s id="d38p10s1">There are lanterns everywhere.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p11">
<s id="d38p11s1">Both children and adults like vividly bright lanterns.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p12">
<s id="d38p12s1">Thousands of decorations to go along with the lanterns are also on sale.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p13">
<s id="d38p13s1">Prices aren’t marked on sale items but sellers are always ready to dicker on the price.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d39">
<p id="d39p1">
<s id="d39p1s1">Vietnamese donut</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p2">
<s id="d39p2s1">‘Banh ran’ is a delicious finger food for breakfast in Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d39p2s2">There are two main kinds of banh ran, namely salty cake and sweet one with the latter being much more common than the former.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p3">
<s id="d39p3s1">While the filling of sweet cake is sweet mashed mung bean, that of salty cake is quite similar to pillow cake‘s, a mixture of minced meat, prawn, glass noodle, veggie.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p4">
<s id="d39p4s1">What is more, among different types of sweet cake, the cake coated with sesame seeds is the best choice due to its moderate sweet taste, crispy cover and subtle fragrant.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p5">
<s id="d39p5s1">The dough is a blend of glutinous rice flour, rice flour, mashed potato and sugar.</s>
<s id="d39p5s2">Mashed mung bean filling is rolled into ball shape, wrapped inside the dough and then rolled over a plate of sesame to make its sesame coat.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p6">
<s id="d39p6s1">After deep-fried, the cake is getting golden brown, crispy and aromatic.</s>
<s id="d39p6s2">Hiding under that crispy cover is the sweet and nutty flavor of potato, rice, and mung bean.</s>
<s id="d39p6s3">So just relish it and discover how tasty it is!</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d40">
<p id="d40p1">
<s id="d40p1s1">Ganh Da Dia - Giant “beehive” in Phu Yen sea</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p2">
<s id="d40p2s1">Ganh Da Dia, which means Sea Cliff of Stone Plates, is a seashore area of uniformly interlocking basalt rock columns located along the coast in An Ninh Dong Commune, Tuy An District, Phu Yen Province in central Vietnam.</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p3">
<s id="d40p3s1">The area is about 100 meters wide and 250 meters long, composed of an estimated 35,000 columns of basalt rocks.</s>
<s id="d40p3s2">The rocks are dark lava columns with roughly flat surfaces of different shapes - round, pentagon, hexagon, polygon...</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p4">
<s id="d40p4s1">Ganh Da Dia looks like a gigantic beehive or pile of dinner plates, hence the name.</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p5">
<s id="d40p5s1">The rock columns were created from volcanic eruptions millions of years ago; when the molten basalt flows met cold water, they solidified and created polygonal formations due to thermal contraction.</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p6">
<s id="d40p6s1">Ganh Da Dia was listed as a National Heritage site in January 1998 by the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d41">
<p id="d41p1">
<s id="d41p1s1">Hectic Tuy Hoa fishing port at dawn</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p2">
<s id="d41p2s1">Visitors traveling to Tuy Hoa fishing port located in the coastal city of Tuy Hoa in Phu Yen Province at around 5 a.m.</s>
<s id="d41p2s2">will have a chance to see how local fishermen begin the day early in the morning.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p3">
<s id="d41p3s1">The fishing port is among the hectic trading places in the coastal city.</s>
<s id="d41p3s2">To local fishermen and traders, this is the most significant time when fishing boats laden with seafood return to the port after fishing trips.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p4">
<s id="d41p4s1">A lot of baskets full of freshly-caught seafood are transported ashore one after another by suntanned men whose weather-battered faces always show happiness for their work.</s>
<s id="d41p4s2">Meanwhile, traders swiftly pick some baskets containing the freshest seafood and then deliver to many other places.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p5">
<s id="d41p5s1">The fishing port is also very famous for the best tuna with certain ones weighing up to hundreds of kilograms.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p6">
<s id="d41p6s1">Heading for the trading area situated right in the port, visitors will get amazed by the bustle and hustle of buyers and sellers.</s>
<s id="d41p6s2">A wide variety of fresh seafood such as fish, crab, prawn and squid are offered for sale.</s>
<s id="d41p6s3">Some people say seafood bought at the port is not actually cheaper than in other markets but they can choose the freshest items.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p7">
<s id="d41p7s1">In addition to local people, a lot of tourists paying a visit to Phu Yen Province prefer going shopping at Tuy Hoa fishing port early in the morning.</s>
<s id="d41p7s2">They can also admire the beautiful sunrise over the horizon and fishing boats busily checking in and out at the same time.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p8">
<s id="d41p8s1">Despite hard work under the sun, Phu Yen fishermen always give a broad grin on their faces.</s>
<s id="d41p8s2">To them, every fishing trip full of fish is a great happiness in the daily lives.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d42">
<p id="d42p1">
<s id="d42p1s1">New life for Mekong floating market</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p2">
<s id="d42p2s1">The Mekong Delta province of Hau Giang is developing eco-tourism products based on its rivers, fruit orchards, and rural sights and life, according to its Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p3">
<s id="d42p3s1">They include Nga Bay floating market in Nga Bay town, an ecological tourism zone in Vi Thuy District and agriculture tourism in Vi Thanh city.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p4">
<s id="d42p4s1">Do Chieu Qui, the department’s director, said the province was undertaking a 35 billion VND (1.5 million USD) project to revive Nga Bay floating market for tourism purposes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p5">
<s id="d42p5s1">The market would be turned into one of the province’s key river tourism products, he said.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p6">
<s id="d42p6s1">Since the floating market was established in 1915 it was located at the meeting point of seven canals and rivers in Nga Bay town and become one of the delta’s busiest markets.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p7">
<s id="d42p7s1">But a decade ago local authorities moved it to a new site three kilometres away to improve traffic safety at the confluence, and the market’s activities began to dwindle because of the inconvenient location.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p8">
<s id="d42p8s1">The project to revive it is expected to be completed in 2019.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p9">
<s id="d42p9s1">At the 145ha ecological tourism zone, several tasks have been completed, including the dredging of a 14km canal and creation of a 13ha fruit orchard, 5ha bird garden and 11ha area for breeding wild animals and freshwater aquatic species.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p10">
<s id="d42p10s1">The zone is expected to be ready by the end of 2018, according to the department.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p11">
<s id="d42p11s1">The department is also working with relevant agencies and district authorities to conserve and develop historic and cultural relics, including the Temple of Uncle Ho, Can Tho Party Committee base and Relics of Chuong Dien Victory.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p12">
<s id="d42p12s1">The province has also set up community tourism sites at the Cau Duc pineapple farming area in Vi Thanh and Long Tri sweet mandarin area in Long My District and developed agricultural tourism in Vi Thanh.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p13">
<s id="d42p13s1">Hau Giang has zoned off a 130ha eco-tourism area at the Mua Xuan Agricultural Centre in Phung Hiep District.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p14">
<s id="d42p14s1">It also plans to develop eco-tourism at the 2,800ha Lung Ngoc Hoang Nature Wetland Reserve in Phung Hiep.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p15">
<s id="d42p15s1">Hau Giang, located in the delta’s central part, hopes to attract 160,000 tourists a year, including 18,000 foreigners, by 2020, according to its tourism development plan.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p16">
<s id="d42p16s1">Speaking at a meeting on August 12, the province’s Party Committee Secretary, Tran Cong Chanh, told local authorities to continue surveying sites so that appropriate tourism development plans can be made and human resources developed.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p17">
<s id="d42p17s1">The investment to develop eco-tourism sites should be linked with the national programme to build new rural areas, he said.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p18">
<s id="d42p18s1">The Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism should monitor and provide advice during the process of creating eco-tourism products at the Mua Xuan Agricultural Centre, he said.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p19">
<s id="d42p19s1">After two years of implementing the province Party Committee’s Resolution No.</s>
<s id="d42p19s2">9 on developing tourism, Hau Giang has also organised many tourism training courses for households in eco-tourism areas.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p20">
<s id="d42p20s1">On August 3, for instance, 40 farmers in Vi Thuy District were provided training in tourism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p21">
<s id="d42p21s1">The trainees also visited a community tourism model in the district.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p22">
<s id="d42p22s1">Le Quoc Chien, who has participated in a tourism training course, offers tourism services in his 1ha fruit orchard in Vi Thanh.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p23">
<s id="d42p23s1">He grows many kinds of fruits like durian, mangosteen, jack fruit, red flesh dragon fruit, mango and guava and also has ponds for tourists to fish.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p24">
<s id="d42p24s1">Le Minh Tam of Nga Bay town’s Nga Bay Ward developed his 5ha Burmese grape orchard into a tourism site in 2014.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p25">
<s id="d42p25s1">It receives about 100 tourists a day, and 300-400 during the peak Burmese grape harvest season.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p26">
<s id="d42p26s1">Tam has tied up with travel companies in HCM City and Vinh Long and Kien Giang provinces to bring tourists to his orchard, which has fruits between April and September.</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p27">
<s id="d42p27s1">“I plan to replace old Burmese grape plants with other trees like king orange and rambutan to ensure my orchard has fruits year round.”</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d43">
<p id="d43p1">
<s id="d43p1s1">Grilled sharpbelly - A specialty of Phu Yen Province</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p2">
<s id="d43p2s1">As simple as the dish is but grilled sharpbelly is a very famous dish in the land of Phu Yen where visitors can hardly ignore.</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p3">
<s id="d43p3s1">Like other freshwater fishes such as sand goby and white fish, sharpbelly is long and thin, up to an adult finger, usually live in herds in the rivers and streams.</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p4">
<s id="d43p4s1">Fresh sharpbelly is washed and grilled or fried then is cooked over charcoal fire.</s>
<s id="d43p4s2">When grilling, you need to always turnover each side so that its scab is cooked without being charred.</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p5">
<s id="d43p5s1">It is served with vegetables of all kinds, fresh rice noodles, rice paper with spicy sauce.</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p6">
<s id="d43p6s1">There are many ways to eat grilled sharpbelly, it can be served with fish sauce and rice.</s>
<s id="d43p6s2">But the most delicious way is to roll with ricepaper and other vegetables, such as lettuce, cucumber; fragrant basil; slip basil; and fresh beansprout along with spicy chilli fish sauce.</s>
<s id="d43p6s3">/</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d44">
<p id="d44p1">
<s id="d44p1s1">Diep Son islands - the most attractive beach in 2016 summer</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p2">
<s id="d44p2s1">Diep Son islands, located in the Van Phong Bay in the south central province of Khanh Hoa is well-known for its white-sand beach, crystal-clear water and the winding path connecting two islets.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p3">
<s id="d44p3s1">Diep Son islands consist of three small islets.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p4">
<s id="d44p4s1">There is the unique road on the islands.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p5">
<s id="d44p5s1">Crystal clear water.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p6">
<s id="d44p6s1">There are many beautiful, untouched beaches.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p7">
<s id="d44p7s1">Diep Son is among the favourite destinations of young people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p8">
<s id="d44p8s1">Catering services are available.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p9">
<s id="d44p9s1">5 experiences not to be missed in Vietnam</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p10">
<s id="d44p10s1">There's no point dipping your foot in the water; you have to dive right in on a trip to Vietnam.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p11">
<s id="d44p11s1">Vietnam boasts an abundance of beautiful sights to behold and delicious food to taste.</s>
<s id="d44p11s2">But if time is not your friend, here are five must-visit destinations that will guarantee you a trip to remember.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d45">
<p id="d45p1">
<s id="d45p1s1">Taking a train to Sapa</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p2">
<s id="d45p2s1">Sapa is a small town in the northern province of Lao Cai.</s>
<s id="d45p2s2">Dubbed the "the Tonkinese Alps", the region is home to hill tribe minority groups who farm on terraced rice fields.</s>
<s id="d45p2s3">Mount Fansipan, the roof of Indochina, stands tall at 3,143 meters right in the center of the Hoang Lien Son mountain range not far from Sapa.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p3">
<s id="d45p3s1">Taking a train from Hanoi to Lao Cai.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p4">
<s id="d45p4s1">The town, 376km north of Hanoi, is easily accessible by an overnight train from the capital.</s>
<s id="d45p4s2">One can take a bus too, but such a long journey is usually reserved for those with a thirst for adventure.</s>
<s id="d45p4s3">The train, on the other hand, is safe, cheap and convenient while still affording you a breathtaking view out of the window from a cabin that still breathes the air from the French colonial period.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p5">
<s id="d45p5s1">If you opt for the train, tickets should be booked at least a few days or even months in advance, especially if you plan to travel during public holidays such as Labor Day on May 1 or National Day on September 2.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d46">
<p id="d46p1">
<s id="d46p1s1">Drinking ‘bia hoi’ with locals</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p2">
<s id="d46p2s1">‘Bia hoi’, roughly translated as fresh beer, is a locally-brewed, preservative-free beer served at small bars and at street corners.</s>
<s id="d46p2s2">A visit to Hanoi is incomplete without a stop at the ‘bia hoi’ corner at the crossroads of Luong Ngoc Quyen, Ta Hien and Dinh Liet streets for a glass of 20 cent beer.</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p3">
<s id="d46p3s1">Most ‘bia hoi’ joints also serve inexpensive street food that goes well with the beer.</s>
<s id="d46p3s2">There are prawns barbecued with chili and salt, clams steamed with lemongrass, green mango with a prawn-chili-salt dip or coconut snails sautéed with butter and fish sauce.</s>
<s id="d46p3s3">Instead of a “proper” table, you’ll find yourself seated on tiny plastic stools, most likely blue, which also serve as mini tables.</s>
<s id="d46p3s4">As the alcohol kicks in, you’ll soon forget the discomfort in your legs to cheer the night away.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d47">
<p id="d47p1">
<s id="d47p1s1">Overnight cruise in Ha Long Bay</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p2">
<s id="d47p2s1">Ha Long Bay, the famous UNESCO World Heritage Site, is not to be missed in the northern province of Quang Ninh.</s>
<s id="d47p2s2">Spanning an area of 1,553 km2, the bay features thousands of limestone karsts formed over 500 million years and 2,000 islets that come in all shapes and sizes.</s>
<s id="d47p2s3">You can venture out onto the waters in a kayak, descend into mysterious caves or discover your own secret hideout among the thousands of islets.</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p3">
<s id="d47p3s1">The sunrise or sunset on a cruisewould take your breath away.</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p4">
<s id="d47p4s1">Travelers can book an overnight cruise that comes with a double room, breakfast, lunch and dinner.</s>
<s id="d47p4s2">As the sun comes up, you will be treated to piercing limestone karsts rising majestically out of the bay.</s>
<s id="d47p4s3">By evening, a candlelight dinner awaits you onboard under the stars and the moon, lighting the way for small fishing boats heading out for the night.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d48">
<p id="d48p1">
<s id="d48p1s1">Hoi An food heaven</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p2">
<s id="d48p2s1">Inside the ancient town of Hoi An lies a whole new world for you to discover.</s>
<s id="d48p2s2">And it’s not just 16th century houses for which this former port city has been recognized by UNESCO as a World Heritage.</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p3">
<s id="d48p3s1">On its small sidewalks and inside unassuming houses there are 1,001 street food specialties awaiting you.</s>
<s id="d48p3s2">Here are just a few to add to your bucket list, because you won’t find a cheaper or tastier equivalent anywhere else:</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p4">
<s id="d48p4s1">- ‘Mi Quang’, or Quang noodles, the central sister of pho, just bigger and with a pulpy rather than silky texture</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p5">
<s id="d48p5s1">- ‘Hen xuc banh trang’: Vietnamese burritos - sautéed clams eaten with crispy rice paper</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p6">
<s id="d48p6s1">- ‘Cao lau’: Brown noodles with pork and greens, only in Hoi An</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d49">
<p id="d49p1">
<s id="d49p1s1">Floating market in Mekong Delta</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p2">
<s id="d49p2s1">The Mekong Delta down south is criss-crossed with thousands of canals interlocking through fields and mangrove forests that have created a world of their own: life on water.</s>
<s id="d49p2s2">Put your bike aside and jump in a boat to discover tropical fruits on offer at floating markets.</s>
<s id="d49p2s3">The most famous ones include Cai Rang (Can Tho Province), Cai Be (Tien Giang Province), Phung Hiep (also called Nga Bay in Hau Giang Province), Long Xuyen (An Giang Province) and Tra On (Vinh Long Province).</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p3">
<s id="d49p3s1">Floating markets have long been the iconic feature of the Mekong Delta.</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p4">
<s id="d49p4s1">In the midst of hundreds of boats anchored next to each other, you’ll find huge crowds of buyers and seller bargaining over fruit, fish, poultry, fabric, home appliances and farming tools.</s>
<s id="d49p4s2">The goods are hung on long bamboo polls for customers to choose from.</s>
<s id="d49p4s3">For the more adventurous, you can go snake and snake wine shopping in Phung Hiep Market.</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p5">
<s id="d49p5s1">Vietnam's most beautiful lakes</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p6">
<s id="d49p6s1">Immerse yourself in stunning bodies of water from north to south.</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p7">
<s id="d49p7s1">These must-see lakes have become ideal tourist destinations for those who wish to escape their hectic lives and immerse themselves in nature.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d50">
<p id="d50p1">
<s id="d50p1s1">Ba Be Lake, Bac Kan</s>
</p>
<p id="d50p2">
<s id="d50p2s1">Ba Be lake, which means ‘Three Lakes’ in English, is located in the northern province of Bac Kan, about 240 kilometers northwest of the capital Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d50p2s2">Surrounded by limestone cliffs, Vietnam’s largest natural freshwater lake stretches about eight kilometers north to south and reaches depths of 35 meters.</s>
<s id="d50p2s3">It takes visitors at least two days to explore the lake, not to mention the nearby caves and a spectacular waterfall further upstream.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d51">
<p id="d51p1">
<s id="d51p1s1">West Lake, Hanoi</s>
</p>
<p id="d51p2">
<s id="d51p2s1">West Lake is Hanoi’s largest freshwater lake, located right in the center of the capital.</s>
<s id="d51p2s2">The lake draws scores of foreign tourists as well as local citizens who wish to see a thin blanket of mist rise over the surface at sunrise and sunset.</s>
<s id="d51p2s3">Take a trip around the lake to see how people live and fish, and you will forget all about the city’s crazy traffic.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d52">
<p id="d52p1">
<s id="d52p1s1">Song Muc Lake, Thanh Hoa</s>
</p>
<p id="d52p2">
<s id="d52p2s1">Set in Ben En National Park in the northern coastal province of Thanh Hoa, Song Muc Lake is the main tourist attraction.</s>
<s id="d52p2s2">Filled by the Muc River and four other streams, the water is always crystal clear throughout the year.</s>
<s id="d52p2s3">Together with a group of 21 floating islands, tourists can enjoy sightseeing excursions by boat or kayak.</s>
<s id="d52p2s4">They can also experience daily life and cast their lines at a spot of fishing.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d53">
<p id="d53p1">
<s id="d53p1s1">Ke Go Lake, Ha Tinh</s>
</p>
<p id="d53p2">
<s id="d53p2s1">Ke Go Lake was built in 1976 in the central province of Ha Tinh.</s>
<s id="d53p2s2">It is the largest irrigation project in the province, and holds 350 million cubic meters of water.</s>
<s id="d53p2s3">Covered by natural forests with abundant flora and fauna, Ke Go Lake has been visited by both national and international scientists.</s>
<s id="d53p2s4">Tourists who reach Ke Go can now take a boat to take in water pouring down from the mountain, have a picnic along the banks and enjoy grilled fish, a specialty of the region.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d54">
<p id="d54p1">
<s id="d54p1s1">Tuyen Lam Lake, Lam Dong</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p2">
<s id="d54p2s1">No one knows for sure when and why the lake was called Tuyen Lam, but many think that Tuyen stands for stream and Lam stands for forest.</s>
<s id="d54p2s2">Tuyen Lam is a place where water and trees meet.</s>
<s id="d54p2s3">Located in the Central Highland province of Lam Dong, where the dry season lasts up to six months, the lake is full of water all year round.</s>
<s id="d54p2s4">If viewed from the cable hanger above, Tuyen Lam Lake is as a miniature ocean with each island oasis on the lake representing a continent.</s>
<s id="d54p2s5">Here tourists have a chance to enjoy the cool highlands air, explore the cultural patterns of ethnic groups and join in exciting activities like elephant riding.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d55">
<p id="d55p1">
<s id="d55p1s1">To Nung Lake, Gia Lai</s>
</p>
<p id="d55p2">
<s id="d55p2s1">Located six kilometers north of downtown Pleiku in the Central Highland province of Gia Lai, To Nung Lake is in fact a volcanic crater formed millions of years ago.</s>
<s id="d55p2s2">The lake has a surface of 280 hectares (692 acres) and an average depth of 16-19 meters, reaching 40 meters at its deepest.</s>
<s id="d55p2s3">Visitors can discover To Nung Lake by boat, but they can also choose to enjoy the beautiful landscapes from the back of an elephant.</s>
<s id="d55p2s4">In the evening, they can share a dance, a song or some wine with local ethnic people while listening to their traditional music.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d56">
<p id="d56p1">
<s id="d56p1s1">Romantic Bo Bo Pine Forest</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p2">
<s id="d56p2s1">Around 25km southwest of Da Nang, the Bo Bo Pine Forest is situated in Dien Tien Commune in Quang Nam Province’s Dien Ban District.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p3">
<s id="d56p3s1">The forest consists of 4 small hills located in an area covering more than 200ha.</s>
<s id="d56p3s2">The forest boasts romantic natural landscapes thanks to its beautiful pine trees, birds singing, peaceful lakes, and year-round cool weather.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p4">
<s id="d56p4s1">Tran Van Dung, a local young photographer, is a typical example.</s>
<s id="d56p4s2">He said “I accidentally saw Bo Bo Pine Forest when I was on my way to Dai Loc District.</s>
<s id="d56p4s3">I was mesmerised by the forest’s amazing natural landscapes, and decided to take some photos and upload them on my Facebook page.</s>
<s id="d56p4s4">Many people from my Facebook friends list were also deeply impressed by the beauty of the area, and they asked me to take them there”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p5">
<s id="d56p5s1">With the highest hill standing 55 meters above sea level, from its summit visitors can admire the amazing panoramic views over the northern side of Quang Nam Province, the eastern side of the province’s Dai Loc District, and the southern side of Da Nang.</s>
<s id="d56p5s2">Thanks to this, the area has now become a popular venue for backpackers and hotographers from Da Nang.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d57">
<p id="d57p1">
<s id="d57p1s1">Nhat Lam Thuy Trang Tra ecotourism site - a peaceful and romantic venue</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p2">
<s id="d57p2s1">About 10km east of Da Nang, the Nhat Lam Thuy Trang Tra ecotourism site on the Son Tra peninsula boasts a simple, poetic beauty set amongst outstanding nature</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p3">
<s id="d57p3s1">The site’s owner, Mr Pham Truong Mai, said that the site was created in 2007 and was originally named ‘Truong Mai’ after him.</s>
<s id="d57p3s2">A few years later, it was renamed ‘Nhat Lam Thuy Trang Tra’, which implies a beautiful natural area featuring mountains, water, green trees and grass.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p4">
<s id="d57p4s1">Over recent years, Mr Mai and his family have taken advantage of the site’s natural conditions to raise wild boars and backyard chickens, farm fish, and plant wild vegetables.</s>
<s id="d57p4s2">This has helped his family to increase their production activities, and become involved in protecting the forest.</s>
<s id="d57p4s3">Thanks to its beautiful landscapes and airy spaces, ‘Nhat Lam Thuy Trang Tra’ is now attracting a great deal of attention from local residents and visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p5">
<s id="d57p5s1">The path to the ecotourism site is quite romantic thanks to the green trees and grass alongside.</s>
<s id="d57p5s2">From the peninsula’s Ban Co Peak (Chess Board Peak), visitors need to go straight on until they meet a T-junction and then turn left.</s>
<s id="d57p5s3">They continue going straight ahead for several kilometres until they come to the site.</s>
<s id="d57p5s4">Interestingly, some of the bends on the road leading to the venue will challenge drivers with their 40% uphill slope.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p6">
<s id="d57p6s1">Visitors to the site have the opportunity to enjoy a wide range of delicious rustic dishes made from the backyard chickens, farm-bred wild boars, and wild vegetables.</s>
<s id="d57p6s2">Most notably, the coconut wine is highly recommended for people who love a light and sweet spirit which is fermented from coconut water.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d58">
<p id="d58p1">
<s id="d58p1s1">New attractions for tourists</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p2">
<s id="d58p2s1">To create variety and novelty for visitors to Da Nang, many local young people are trying to develop new and special tourist attractions.</s>
<s id="d58p2s2">The ‘Chan Troi Goc Be’ (All Corners of the World) eco-restaurant is a typical example.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p3">
<s id="d58p3s1">Located on Le Van Duyet at the foot of the Thuan Phuoc Suspension Bridge, the eco-restaurant is the perfect venue for anyone who wants to enjoy relaxing moments away from the hustle and bustle of the city, or interesting outdoor activities with their relatives and friends.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p4">
<s id="d58p4s1">The 5,000m2 area features many spacious bamboo watch-towers which bring its customers relaxation, peace, and tranquility.</s>
<s id="d58p4s2">On display are mounds of straw and rice straw-woven items, as well as re-creations of images of rural areas.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p5">
<s id="d58p5s1">In addition, visitors have the opportunity to be immersed in nature by participating in collective games on the spacious grassland or in water sports such as boat racing and floating water bike cycling.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p6">
<s id="d58p6s1">Another example is the company MTV Nguyen-Eco which specialises in offering sea and island tours.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p7">
<s id="d58p7s1">Mr Duong Van Nguyen, the company’s Deputy Director, said that Da Nang welcomes an increasing number of international visitors, but they seem to prefer to experience ecological tourism activities in Hoi An rather than take tours around the city.</s>
<s id="d58p7s2">Yet the city possesses many time-honoured traditional crafts which have great potential for the development of eco-tourism.</s>
<s id="d58p7s3">Included are the making of sedge mats in Cam Ne Village and bamboo knitting in Yen Ne.</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p8">
<s id="d58p8s1">He remarked, “To meet the increasing demand from foreigners for this type of tourism, my company has launched a ‘Nguyen Eco ecotourism’ tour along the banks of the Cam Le River.</s>
<s id="d58p8s2">Enjoying the tour, visitors will have the opportunity to experience sedge mat-making or picking vegetables themselves to prepare their own meals”.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d59">
<p id="d59p1">
<s id="d59p1s1">Developing tourist attractions in Hoa Vang District</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p2">
<s id="d59p2s1">Over recent years, many domestic and foreign visitors arriving in Da Nang have been attracted to the rustic tourism products and tourist sites in Hoa Vang District.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p3">
<s id="d59p3s1">About 20 km west of the city, the 186ha Hoa Trung Lake in the district’s Hoa Lien Commune boasts a peaceful and simple charming beauty with numerous artificial floating islands and smooth green grass.</s>
<s id="d59p3s2">During the days of shallow water in the summer, the lakeside area is larger and looks like a vast and quiet steppe.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p4">
<s id="d59p4s1">According to a Vietnamese website, this place is as beautiful as the renowned Mongolian-Manchurian steppe.</s>
<s id="d59p4s2">Thanks to its impressive beauty, the lake has now become very popular with residents from Da Nang who want to take part in outdoor activities or stay overnight here with their friends and family members.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p5">
<s id="d59p5s1">In addition to the peaceful lake, the district is famous for around 100 ancient houses which are all over 100 years old.</s>
<s id="d59p5s2">Amongst them, the 200-year-old Tich Thien Duong house in Hoa Nhon Ward’s Thai Lai Village has become a must-visit place.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p6">
<s id="d59p6s1">This house keeps intact some of the unique architectural characteristics of an ancient traditional Vietnamese house, including a moss-covered roof, sophisticated carved patterns, and east and west-facing rooms in accordance with the ancient Oriental architecture.</s>
<s id="d59p6s2">In addition, many old utensils are kept in the house, such as a flour mill, rice mortar, cake mold and coal iron, and these reflect the rural life of the past.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p7">
<s id="d59p7s1">A group from the municipal Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism and other local relevant agencies recently surveyed the new tourism products in Thai Lai Village.</s>
<s id="d59p7s2">The intention was to find ways to boost the development of the local river tourism with the aim of starting a new boat tour, developing new tourist attractions, and building a trip boat pier there.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p8">
<s id="d59p8s1">The Han River-Tuy Loan Village-Thai Lai Village sightseeing boat tour will provide an opportunity for visitors to enjoy the beauty of the city’s bridges across the river, the La Huong vegetable growing area in Cam Le District, the Tuy Loan Village Communal House, the Tich Thien Duong house, and numerous fruit-laden orchards in Thai Lai Village.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p9">
<s id="d59p9s1">In an attempt to develop tourism products featuring the special characteristics of the land and people of Hoa Vang District, Mr Nguyen Thuc Dung from the district’s Culture and Sports Office stressed the need to make the existing popular tourist sites more attractive to both domestic and foreign visitors.</s>
<s id="d59p9s2">Top priority should be given to promoting community-based eco-tourism in Thai Lai Village because this type of tourism will prove effective in this rural area.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d60">
<p id="d60p1">
<s id="d60p1s1">Peaceful Hoa Trung Lake</s>
</p>
<p id="d60p2">
<s id="d60p2s1">About 20 km west of Da Nang, Hoa Trung Lake in Hoa Vang District’s Hoa Lien Commune supplies water for the daily lives and agricultural activities of local residents in the Hoa Son and Hoa Lien communes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d60p3">
<s id="d60p3s1">The lake boasts a peaceful and simply charming beauty with numerous artificial floating isles and smooth green grass.</s>
<s id="d60p3s2">During the days of shallow water, the lakeside area is larger and looks like a vast and quiet steppe.</s>
</p>
<p id="d60p4">
<s id="d60p4s1">Visitors to the site will also be impressed by the images of a Vietnamese rural village, such as herds of cows and buffalo eating on the grass, and white storks flying across the sky.</s>
</p>
<p id="d60p5">
<s id="d60p5s1">Thanks to its impressive beauty, the lake has now become very popular with residents from Da Nang who want to take part in outdoor activities or stay overnight here with their friends and family members.</s>
<s id="d60p5s2">In addition, the site is drawing a great attention from the city’s amateur photographers who want to capture the amazing beauty of the lake.</s>
</p>
<p id="d60p6">
<s id="d60p6s1">Local photographer Minh Tran said that he often takes photos at the lake, and sees many young couples from Da Nang visiting there to shoot beautiful photos before their weddings.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d61">
<p id="d61p1">
<s id="d61p1s1">Ngoc (Ruby) Island - an attractive venue for outdoor activities</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p2">
<s id="d61p2s1">Located about 15km off the Da Nang coast, Ngoc (Ruby) Island is an excelllent place for anyone who wants to enjoy relaxing moments away from the hustle and bustle of the city, or fascinating outdoor activities with their relatives and friends.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p3">
<s id="d61p3s1">The island is locally called by several different names such as Hon Chao, Hon Son Tra and Han Island.</s>
<s id="d61p3s2">It can be reached in 10 minutes by speedboat or 40 minutes by tourist boat from the Han River.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p4">
<s id="d61p4s1">Despite being only 1.5km wide, the island features mountains, waters and large rocks heaped together.</s>
<s id="d61p4s2">It is home to diverse and rich marine animal and plant populations, including 144 species of corals, 135 species of seaweed, and 162 species of colourful fish.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p5">
<s id="d61p5s1">Visitors to the venue can enjoy the sounds of splashing waves and wind whilst walking barefoot on the white sand.</s>
<s id="d61p5s2">In addition, they can take the opportunity to participate in interesting water sports, including jet-skiing, kayak racing, parachute surfing, and going fishing with local fishermen.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p6">
<s id="d61p6s1">Mr Ho Minh Dung from Ha Noi’s Hoan Kiem District said that he was deeply impressed by the fascinating activities on the island, such as going seine net fishing, collecting rock and 'vu nang' (her breast) snails, and diving to explore the colourful corals and fish.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d62">
<p id="d62p1">
<s id="d62p1s1">Hai Van Pass, a challenge for new and experienced bikers</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p2">
<s id="d62p2s1">The 24km scenic and zigzagging road of the Hai Van Pass is always a favourite of motorbike adventurers.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p3">
<s id="d62p3s1">The top of Hai Van Pass, which is the frontier between Thua Thien-Hue Province and Da Nang City, still boasts the historic brick Hai Van Gate, built under the Tran dynasty in 1470, when King Tran Nhan Tong proclaimed that Hai Van was ‘the most marvelous wonder'.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p4">
<s id="d62p4s1">The pass, popular for motorbike drivers since the Hai Van Tunnel became operational in 2005, is quiet and safe for off-road bikers and tourists.</s>
<s id="d62p4s2">But the bends on the road still challenge drivers with a 15 percent uphill slope.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p5">
<s id="d62p5s1">The mountain top is always covered by clouds, and often has a cool temperature of about 17 degrees Celsius.</s>
<s id="d62p5s2">Drivers can face difficulties due to fog on rainy days and also late in the evening.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p6">
<s id="d62p6s1">Tourists can reach the top of the pass and return to find a rest stop at the base of the mountain in Da Nang.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p7">
<s id="d62p7s1">The Mekong Hai Van rest stop at the base of the mountain is often a stop for trans-Viet Nam travellers, and for camping as well as a rendezvous point for weekend team-building activities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p8">
<s id="d62p8s1">It's also the first stop just 2km after the Hai Van Tunnel – the longest tunnel in ASEAN, connecting Thua Thien-Hue province and Da Nang city – for people travelling a long distance by bus or motorbikes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p9">
<s id="d62p9s1">The main two-storey building, with a 200m–diameter conical structure, has souvenir shops and food corners for visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d62p10">
<s id="d62p10s1">Pham Van Tuan, the manager of the Mekong Hai Van restaurant, said three restaurants with 2,500 seats offered a large and relaxed space for travellers.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d63">
<p id="d63p1">
<s id="d63p1s1">Am Phu Cave – a mysterious trip to hell</s>
</p>
<p id="d63p2">
<s id="d63p2s1">Da Nang’s Marble Mountains is renowned for its numerous mysterious caves.</s>
<s id="d63p2s2">Most notably, the Am Phu (Hell) Cave is the longest and most mysterious at this tourist site.</s>
</p>
<p id="d63p3">
<s id="d63p3s1">The 302m-long cave is located inside Thuy Son (Water Mountain), which is one of the 5 mountains symbolising the basic elements of ancient oriental philosophy.</s>
<s id="d63p3s2">The arches of the natural cave range from 45m to 50m, and there are impressive rock formations featuring the Buddhist perception of hell or purgatory.</s>
</p>
<p id="d63p4">
<s id="d63p4s1">The cave has 2 sets of stairs - one up to heaven, and the other down to hell.</s>
<s id="d63p4s2">Buddhist monk Thich Hue Hung was monitoring the restoration of the cave between 2003 and 2006.</s>
<s id="d63p4s3">In his explanation of the Buddhist philosophy of causality, he said that those who did good deeds in life would be guaranteed a trip to the cave’s 'Thien Thai Gioi' (Paradise) immediately upon their death, whilst anyone committing wrong or evil actions would descend to the 10 circles of hell, and especially to the ‘Nguc A Ty’ (A Ty Jail), which is the cave’s deepest point.</s>
</p>
<p id="d63p5">
<s id="d63p5s1">Walking through the impressive stalactites and stalagmites, visitors cannot fail to be impressed by the cave’s Purgatory section, through which sinners’ souls must first pass to be punished.</s>
<s id="d63p5s2">There is also a court where hell’s judges evaluate a sinner's acts and decide on the level of punishment.</s>
<s id="d63p5s3">In the middle of the cave is a statue of the Ksitigarbha Bodhisattva who is often referred to as the Bodhisattva of the Hell beings.</s>
<s id="d63p5s4">Here, a spiritual scale is used to weigh one’s good and bad deeds.</s>
<s id="d63p5s5">Most notably, the cave has many man-made sculptures showing threatening scenes of punishment.</s>
</p>
<p id="d63p6">
<s id="d63p6s1">The Am Phu Cave features a harmonious combination of folklore and Buddhism's valuable philosophy of humanity.</s>
<s id="d63p6s2">The scenes of horror mentioned-above intend to educate human beings about doing good deeds in life and to ‘turn over a new leaf’ to stop a bad habit or make a positive change to their characters.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d64">
<p id="d64p1">
<s id="d64p1s1">Hoa My Sakyamuni Buddha Statue</s>
</p>
<p id="d64p2">
<s id="d64p2s1">The Hoa My Sakyamuni Buddha Statue is situated near the Quang Minh Pagoda in Lien Chieu District’s Hoa Minh Ward, about 7km west of the inner city.</s>
<s id="d64p2s2">The 20m-high statue sits on a 10m-high lotus-shaped pedestal.</s>
</p>
<p id="d64p3">
<s id="d64p3s1">Built in 1965, the statue has 5 floors inside.</s>
<s id="d64p3s2">The 1st floor, with a diameter of 9.6m, has been used as a Buddhist library for the past 5 years.</s>
<s id="d64p3s3">On the left-hand side of the 1st floor’s front door, 29 internal steps lead up to the 2nd floor which is an exhibition area for Buddha statues, calligraphic paintings, and pictures of Bodhidharma.</s>
</p>
<p id="d64p4">
<s id="d64p4s1">From the 2nd floor, there is a 26-step staircase leading to the 3rd floor which showcases calligraphy and watercolour paintings.</s>
<s id="d64p4s2">From here, a further 23 steps lead up to the 4th floor and the display of a Buddha Shakyamuni Statue, and another 23 lead visitors to the top floor.</s>
<s id="d64p4s3">Between the 4th and 5th floors there is a 60cm-diameter circular window from which visitors can enjoy an amazing panoramic view of this part of the city.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d65">
<p id="d65p1">
<s id="d65p1s1">Tran Thi Ly Bridge - a striking landmark</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p2">
<s id="d65p2s1">Da Nang’s Tran Thi Ly Bridge is the fifth bridge up the Han River, about 1 km south of the Rong (Dragon) Bridge.</s>
<s id="d65p2s2">The construction of the 1,709 billion VND bridge began in April 2009, and it was officially opened to traffic on 29 March 2013.</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p3">
<s id="d65p3s1">With its suspension cables, the bridge forms an upside-down capital “Y” and is intended to look like sails facing towards the East Sea.</s>
<s id="d65p3s2">The bridge has emerged as a must-see feature of Da Nang and an ideal place for visitors who like taking souvenir photos during their stay in the city.</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p4">
<s id="d65p4s1">It is believed that the bridge, with the image of sails filled with wind, not only shows charming and gentle characteristics, but also symbolises the city’s aspirations for further development in the future.</s>
<s id="d65p4s2">It has one of the most unique architectural styles of all the bridges in Viet Nam.</s>
<s id="d65p4s3">A striking feature of its design is the 145m-high, backwards-leaning single tower which creates the eye-catching form of the bridge.</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p5">
<s id="d65p5s1">The bridge was named after Vietnamese revolutionary activist Tran Thi Ly from Quang Nam Province’s Dien Ban District, whose real name was Tran Thi Nham.</s>
<s id="d65p5s2">She was a member of the Viet Nam People’s Army and the South Viet Nam Liberation Army.</s>
<s id="d65p5s3">During the past two resistance wars, even though Miss Ly was brutally and inhumanely tortured in the prisons of the invaders, she showed her indomitable spirit and admirable bravery, and she never revealed any of Viet Nam’s revolutionary strategies and plans to the enemy.</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p6">
<s id="d65p6s1">Before the building of the Tran Thi Ly Bridge could begin, an older bridge had to be removed from the same site.</s>
<s id="d65p6s2">Built by the French over 60 years ago, the De Lattre Bridge was the first bridge to span across the Han River.</s>
<s id="d65p6s3">In the 1950s, experts from the USA arrived in Da Nang to conduct surveys on the Son Tra Peninsula and the Marble Mountains.</s>
<s id="d65p6s4">At that time, the French colonisers embarked on turning Da Nang into a military base through the construction of new infrastructure and upgrading the existing.</s>
<s id="d65p6s5">Amongst the new constructions was the De Lattre Bridge to link the inner-city with the port of Da Nang.</s>
<s id="d65p6s6">The bridge had the important role of facilitating the transport of aid coming in from the USA to the French in the city.</s>
</p>
<p id="d65p7">
<s id="d65p7s1">By 1955, all the local streets whose names were in French had been renamed in Vietnamese, except for Pasteur and Yersin streets which were named after two great benefactors of humanity.</s>
<s id="d65p7s2">During this period, the De Lattre Bridge was renamed the Trinh Minh The Bridge after a military official under the Republic of Viet Nam during the 1954 - 1975 period.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d66">
<p id="d66p1">
<s id="d66p1s1">Con Market - largest wholesale and retail venue in central region</s>
</p>
<p id="d66p2">
<s id="d66p2s1">The Con Market at 318 Ong Ich Khiem Street in Da Nang’s Hai Chau District is now the largest wholesale and retail venue in the central region, with over 2,000 traders operating there.</s>
<s id="d66p2s2">Its reputation entitles the market to first position in the category of local markets on the website of the Da Nang Markets and Fairs Exhibition Management Company at hctl-danang.com.vn.</s>
</p>
<p id="d66p3">
<s id="d66p3s1">The market was first established in the 1940s on a hillock at the centre of the city.</s>
<s id="d66p3s2">At that time, it was a perfect trading venue for the many traders from the city and the rural districts of Dai Loc, Que Son and Thang Binh in Quang Nam Province.</s>
<s id="d66p3s3">The traders sold their locally-grown agricultural products, mainly fresh vegetables and poultry.</s>
</p>
<p id="d66p4">
<s id="d66p4s1">A rebuild of the market started in December 1984.</s>
<s id="d66p4s2">It took over 3 months to complete the construction, and it was officially inaugurated on 29 March 1985 to mark the 10th anniversary of the city’s liberation.</s>
<s id="d66p4s3">The new market incorporated a 3,480 m2 3-storey building, two 1,562 m2 2-storey buildings, and a block of single-storey houses with a total area of 8,828 m2, along with a number of other auxiliary facilities.</s>
<s id="d66p4s4">There were 1,473 traders in the market, and many local cooperatives, private businesses and limited companies became involved in trading activities there.</s>
<s id="d66p4s5">Various types of goods were sold at the venue to satisfy the increasing shopping demands of the local residents, and tens of thousands of customers were welcomed every day.</s>
<s id="d66p4s6">The market was at one time renamed Da Nang Commercial Centre.</s>
</p>
<p id="d66p5">
<s id="d66p5s1">The current Con Market is now not only a shopping venue in the inner city, but a must-see destination for tourists visiting the beautiful seaside city.</s>
<s id="d66p5s2">The market sells whatever you want to buy.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d67">
<p id="d67p1">
<s id="d67p1s1">Da Den - a hidden gem for outdoor activities</s>
</p>
<p id="d67p2">
<s id="d67p2s1">Da Den (Black Rock) is a beautiful spot on the northern side of Da Nang’s Son Tra Peninsula, and it can be reached by tourist boat from the Han River.</s>
<s id="d67p2s2">It is an ideal place for outdoor activities with relatives and friends.</s>
</p>
<p id="d67p3">
<s id="d67p3s1">As its name suggests, Da Den features many large black rocks heaped together, which creates beautiful viewing angles.</s>
<s id="d67p3s2">In the nearby waters there is a wide variety of marine creatures such as red snapper, goby, grouper, littorina littorea, scallop, and “vu nang” (her breast) snail which was thought to be only found on the Cu Lao Cham Island off Hoi An.</s>
</p>
<p id="d67p4">
<s id="d67p4s1">Visitors to Da Den can take the opportunity to go fishing with local fishermen or dive to explore the coral reefs.</s>
<s id="d67p4s2">Apart from a fine beach for sunbathing and swimming, it is also a perfect place for building a campfire or for organising interesting teambuilding activities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d67p5">
<s id="d67p5s1">In order to provide easier access for visitors, a pier for the tourist boats is planned to be built here soon.</s>
<s id="d67p5s2">In addition, local travel agents are planning to launch more tours to attract more visitors, both domestic and foreign.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d68">
<p id="d68p1">
<s id="d68p1s1">Wax Museum gaining in popularity</s>
</p>
<p id="d68p2">
<s id="d68p2s1">Located at Da Nang’s Ba Na Hills Resort, the first-ever Wax Museum in Viet Nam has become very popular with local residents, and domestic and foreign visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d68p3">
<s id="d68p3s1">The museum, created in an ancient French architectural style, has 10 different display areas which feature about 50 wax replicas of world-renowned politicians, athletes and movie stars.</s>
<s id="d68p3s2">They include the US President Barack Obama, the Russian President Vladimir Putin, the former South African President Nelson Mandela, the late martial artist Bruce Lee, the Chinese martial artist Jet Li, soccer stars David Beckham and Lionel Messi, movie stars Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie, and the late singer Michael Jackson.</s>
<s id="d68p3s3">The real-size replicas are made of a mixture of beeswax and plastic.</s>
</p>
<p id="d68p4">
<s id="d68p4s1">Visitors to the museum will have an opportunity to take photos of the wax figures of their idols, and learn about how waxworks are made, at a factory in the museum.</s>
<s id="d68p4s2">In addition, there is an area for visitors to make their own waxworks.</s>
</p>
<p id="d68p5">
<s id="d68p5s1">After 10 months of operation, the museum now welcomes an estimated 1,000 people per day.</s>
<s id="d68p5s2">The admission fee is 50,000 VND per person.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d69">
<p id="d69p1">
<s id="d69p1s1">But Beach – wonderfully relaxing</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p2">
<s id="d69p2s1">But (Buddha) Beach is a beautiful spot on the Son Tra Peninsula, and a must-see place for lovers of ecology.</s>
<s id="d69p2s2">According to legend, in the time of Emperor Minh Mang, local fishermen discovered a statue of the Goddess of Mercy on the beach, and a temple dedicated to the goddess was built on the site.</s>
<s id="d69p2s3">Since then, local residents have enjoyed peaceful and prosperous lives, and the area is known as But (Buddha) Beach.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p3">
<s id="d69p3s1">Just about 20 minutes from the city centre, But Beach has become a popular destination for both domestic and foreign visitors over recent years because its natural environment is a perfect example of the harmony between mountains and sea.</s>
<s id="d69p3s2">Besides being a fine beach for sunbathing and swimming, it is a perfect place for diving to discover the amazing and colourful underwater world of corals and other marine creatures.</s>
<s id="d69p3s3">In addition, the beach is home to numerous rare plants and animals which are listed in the national Red Book.</s>
<s id="d69p3s4">Visitors to the beach will also have the opportunity to enjoy a wide range of delicious food and drinks, focusing on local specialities which are served at reasonable prices.</s>
<s id="d69p3s5">Additionally, there are several water sports and fun beach activities here, such as sailing, surfing and jet-skiing.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p4">
<s id="d69p4s1">In an effort to make But Beach an ideal holiday destination in Da Nang, the construction of the But Beach Bay Complex Resort, one of the city’s large-scale tourism projects, began on 30 April 2004.</s>
<s id="d69p4s2">The 19 million USD project will cover 199,786m2 of land and 100,500m2 of water, and will become one of the leading luxury resorts in the central region.</s>
<s id="d69p4s3">The property will feature luxury villas, conference and service centres, a 5-star hotel, and other facilities.</s>
<s id="d69p4s4">Its design is a perfect combination of modern-style architecture and the cultural characteristics of the coastal central region.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p5">
<s id="d69p5s1">The 1st stage of the project will comprise about 140 luxury garden villas and over 100 bungalows.</s>
<s id="d69p5s2">The classic-style villas and bungalows are nestled in the hillsides, surrounded by trees of varying shades of green.</s>
<s id="d69p5s3">Although the project is under construction, many foreigners are showing a keen interest in buying these wonderful villas.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p6">
<s id="d69p6s1">A 5-star 17-storey hotel will be built on an area of 34,432m2 in the project’s 2nd phase.</s>
<s id="d69p6s2">It will offer wonderful stays with a nice panoramic overview of Da Nang and beautiful sunny beaches for its guests.</s>
<s id="d69p6s3">In addition, the hotel will provide unforgettable experiences and opportunities to enjoy great sunrise and sunset moments.</s>
<s id="d69p6s4">Most notably, the Family Hotel, the first of its kind in the But Beach Complex, will be situated at the centre of the project.</s>
<s id="d69p6s5">This hotel will be a good choice for guests wanting value for money with unlimited numbers of people allowed to stay in one room and use all the hotel’s services.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p7">
<s id="d69p7s1">For the 3rd stage of the project, a square will be built on the But Beach and it will become an attractive shopping area and an excellent avenue to host traditional cultural festivals, and international fairs and exhibitions.</s>
<s id="d69p7s2">In addition, there will be an exhibition area to display the city’s artworks, and to introduce its history and development to visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p8">
<s id="d69p8s1">The most impressive feature of the resort will be a special area for water, sound and light shows.</s>
<s id="d69p8s2">Guests will be treated to exciting and thrilling performances.</s>
</p>
<p id="d69p9">
<s id="d69p9s1">It is expected that the But Beach Bay Complex Resort in particular, and the But Beach Tourist Area in general, will emerge as Da Nang’s most attractive and romantic destination for travellers from home and abroad.</s>
<s id="d69p9s2">The beach will be the best place to get close to the natural world, and a truly peaceful place to relax.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d70">
<p id="d70p1">
<s id="d70p1s1">Tho Quang fishing village</s>
</p>
<p id="d70p2">
<s id="d70p2s1">Just about 8km northeast of Da Nang’s centre, the Tho Quang fishing village in Son Tra District is proud of the solidarity among its local residents.</s>
<s id="d70p2s2">In addition, villagers are honest and live in harmony with nature.</s>
<s id="d70p2s3">They all feel very happy when they bring home bumper catches.</s>
</p>
<p id="d70p3">
<s id="d70p3s1">All of the village’s men go offshore fishing and their wives help their husbands to take their seafood catches to markets for sale.</s>
<s id="d70p3s2">The villagers depend directly on fishing activities for their livelihood.</s>
</p>
<p id="d70p4">
<s id="d70p4s1">Like other craft villages in Viet Nam, the skilled local villagers make their own fishing tackle to help them to catch more fish.</s>
<s id="d70p4s2">In spite of all the difficulties and challenges in their lives, the villagers show solidarity and support for each other.</s>
<s id="d70p4s3">The local fishermen help each other while fishing at sea in situations of bad weather or other dangers.</s>
<s id="d70p4s4">Although they have a habit of talking loudly, they are hard-working, gentle, honest, friendly, kind and helpful people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d70p5">
<s id="d70p5s1">Fishing is a dangerous job and fishermen often work under extreme conditions at sea.</s>
<s id="d70p5s2">Therefore, various events are held every year in the village to show the local fishermen’s strong desire for safe offshore fishing trips, with bumper catches.</s>
<s id="d70p5s3">These include the whale worship cult, and the annual “Cau Ngu” festival.</s>
<s id="d70p5s4">The events feature a number of solemn traditional rituals to pray for happiness and prosperity throughout the year, as well as for a safe and profitable fishing season.</s>
</p>
<p id="d70p6">
<s id="d70p6s1">Apart from being involved in fishing activities, the Tho Quang fishing village is also well-known for its fish sauce-making.</s>
<s id="d70p6s2">It is very famous for many types of mam (salted fish) such as mam nem (a type of fish sauce, made from small fish or small shrimps) and mam ruoc (fermented shrimp paste).</s>
<s id="d70p6s3">In particular, the village’s mam ruoc is very popular with the city’s people.</s>
<s id="d70p6s4">The mam products are an indispensable dipping sauce with the daily meals of residents in the central region.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d71">
<p id="d71p1">
<s id="d71p1s1">Cam Le kho me cake village</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p2">
<s id="d71p2s1">Cam Le village is situated in Cam Le District’s Khue Trung Ward, and is well-known for its kho me (sesame) cake making.</s>
<s id="d71p2s2">Visitors to this village will fall in love with the scenic beauty and peaceful atmosphere of the landscape here.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p3">
<s id="d71p3s1">Kho me cake is a speciality of Quang Nam Province and Da Nang, and Cam Le village has the best reputation in Viet Nam.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p4">
<s id="d71p4s1">The village is home to 6 cake production establishments which create job opportunities for over 50 local people.</s>
<s id="d71p4s2">Amongst local cake producers, the brand name ‘Mrs Lieu’ is very famous in both domestic and foreign markets.</s>
<s id="d71p4s3">This brand name is owned by Huynh Thi Dieu whose production facility is located on the northern side of the Cam Le Bridge.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p5">
<s id="d71p5s1">Kho me cakes are made from glutinous flour, rice flour, granulated sugar, ginger, and sesame seeds.</s>
<s id="d71p5s2">The rice flour is mixed with the glutinous flour, then poured into a mould to be steamed and then dried.</s>
<s id="d71p5s3">Next, the cakes are coated in sugar or sesame.</s>
<s id="d71p5s4">The ones that are coated in sugar are called “kho no”, whilst those coated in sesame are called “kho me”.</s>
<s id="d71p5s5">The delicious cakes are soft with well-dried sesame, and when they are broken the sugar must be like thin yellow silk cords.</s>
<s id="d71p5s6">Local families usually put these cakes on their altars on the death anniversaries of their relatives or at Tet.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p6">
<s id="d71p6s1">Cam Le banh kho me has made it into the list of the top 10 most well-known Vietnamese gift specialities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p7">
<s id="d71p7s1">Visitors to this village can buy these cakes and give them as gifts to their relatives and friends.</s>
<s id="d71p7s2">This is one of the local specialties which many visitors are interested in.</s>
</p>
<p id="d71p8">
<s id="d71p8s1">Today, kho me cakes are sold across the whole country, as well as abroad.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d72">
<p id="d72p1">
<s id="d72p1s1">Tuy Loan rice paper village</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p2">
<s id="d72p2s1">About 15km southwest of Da Nang, the Tuy Loan ancient village is located in Hoa Vang District’s Hoa Phong Commune.</s>
<s id="d72p2s2">It boasts beautiful scenery and the unique characteristics of a typical Vietnamese rural village.</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p3">
<s id="d72p3s1">Despite its many ups and downs over the past 5 centuries, local residents are proud of the village's many old houses, its history, its beautiful setting and its many interesting features which include an old banyan tree, a boat station, and a communal house.</s>
<s id="d72p3s2">Villagers also take pride in their My Quang (Quang rice noodles) speciality and their rice paper making.</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p4">
<s id="d72p4s1">Soft rice paper is one of the most popular foods at Tet.</s>
<s id="d72p4s2">Although there are many different types of rice paper, Tuy Loan’s is the most famous because of its unique method of production and its amazing flavours of garlic and ginger.</s>
<s id="d72p4s3">It has become very popular with local residents and both domestic and overseas visitors.</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p5">
<s id="d72p5s1">In order to make the tasty rice paper, deliciously scented rice from the winter-spring crop is used.</s>
<s id="d72p5s2">Tuy Loan’s rice paper tastes very different from similar products produced elsewhere thanks to its special recipe which includes various spice mixes such as dipping sauce, salt, sugar, garlic and sesame.</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p6">
<s id="d72p6s1">Also unlike elsewhere in the country, Tuy Loan’s villagers dry their products on charcoal fires instead of drying them in the sun, which prevents any mould formation.</s>
</p>
<p id="d72p7">
<s id="d72p7s1">If you visit this village, you will have an unforgettable experience enjoying delicious My Quang accompanied by Tuy Loan’s rice paper.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d73">
<p id="d73p1">
<s id="d73p1s1">Nam O fish sauce village</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p2">
<s id="d73p2s1">Nestled on Hoa Hiep Ward, Lien Chieu District, the Nam O village is well-known for its fish sauce-making.</s>
<s id="d73p2s2">Its product wins the trust of customers both at home and abroad.</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p3">
<s id="d73p3s1">Established in the early 20th century, Nam O is a small fishing village which is regarded as one of the best producers of this delicious dipping sauce.</s>
<s id="d73p3s2">The Nam O village used to support itself by producing firecrackers until the government imposed a ban on them in 1995.</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p4">
<s id="d73p4s1">The Nam O brand of fish sauce tastes very different from similar products from elsewhere in the country thanks to its special recipe.</s>
<s id="d73p4s2">An Association of the Nam O Fish Sauce Village has been established and is recognised by the National Office of Intellectual Property of Viet Nam.</s>
<s id="d73p4s3">In addition, the Association has been granted a collective label for its fish sauce product.</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p5">
<s id="d73p5s1">Nam O fish sauce is made from long-jawed anchovies with a high protein content which are caught in the 3rd lunar month.</s>
<s id="d73p5s2">Its delicious taste is partly attributed to the fish mixed with salt which is sourced from Ca Na Beach in Ninh Thuan Province.</s>
<s id="d73p5s3">The grains of this salt are white, well-dried, and larger than the salt from other localities.</s>
<s id="d73p5s4">It is dried on a cement floor for between five and seven days, and it is then stored in pottery vats for a few of years before being used to salt the fish.</s>
<s id="d73p5s5">The process of salting the fish starts from the 3rd lunar month and the sauce-making will be finished in the days leading up to the next Tet Festival.</s>
<s id="d73p5s6">Nam O fish sauce is dark red and has a very nice aroma.</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p6">
<s id="d73p6s1">The fish must be freshly caught and of medium size.</s>
<s id="d73p6s2">They are cleaned in sea water before being preserved, not fresh water because this takes away their taste and smell and the fish can go off easily during the long preservation period.</s>
<s id="d73p6s3">The vats must be made from special woods, including jackfruit wood.</s>
<s id="d73p6s4">The fish is mixed with salt and layered in the jars.</s>
<s id="d73p6s5">Over the top layer is placed a grid of bamboo or dried areca bark.</s>
<s id="d73p6s6">The vat is carefully sealed and kept in a dark, dry, clean and cool place away from the wind.</s>
<s id="d73p6s7">After six or seven months, the fish is stirred.</s>
<s id="d73p6s8">When a white yeast substance forms on the top, the grid is taken off.</s>
<s id="d73p6s9">At the beginning of the lunar new year, the preserved mixture is filtered through a piece of silk to create the dark red fish sauce.</s>
</p>
<p id="d73p7">
<s id="d73p7s1">Despite its many ups and downs over the past 2 centuries, fish sauce-making in this village still flourishes today due to its special secret recipe.</s>
<s id="d73p7s2">At Tet or on other special occasions, many people in the city and from localities beyond seek to buy bottles of Nam O fish sauce because of its special flavour.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d74">
<p id="d74p1">
<s id="d74p1s1">Cam Ne sedge mat-making village</s>
</p>
<p id="d74p2">
<s id="d74p2s1">Located in Hoa Tien Commune, Hoa Vang District, just about 14km south-west of Da Nang's centre, the Cam Ne Village is widely known for its long-standing sedge mat-making craft.</s>
<s id="d74p2s2">These beautifully-coloured mats are used for sleeping on.</s>
</p>
<p id="d74p3">
<s id="d74p3s1">Senior villagers said that the craft originated in Thanh Hoa Province’s Hoang Hoa District and it was introduced to Da Nang in the 15th century by immigrants from this Thanh Hoa.</s>
<s id="d74p3s2">After that, Cam Ne’s craft developed strongly and became well-known under the Nguyen Dynasty.</s>
<s id="d74p3s3">The mats were used by the Nguyen royal family and many artisans from the village were honoured by the Nguyen emperors.</s>
<s id="d74p3s4">Despite its many ups and downs over the past 6 centuries, sedge mat-making in this village is still flourishing today.</s>
</p>
<p id="d74p4">
<s id="d74p4s1">Mat makers require skilful hands and an artist's eye to create these beautiful and quality products.</s>
<s id="d74p4s2">Sedges are cleaned, dyed in various colours, and then dried under the sun.</s>
<s id="d74p4s3">Then they are soaked in water to become soft before they are used to make the mats.</s>
<s id="d74p4s4">Once produced, the mats are cleaned and made smooth before sale.</s>
</p>
<p id="d74p5">
<s id="d74p5s1">Cam Ne sedge mats are more durable and thicker than similar products from other localities, and users will feel cool in the summer and warm in the winter.</s>
<s id="d74p5s2">A pair of mats 1.6m wide x 2m long sells for 500,000VND.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d75">
<p id="d75p1">
<s id="d75p1s1">Nam O Beach – a wonderful gift of nature</s>
</p>
<p id="d75p2">
<s id="d75p2s1">Nestled in Hoa Hiep Nam Ward, Lien Chieu District, just about 17km north-west of Da Nang’s centre, Nam O Beach boasts stunning scenery and it is truly nature’s wonderful gift.</s>
</p>
<p id="d75p3">
<s id="d75p3s1">This beach is best viewed at low tide when a large area of rock and sandy shoreline is exposed.</s>
<s id="d75p3s2">It shelters a large population of rare fish and other marine species, and has a moderate slope with clear blue water and white sand stretching along the foot of a mountain.</s>
<s id="d75p3s3">From here, visitors can reach the Son Tra peninsula by road along the mountain or by boat to the west coast, or visit a village of the Co Tu ethnic group in Hoa Vang District’s Hoa Bac Commune.</s>
</p>
<p id="d75p4">
<s id="d75p4s1">According to locals, the name “Nam O” means the south of O District (a very old location).</s>
<s id="d75p4s2">The Nam O village used to support itself by producing firecrackers until the government imposed a ban on them in 1995.</s>
<s id="d75p4s3">Nowadays, the villagers make nuoc mam (fish sauce) and goi ca.</s>
<s id="d75p4s4">The latter is a kind of Vietnamese sushi: fresh, raw fish fillets marinated in a special sauce and coated in a spicy powder.</s>
<s id="d75p4s5">It is served with fresh vegetables in rice-paper rolls.</s>
<s id="d75p4s6">You will find it for sale on the beach in the summer, or look out for it in the village.</s>
</p>
<p id="d75p5">
<s id="d75p5s1">Developed in the early 1960s, Nam O Beach is frequented by local residents.</s>
<s id="d75p5s2">Some stilt houses have now been built for tourism purposes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d75p6">
<s id="d75p6s1">Nam O Beach has increased in popularity since the Xuan Thieu (Red) Beach Resort was built.</s>
<s id="d75p6s2">The beach has also been incorporated into a project to embellish landscapes and solve the problems of pollution.</s>
<s id="d75p6s3">An 800-metre road linking the Nam O Bridge with the beach resorts will be constructed in the near future.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d76">
<p id="d76p1">
<s id="d76p1s1">Qua Giang Communal House</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p2">
<s id="d76p2s1">The Qua Giang Communal House is situated in Qua Giang Village, Hoa Phuoc Commune, Hoa Vang District, Da Nang.</s>
<s id="d76p2s2">It was built in 1821 and it is an interesting place for those who want to learn more about the history and culture of a Vietnamese ancient village.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p3">
<s id="d76p3s1">The site is home to the holy temple of Quan Thanh De Quan, the saint who has been praised for his resplendent symbol of morality, loyalty, faith, frankness and righteousness.</s>
<s id="d76p3s2">In addition, it is dedicated to the founding members of Qua Giang Village’s 4 clans, named Dinh, Le, Tran and Nguyen.</s>
<s id="d76p3s3">In the reign of Lord Nguyen, these clans from the northern region together founded Qua Giang Village which originally consisted of Qua Giang, Giang Nam, Tra Kiem, An Luu and Con Mong areas.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p4">
<s id="d76p4s1">The house is a great example of the architectural style of the Nguyen dynasty, with its pantile roofs and brick walls.</s>
<s id="d76p4s2">It features 2 parts - the front house and the main temple terrace, and 2 covered corridors connect these parts to form a rectangular-shaped structure.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p5">
<s id="d76p5s1">The front house has 8 main wood pillars, each measuring 5m in height.</s>
<s id="d76p5s2">The rafters are patterned after "Chong ruong - Gia thu" and are carved with stylised floral and animal designs.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p6">
<s id="d76p6s1">The main temple terrace has three sections with four roofs.</s>
<s id="d76p6s2">The pillars against the walls are carved with dragon’s heads, the word “longevity” written in Chinese script, and floral designs.</s>
<s id="d76p6s3">The doors were made by skilful carpenters from Kim Bong Village in Hoi An.</s>
<s id="d76p6s4">The temple’s roof is decorated with two dragons turning their heads and looking at each other, a well-matched pair of phoenixes, unicorns and tortoises.</s>
<s id="d76p6s5">According to Vietnamese beliefs, these are the 4 sacred animals which symbolise power, intellect, longevity and nobility.</s>
<s id="d76p6s6">They are all encrusted with shards of pottery.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p7">
<s id="d76p7s1">The communal house was recognised as a historical and cultural relic on 1 February 2000 by the Ministry of Culture and Information.</s>
</p>
<p id="d76p8">
<s id="d76p8s1">To commemorate the village’s founders, ceremonies are held annually at the communal house on the 20th day of the 2nd lunar month, and the 12th day of the 7th lunar month.</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>
