<text>
<body id="b1">
<head>PHU THO TOURIST - POTENTIAL AND INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITIES</head>
<div id="d1">
<head>GENERAL INTRODUCTION TO TOURISM OF PHU THO PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Phu Tho is a midland province in the Northern of Vietnam with nature land area at 3,532km2, of which 97,610 ha are agricultural land, 200,000 ha of forest land including 64,064 ha of natural forest, 10,000 ha of water surface for aquaculture and other land.</s>
<s id="d1p1s2">The province plays as a northwest gate of Hanoi capital, is 50 kilometers distance from He kou international border gate (between Lao Cai - Vietnam and Yunnan - China).</s>
<s id="d1p1s3">This province is the center of the region and is the meeting point of three large rivers (Da river, Red river and Lo river), so it makes Phu Tho favorable traffic system on land, railway and by water.</s>
<s id="d1p1s4">This foundation makes strong potential for economic development and exchange with the other economic regions of both domestic and other nations.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p2">
<s id="d1p2s1">Phu Tho is well known as the cradle of civilization of Lac Viet culture - the center land of Viet ancient people - era Hung Kings - Van Lang country.</s>
<s id="d1p2s2">Passing thousand years of history, this land still preserves a relic system remarks the foundation of the country.</s>
<s id="d1p2s3">There are more than 1,372 historical monuments of culture (of which, Hung temple is a special national monument), and 223 folk festivals, and specific arts (specially, "Xoan Singing of Phu Tho province" - the intangible cultural heritage in need of urgent safeguarding and Hung Kings Worship and Belief in Phu Tho - the intangible cultural heritage representative of humanity have been recognized by UNESCO in 2011 and 2012).</s>
<s id="d1p2s4">Phu Tho is also famous for well-known tourist attractions including Xuan Son National Park (with system of interesting caverns and caves, diversified plants and animals), Thanh Thuy hot mineral water site with huge capacity for health care, Ao Chau and Van Hoi lagoon, Ao Gioi - Suoi Tien (God Pond - Fairy spring), ect.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p3">
<s id="d1p3s1">In order to exploit all potentials and strengthens on tourism, Phu Tho made a planning of tourism development in term from 2011 - 2015 and orientation to 2030 and encourages  both domestic and international investors on developing tourism of culture and original spirit, ecological - beauty of nature tourism, tourism of resorts and health care, ect.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p4">
<s id="d1p4s1">Phu Tho province warmly welcomes and will be your companion in the investment process.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<head>Project 1: Investment project to build Southern Hung King temple Tourism and Service area - Hung King temple historical monument</head>
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Project's name: Investing to build Southern Hung King temple Tourism and Service area</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p2">
<s id="d2p2s1">Location: At Hung King temple historical monument - Viet Tri city - Phu Tno province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p3">
<s id="d2p3s1">Description: under the project's planning, the project is executed on total land area at 235.026 ha, including two functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p3s2">Hung King culture tourism village: 80.02 ha including following work items</s>
<s id="d2p3s3">Reception area, technical infrastructure and common works; total land area for building is at 28.69 ha; building area is at 21352m2</s>
<s id="d2p3s4">Area for building of patriotic-war-dead memorial: total land area for building is at 5.91 ha; building area is at 7000m2</s>
<s id="d2p3s5">Area for Hung King culture and exhibition: total land area for building is at 45.42 ha; building area is at 48523m2</s>
<s id="d2p3s6">Forest at the South: 1 55.01 ha, including:</s>
<s id="d2p3s7">Reception area and supplying common service; total land area for building is at 6.54 ha; building area is at 13900m2</s>
<s id="d2p3s8">Forest of odd and strange flowers and plants: total land area for building is at 14.09 ha; building area is at 16.167m2</s>
<s id="d2p3s9">Mountainous and beautiful view area: total land area for building is at 34.55 ha; building area is at 22.142m2.</s>
<s id="d2p3s10">Guest houses with future houses: total land area for building is at 36.12 ha; building area is at 38.136m2.</s>
<s id="d2p3s11">Complex area of service and forest structure with season color changing: total land area for building is at 26.38 ha; building area is at 37.283m2.</s>
<s id="d2p3s12">Area of Project management Unit and common works: total land area for building is at 37.32 ha; building area is at 23.839m2</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<head>Project 2: Investment Project to build Van Lang service and tourism area</head>
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Project's name: Investing to build Van Lang tourism area</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p2">
<s id="d3p2s1">Location: Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p3">
<s id="d3p3s1">Description: under the project's planning, the project is executed on total land area at 116.2 ha, including 13 Functional areas:</s>
<s id="d3p3s2">Lac Long Quan - Au Co area: 6.64 ha; including works: Gate, water shops, souvenir shops, water palace, Mrs.Au Co statue, statues of 54 ethnics of Vietnam, house for rest, WC, and parking.</s>
<s id="d3p3s3">Son Tlnh - Thuy Tinh area: 2.55ha, including works and items: gate, upper floor for choosing son-in-law, house for taking photograph, bonsai pool, house for rest, statues of gifts (elephant with 9 ivories, chicken with 9 spurs), ventilation booth houses, restaurant of fish, car parking, tower of fishing.</s>
<s id="d3p3s4">Area for legend of Hung King era: 5.25 ha, including items and works: Area of piper bithe and areca-nut history, magic rice history, Chung - Day cake history, WC, car  parking.</s>
<s id="d3p3s5">Area of Tien Dung - Chu Dong Tu island: 0.62 ha, including works and building: Tien Dung - Chu Dong Tu palace.</s>
<s id="d3p3s6">Island of Mai An Hem: 0.21 ha</s>
<s id="d3p3s7">Area of culture and art performance: 2.03ha including works and items: communal house of Hung King, other auxiliaries works as Xoan singing performance area, service house, statue of Miss.Que Hoa, flower house, tower of rest, car parking.</s>
<s id="d3p3s8">Area for teenagers: 1.99ha, including works and items: Square for entertainment, Giong hero statue, area for camping, clubs of teenagers.</s>
<s id="d3p3s9">Green tree and landscape: 15.19 ha</s>
<s id="d3p3s10">Public service area: 2.33ha; including works of management house, Van Lang bookstore, Souvenir shops, flower shop, house for taking photograph, house for fine arts  exhibition.</s>
<s id="d3p3s11">Area of food: 1 .36ha including: Drinking and ice cream shop, boathouse, small hotel (two floors), and small restaurants.</s>
<s id="d3p3s12">Controlling area: 0.26ha</s>
<s id="d3p3s13">Water surface: 64.30ha including bonsai pool with fish, row.</s>
<s id="d3p3s14">Car parking: 1 ,77ha including management house, hall, kiots , house for guardians.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d4">
<head>Project 3:Investment project to build Thanh Thuy mineral hot water tourism area</head>
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">Project's name: Investing to build Thanh Thuy mineral hot water tourism area</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p2">
<s id="d4p2s1">Location: Thanh Thuy district - Phu Tho province</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p3">
<s id="d4p3s1">Description: under the project's planning, the project Is executed on total land area at 4772.54 ha, including 9 functional areas:</s>
<s id="d4p3s2">Center of culture, sport, entertainment, and trade: 327.70 ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha communes).</s>
<s id="d4p3s3">Tourism area as special: 04.01 ha (La Phu, Son Thuy)</s>
<s id="d4p3s4">Villas and resorts: 89ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu)</s>
<s id="d4p3s5">Area of mineral hot wafer washing and product (ram nature: 41.56 ha (Son Thuy commune)</s>
<s id="d4p3s6">Area of ecology tourism and golf: 843.70 ha (La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen)</s>
<s id="d4p3s7">Area of cinema: 410.46 ha (Thach Khoan - La Phu)</s>
<s id="d4p3s8">Resident area and new urban area: 303.29ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha).</s>
<s id="d4p3s9">Area of infrastructure, management, and production of mineral water bottles and common works: 131.94ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha).</s>
<s id="d4p3s10">Buffer areas to maintain sites and protect water resources, rural areas and afforest: 2075.36ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha).</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<head>Project 4:Investment project to build service and tourism area - Xuan Son national part</head>
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">Project's name: Investment to build Toursim area of Xuan Son National park</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p2">
<s id="d5p2s1">Location: Xuan Son National park, Tan Son district, Phu Tho province</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p3">
<s id="d5p3s1">Description: under the project, total land area for building is at 43.791, including 4 functional areas:</s>
<s id="d5p3s2">Tourism area of creature and landscape (core area of Xuan Son national park) with total area at 15890.45ha.</s>
<s id="d5p3s3">Including all area of Xuan Son commune, a part of Tan Phu, Dong Son, Lai Dong, Tan Son, Xuan Dai and Kim Thuong communes.</s>
<s id="d5p3s4">Area of tourism, service, and trade of Thach Kiet -Tan Phu is 7,056.49 ha consists of all area of Tan Phu, Thach Kiet, Xuan Dai communes.</s>
<s id="d5p3s5">Area of urban, culture, and sport of Minh Dal -land area at 4364.75 ha including Minh Dai and Van Luong communes.</s>
<s id="d5p3s6">Farms and feeding semi-wife animal with total 15402.18ha including a land part of Dong Son, Kiet Son, Tan Son, Xuan Dai, Thuong communes.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<head>Project 5:Investment project to build Ao Chau lagoon tourism area</head>
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">Project's name: Investing to build Ao Chau lagoon tourism area</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p2">
<s id="d6p2s1">Locations: Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p3">
<s id="d6p3s1">Decision of planning: No.: 3522/QD-UB dated 15th October 2001 Phu Tho provincial People's Committee on approving the general planning of Ao Chau lagoon  tourism area, Ha Hoa district.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p4">
<s id="d6p4s1">Descriptions: under the projects planning, the project is executed on total land area at 1500 ha (of which 300 ha of water surface), including the followed functional areas:</s>
<s id="d6p4s2">Center of reception and tourism controlling: 15ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s3">The main guest house and hotel (2-3 stars): 7.5ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s4">Area of park with general entertainment: 18ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s5">Area of camping, fishing: 55ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s6">Guest house for common people: 60ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s7">Green park under each theam: 120 ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s8">Park with animal: 95ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s9">Green plant with landscape: 34.5ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s10">Area for resident for a long time: 33ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s11">Area for development reservation: 23ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s12">Traffic (road, bus station): 9ha</s>
<s id="d6p4s13">Route for tourism along lagoon and branches of the lagoon and lead to functional areas.</s>
<s id="d6p4s14">Protection forest and buffer area: 800ha</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d7">
<head>Project 6: Investment project to build works of culture, technical Infrastructure for tourism, service at Au Co Mother temple monument</head>
<p id="d7p1">
<s id="d7p1s1">Au Co Mother temple is one of the national culture monument which last for more 5 centuries.</s>
<s id="d7p1s2">And now this land is the original of Au Co Mother worship of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d7p1s3">Au Co Mother temple has high value on architectural art.</s>
<s id="d7p1s4">Festival of Au Co Mother temple has also much supernatural power in sprit of Vietnamese people.</s>
<s id="d7p1s5">The temple locates near to Ao Chau lagoon, Ao Gioi - Suoi Tien (Heaven pond - Fairly stream), Van Hoi lagoon, and places on the tourism route from Hung King temple - Au Co Mother Temple -Yen Bai province - Lao Cai province.</s>
<s id="d7p1s6">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to build culture constructions and technical infrastructure for service of tourism and explode the tourism service of spirit and culture connected with beautiful landscape.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d8">
<head>Project 7: Investment to build technical Infrastructure for tourism and service at Lang Suong temple monument</head>
<p id="d8p1">
<s id="d8p1s1">The historical monument - Lang Suong temple locates a Lang Suong hamlet, Trung Nghia commune, Thanh Thuy district, Phu Tho province; it is far from Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area at 5km, and far from Ho Chi Minh historical monument (Chong rock - Ba Vi) at 3km and placed at the tourism route Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area - Xuan Son national park.</s>
<s id="d8p1s2">This is nominal monument for worship of mother at North Delta and the worship of Tan Vien hero at Ba Vi mountain.</s>
<s id="d8p1s3">Lang Suong temple is planed as place of festival tourism with total area at 42.97m2, including functional places of culture, food, staying, and service.</s>
<s id="d8p1s4">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to build technical infrastructure for service of tourism and explode Lang Suong temple for the tourism service of spirit and culture.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d9">
<head>Project 8:Investment project to build infrastructure, technical material for tourism, service at Historical and culture monument - Phuc Co revolution base.</head>
<p id="d9p1">
<s id="d9p1s1">Phuc Co revolution base, Minh Hoa commune, Yen Lap district is one of five famous resistance bases of Phu Tho province at time of pre-revolution and this land is recognized as historical and cultural monument of the province.</s>
<s id="d9p1s2">In this land, the landscape is neglected with Long Chao stream with small falls, beautiful landscape.</s>
<s id="d9p1s3">This land is good place for tourism investment with services of ecology, resort, traditional culture of Muong ethnic people.</s>
<s id="d9p1s4">Under the plan, cultural and historical monument - Phuc Co revolution base will connect with community ecology tourism with total area at 330ha with functional areas as magement, area for services of tourism -convalescence - entertainment with tourism tour of crossing fall.</s>
<s id="d9p1s5">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to build culture constructions and technical infrastructure for service of tourism and explode the tourism service of culture, ecology and beautiful landscape, and convalescence.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d10">
<head>Project 9:Investment protect to build May fall tourism area  [Hem fall]</head>
<p id="d10p1">
<s id="d10p1s1">May falls 9ets area at 800ha of Luoi Hai mountain, Huong Can commune, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d10p1s2">This land is far from Viet Tri city at 60km on the southwest, and far from Thanh Thuy Hot mineral water tourism area at 20km on the West, near to highway 316 about 1km.</s>
<s id="d10p1s3">May fall area contains beautiful and wild landscape with primeval forest, projection forest, and fresh environment.</s>
<s id="d10p1s4">May falls contains 13 small and large falls with high fall which pour water into abyss and green and pure water.</s>
<s id="d10p1s5">Along streams, rocks with many odd figure and forms which create wonderful land for tourism.</s>
<s id="d10p1s6">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to change May fall as tourism service of ecology, beautiful landscape, and convalescence.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d11">
<head>Project 10:Investment project to build tourism place - Mo fall [Cu Dong fall]</head>
<p id="d11p1">
<s id="d11p1s1">Mo Fall places at Cu Thang commune, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d11p1s2">This land is far from Thanh Thuy Hot mineral water tourism area at 15km on the West, far from  Xuan Son National Part about 55km and, near to highway 316 about 3km.</s>
<s id="d11p1s3">Mo Fall is system of small falls, continuously.</s>
<s id="d11p1s4">Specially, there is a 60m fall with vertical rock surface and the water pour on cobble with miraculous colors.</s>
<s id="d11p1s5">Along streams, rocks with many odd figure and forms which create wonderful land for tourism.</s>
<s id="d11p1s6">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to change May fall as tourism service  of ecology.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d12">
<head>Project 11:Investment project to build Van Hoi lagoon tourism area</head>
<p id="d12p1">
<s id="d12p1s1">Van Hoi lagoon places at Hien Luong commune, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d12p1s2">This land is far from Viet Tri about 80km, far from Au Co Mother temple (Ha Hoa district)  about 1 km, next to Hai Phong - Ha Noi - Con Minh highway and this project is near to Ngoi Van lagoon about 700m.</s>
<s id="d12p1s3">Van Hoi lagoon places on more 200ha of water surface and 40 islands with largest island, whose land ate is 10 ha of area.</s>
<s id="d12p1s4">The lagoon gets opening systems of water supplying and draining, so the water level of stable, water of the lagoon is pure and fresh.</s>
<s id="d12p1s5">Surrounding of the lagoon is system of mountains, hills, forest and it makes this land is poetic landscape.</s>
<s id="d12p1s6">Phu Tho is mobilizing investment to Van Hoi lagoon as tourism area of convalescence - and luxury entertainment.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d13">
<head>Some other projects</head>
<p id="d13p1">
<s id="d13p1s1">Besides about projects, Phu Tho is encouraging investment on tourism project: hotel with 4-5 stars, project to build Heaven pond - Fairly stream (Ao Gioi - Suoi Tien) - Ha Hoa  province as tourism area of ecology; project to build Archaeological sites of Ca village, Mun hill, Ren hamlet as destination of culture tourism.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d14">
<head>POLICIES AND MECHANISM</head>
<p id="d14p1">
<s id="d14p1s1">Incentives on land use</s>
<s id="d14p1s2">Investors have the right to select the appropriate location and land area to suit their project scale based on approved plan and the right to choose between assigning the  land with land usage fee and leasing the land under the current laws.</s>
<s id="d14p1s3">Investors are exempt from land lease fees from 3 to 15 years and enjoy a reduction of land lease fees from 20 to 50% depending on types of projects and investment locations in accordance with Decree No.: 142/2005/ND-CP dated 14th November 2005; the Decree No.: 121/2010/ND-CP dated 30th December 2010.</s>
<s id="d14p1s4">Investment projects on infrastructure of industrial zones shall receive support at 10% of land rent.</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p2">
<s id="d14p2s1">Tax incentives policies:</s>
<s id="d14p2s2">Incentive beneficiaries: investors in the province are entitled to incentives according to investment sectors and locations as provided by Decree No 108/2006/ND-CP dated 22nd September, 2006 by the Government to issue detailed instructions for the implementation of certain clauses and provisions of the Law on Investment.</s>
<s id="d14p2s3">Incentives on enterprise income tax, import tax are defined in Investment Law, Import Export Tax Law, Decree No 124/2008/ ND-CP dated December 11th, 2008;  Decree No 149/2005/ ND-CP dated December 8th, 2005 and current regulations remaining in force at the time of the project.</s>
<s id="d14p2s4">Investors shall be entitled 10% to 20% of reduction of tax rates for 10 to 30 years according to types of project and investment locations.</s>
<s id="d14p2s5">Investors shall be enjoyed tax holiday from 2 to 4 years and 50% reduction of tax rates in the next 4 to 9 years depending on types of projects and investment location.</s>
<s id="d14p2s6">Investor shall be exempted from import and export tax for create fixed asset of investment project in accordance with approved lists and regulation current in force.</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p3">
<s id="d14p3s1">Other incentives policies:</s>
<s id="d14p3s2">Investors shall be:</s>
<s id="d14p3s3">Received provision of power and water supply to the boundary of the project.</s>
<s id="d14p3s4">Gained support for road construction to the boundary of the industrial zones on scale depending on kind of project and area of investment but shorter than 3km.</s>
<s id="d14p3s5">Exempted from infrastructure fees during construction period (which does not exceed a maximum of 3 years) for the special incentive project; and exempted all with the project on public service in industrial zones.</s>
<s id="d14p3s6">The special important projects for the province shall be considered for special support policies.</s>
<s id="d14p3s7">Provided free of charge with documents relating to the project.</s>
<s id="d14p3s8">Exempted from administrative fees required for project application with project licensed by the province.</s>
<s id="d14p3s9">Exempted for fees for participation in investment and trade promotion conference organized in the province.</s>
<s id="d14p3s10">Exempted from contribution fees for the province when joining the province's team to attend other investment promotion event.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d15">
<head>INVESTMENT PROCEDURES AND PROTOCOLS</head>
<p id="d15p1">
<s id="d15p1s1">Administrative procedure for receiving investment project.</s>
<s id="d15p1s2">Phu Tho provincial People's Committee promulgated "One door" for all projects In Phu Tho with quick, dear, effective procedure.</s>
<s id="d15p1s3">It reduces Inconvenient, cost, and time of Investors.</s>
<s id="d15p1s4">Investor shall prepare documents and submit at one of two main doors:</s>
<s id="d15p1s5">Department of Investment and Planning (for projects outside of Industrial zone)</s>
<s id="d15p1s6">Industrial Zones Management Board (for projects within Industrial zone).</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p2">
<s id="d15p2s1">Investment approval procedures:</s>
<s id="d15p2s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d15p2s3">Application for Investment Approval Award by Investor.</s>
<s id="d15p2s4">Summary of Investment project.</s>
<s id="d15p2s5">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d15p2s6">Department of Investment and Planning ( evaluation and recommendation)</s>
<s id="d15p2s7">Duration: within 07 working days.</s>
<s id="d15p2s8">Phu Tho People's Committee (consideration for approval)</s>
<s id="d15p2s9">Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p3">
<s id="d15p3s1">Investment Certificate Procedure:</s>
<s id="d15p3s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d15p3s3">Location acceptance Permit (approved)</s>
<s id="d15p3s4">Investment Approval Award by the Province's People committee</s>
<s id="d15p3s5">Investment project report and other related documents (if any)</s>
<s id="d15p3s6">Environmental assessment report (or commitment for environmental protection) - approved</s>
<s id="d15p3s7">Request for Investment Certificate Issuance</s>
<s id="d15p3s8">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d15p3s9">Department of Investment and Planning ( evaluation and recommendation)</s>
<s id="d15p3s10">Duration: within 15 working days.</s>
<s id="d15p3s11">Phu Tho People's Committee (consideration for approval)</s>
<s id="d15p3s12">Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p4">
<s id="d15p4s1">Procedure of establishment of enterprises, branches, representative offices</s>
<s id="d15p4s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d15p4s3">Application (or notice on the establishment of branches, representative offices)</s>
<s id="d15p4s4">Identify card</s>
<s id="d15p4s5">Charter of company</s>
<s id="d15p4s6">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d15p4s7">Department of Investment and Planning ( consideration for Issuance)</s>
<s id="d15p4s8">Duration: within 05 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p5">
<s id="d15p5s1">Procedure of applying construction Permit</s>
<s id="d15p5s2">Documents consist:</s>
<s id="d15p5s3">Application for construction permit</s>
<s id="d15p5s4">Copy of document certifying of land use as a required by the Law on land</s>
<s id="d15p5s5">Blue prints of construction plan, cross section, typical vertical cut section, foundation plan, position plan, electricity and water plan with technical connection point for electricity, water and sewage system.</s>
<s id="d15p5s6">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d15p5s7">Department of Investment and Planning (receiving records and transfer to Construction Department)</s>
<s id="d15p5s8">Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
<s id="d15p5s9">Construction Department (consideration For Issuance) Duration: within 15 working days.</s>
</p>
</div>
<head>ADDRESS OF CONTACTING AGENCIES FOR RECEIVING, EVALUATING INVESTMENT PROJECT DOCUMENTS AND SUPPORT INVESTORS</head>
<div id="d16">
<head>Investment and Planning Department</head>
<p id="d16p1">
<s id="d16p1s1">Office</s>
<s id="d16p1s2">Address: Tran Phu road, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d16p1s3">Tex: +84-210 3 846 581</s>
<s id="d16p1s4">Fax: +84-210 3 840 955</s>
<s id="d16p1s5">Email: pitc.phutho@gmail.com</s>
<s id="d16p1s6">Website: www.dpi.phutho.gov.vn</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p2">
<s id="d16p2s1">Phu Tho Investment, Trade and Tourism Promotion Center (Investors supporting and consulting agency)</s>
<s id="d16p2s2">Address: Tran Phu road, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d16p2s3">Tex: +84-210 3 993 689</s>
<s id="d16p2s4">Fax; +84 210 3 993 589</s>
<s id="d16p2s5">Email: ptic.phutho@gmail.com</s>
<s id="d16p2s6">Website: www.dpi.phutho.gov.vn</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d17">
<head>Phu Tho Culture, Sport and Tourism Department (assisting investors)</head>
<p id="d17p1">
<s id="d17p1s1">Division of Tourism Resource* Development </s>
<s id="d17p1s2">Address: Tran Phu road, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d17p1s3">Tex: +84-210 3 686 979</s>
<s id="d17p1s4">Fax: +84-210 3 848 545</s>
<s id="d17p1s5">Email: tainguyendulichphutfio@gmail.com</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p2">
<s id="d17p2s1">PMU of Culture, Sport and Tourism</s>
<s id="d17p2s2">Address: Tran Phu road, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d17p2s3">Tex: +84-210 3 9.40 531.</s>
<s id="d17p2s4">Fax: +84-210 3 952 068</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>

<body id="b2">
<head></head>
<div id="d1">
<head>HUNG KING TEMPLE - A SPECIAL NATIONAL MONUMENT</head>
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Hung King temple is confirmed as a special national monument in 2009.</s>
<s id="d1p1s2">This land is worship Hung Kings - the ancestors of Vietnam people and famous as a historical beautiful site.</s>
<s id="d1p1s3">Hung King temple area is a historical monument where includes: Ha temple, Thien Quang pagoda, Trung temple, Thuong Temple, Hung Vuong mausoleum, Well temple, Au Co Country Mother Temple, Lac Long Quan Country Father temple.</s>
<s id="d1p1s4">Passed years, this place is the center land of culture, spirit, belief of  Vietnam nation.</s>
<s id="d1p1s5">Annually, in the spring, thousands Vietnamese people make pilgrimage to this land to burn incense as grateful to their ancestors:</s>
<s id="d1p1s6">Descendants of three regions visit ancestors tombs</s>
<s id="d1p1s7">The motherland shall be prosperous everlasting.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<head>PHU THO FESTIVALS</head>
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Annual spring, there are about 260 festivals of culture, spirit, and belief hold in this land such as: an ancestor's death anniversary of Hung Kings - Hung King temple festival, Au Co Country Mother temple festival, Van Luong casting-net throwing festival, Lang Suong Mother temple festival, Du Yen temple festival, Festival procession of Queen in Hung Son town, Hien Quan spread Festival, Tro Tram professional performance festival, Phu Ninh buffalo fighting festival, Ngoc Tan communal house festival, Boat contest in Bac Hac river port, Gongs festival and Duong stab festival of Muong ethnic group, and so on.</s>
<s id="d2p1s2">Festivals in Phu Tho are original characters and original culture of this ancestral land.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<head>HISTORICAL AND CULTURAL MONUMENTS</head>
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Historical and cultural monuments is a unique tourism resource of Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d3p1s2">Besides Hung King temple which is classified as special national monument, there are 73 historical monuments listed in the national monuments and 212 historical monuments listed in the provincial monuments, for example Hung Lo communal house, Pho Quang pagoda, Lang Suong temple, Lang Ca archaeological monument, Ren village archaeological monument, and so on where remain valuable architecture value and traditional arts of the nation.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d4">
<head>BEAUTY OF NATURE</head>
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">What's beautiful nation!</s>
<s id="d4p1s2">What are palm tree forest, tee hill, and immense green vast fields!</s>
<s id="d4p1s3">Sun shine on Lo River and hearing a sing of heaven.</s>
<s id="d4p1s4">This land is complex terrain of low hills with fields, small delta through rivers.</s>
<s id="d4p1s5">It creates this land with special and amazing beautiful sites as forest of palm trees, vast green tee hills as face down bowls, and covered with milk and curved rivers.</s>
<s id="d4p1s6">You would see more than a hundred of small and medium islands in Ao Chau lagoon which covered with thick and rich plant and 99 small streams laid down in cross-valleys; you would also take pleasure with view of water and boats as a picture of Hac three-way cross rivers, and you would be calm down the quite air of Xuan Son national park with wind, cloud, and trees.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<head>WORSHIP OF HUNG KINGS IN PHU THO PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">UNESCO just placed the worship of the Hùng Kings on its “List of the Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity".</s>
<s id="d5p1s2">This worship is a long and tradition custom of the nation.</s>
<s id="d5p1s3">It is known as a feature of culture.</s>
<s id="d5p1s4">It shows the pious, grateful, and a philosophy of "Human get their ancestors" of the Nation.</s>
<s id="d5p1s5">For many years with many events, this belief is remained and plays as sacred spirit of Vietnamese people.</s>
<s id="d5p1s6">It locates on each family, in social, and the strong and collected point of national solidarity.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<head>HAT XOAN OR XOAN SINGING OF PHU THO PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">Hat Xoan – an intangible World Cultural Heritage in need of urgent protection.</s>
<s id="d6p1s2">It is known as pride of Vietnam in general and of Phu Tho in narrow.</s>
<s id="d6p1s3">Legend has it that Hat Xoan was created from Hung Kings and now it is preserved at four villages including: An Thai (Phuong Lau commune), Phu Duc, Kim Doi, and Thet (Kim Duc commune).</s>
<s id="d6p1s4">Annually, in the warmly air of spring, in temples of Hung Kings worship, Xoan villages holds Xoan singing competition in a fixed order: Manner singing (Greeting king, Giao trống, Giao pháo, Thơ nhang, and Đóng đám), Quả cách singing (singing 14 quả cách), and dual love song (Bỏ bộ, Hát đúm, Xin huê - word questions, Mó cá, and singing the finish).</s>
<s id="d6p1s5">There are special features of Hát Xoan from its dances, song words, historical value, and human culture value saved.</s>
<s id="d6p1s6">It will fill the gap of time and language for any tourist who comes Phu Tho and enjoy Hat Xoan.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d7">
<head>XUAN SON NATIONAL PARK</head>
<p id="d7p1">
<s id="d7p1s1">Xuan Son Natural Park locates in Tan Son district.</s>
<s id="d7p1s2">This place takes high valuation on its diversified ecological and rich biological with complex tectonics terrain.</s>
<s id="d7p1s3">This land is a special potential resource of tourism with national feature as system of ecological, waterfalls, and community of more than 30 limestone caves and caverns with its specifics: large underground river in huge cave, system of beautiful stalactites as the image of terraced fields.</s>
<s id="d7p1s4">Xuan Son National Park would attracts tourists with traditional festivals, custom, folksongs, and folk dance of Dao, Muong ethnic groups.</s>
<s id="d7p1s5">Xuan Son is known as Ha Long bay in the land.</s>
<s id="d7p1s6">43,791 ha of Xuan Son park is planed as tourism area with four functional sites including ecological and nature viewing site; urban area for tourism, culture, and trade; site of farms for semi wild animal feeding.</s>
<s id="d7p1s7">So, tourists can find this land for culture, ecological, beauty site, discovery, venture sports, and scientific research, and so on</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d8">
<head>THANH THUY MINERAL HEAT WATER TOURISM AREA</head>
<p id="d8p1">
<s id="d8p1s1">This tourism area is located in Thanh Thuy district, on the west bank of Da river, next to Hanoi city.</s>
<s id="d8p1s2">Thanh Thuy mineral heat water area is connected with other regions in both road and water way for better tourism.</s>
<s id="d8p1s3">Mineral heat water gets average temperature from 370C to 540C and exploited from the artesian waters from underground from 30 meters to 60 meters far to surface.</s>
<s id="d8p1s4">Mineral water in this land contains many useful minerals as sodium, potassium, calcium, magnesium.</s>
<s id="d8p1s5">Especially, water in this land contains Radon  - A unique and valuable water in Vietnam and it is very good for bathing, curing, and recuperative.</s>
<s id="d8p1s6">When you come to Thanh Thuy, you can soak in natural mineral heat water pools with roof or open.</s>
<s id="d8p1s7">You can both dip you feet on mineral water and please in natural fresh air.</s>
<s id="d8p1s8">Now, Thanh Thuy mineral heat water tourism area is a complex area with hotels, restaurants, services, so it meets well the demand of tourism, convalescence, health recover, and cure for both domestic and international tourists.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d9">
<head>PHU THO EATING AND DRINKING</head>
<p id="d9p1">
<s id="d9p1s1">Hemibagrus:</s>
<s id="d9p1s2">is a genus of catfishes (order Siluriformes) of the family Bagridae.</s>
<s id="d9p1s3">This genus consists of large-sized catfishes.</s>
<s id="d9p1s4">It includes species with depressed (flattened) heads, rugose (ridged or wrinkled) head shields not covered by skin, and moderately long adipose fins, four antenna.</s>
<s id="d9p1s5">Hemibagrus live in the middle layer water and it is special food of Phu Tho province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p2">
<s id="d9p2s1">Doan Hung pomelo:</s>
<s id="d9p2s2">is a special food of Phu Tho province with trade mark "Doan Hung pomelo - Favour taste of Ancestral Land".</s>
<s id="d9p2s3">The features of this pomelo are small fruit, thin skin, small section, good sweet-taste.</s>
<s id="d9p2s4">When you make pilgrimage to the Ancestral Land, you should preserve this pomelo - it is the unique and essential taste of the midland.</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p2">
<s id="d9p2s1">Multi spurs chicken:</s>
<s id="d9p2s2">This kind of chicken are sourced for many years since the legend of Hung Kings who found son-in-law for Ngoc Hoa princess - "Betrothal gifts shall be elephant with nine tusks, chicken with nine spurs, horse with nine pink furs".</s>
<s id="d9p2s3">Meat of the chicken is tasted very well.</s>
<s id="d9p2s4">It is favour present for holidays, Tet holidays, new house ceremony, adult ceremony in local people.</s>
<s id="d9p2s5">Now, this chicken is a special food for tourists who visit Xuan Son National Park.</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>

<body id="b3">
<head></head>
<div id="d1">
<head>GENERAL INTRODUCTION TO TOURISM OF PHUTHO PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Phu Tho is a midland province in the Northern of Vietnam with nature land area at 3,532km2, of which 97,610ha are agricultural land, 200,000 ha of forest land including 64,064 ha of natural forest, 10,000 ha of water surface for aquaculture and other land.</s>
<s id="d1p1s2">The province plays as a northwest gate of Hanoi capital, is 50 kilometers distance from He kou international border gate (between Lao Cai – Vietnam and Yunnan - China).</s>
<s id="d1p1s3">This province is the center of the region and is the meeting point of three large rivers (Da river, Red river and Lo river), so it makes Phu Tho favorable traffic system on land, railway and by water.</s>
<s id="d1p1s4">This foundation makes strong potential for economic development and exchange with the other economic regions of both domestic and other nations.</s>
<s id="d1p1s5">Phu Tho is well known as the cradle of civilization of Lac Viet culture – the center land of Viet ancient people – era Hung Kings – Van Lang country.</s>
<s id="d1p1s6">Passing thousand years of history, this land still preserves a relic system remarks the foundation of the country.</s>
<s id="d1p1s7">There are more than 1,372 historical monuments of culture (of which, Hung temple is a special national monument), and 223 folk festivals, and specific arts (specially, “Xoan Singing of Phu Tho province” - the intangible cultural heritage in need of urgent safeguarding and Hung Kings Worship and Belief in Phu Tho – the intangible cultural heritage representative of humanity have been recognized by UNESCO in 2011 and 2012).</s>
<s id="d1p1s8">Phu Tho is also famous for well-known tourist attractions including Xuan Son National Park (with system of interesting caverns and caves, diversified plants and animals), Thanh Thuy hot mineral water site with huge capacity for health care, Ao Chau and Van Hoi lagoon, Ao Gioi – Suoi Tien (God Pond – Fairy spring), ect.</s>
<s id="d1p1s9">In order to exploit all potentials and strengthens on tourism,  Phu Tho made a planning of tourism development in term from 2011 – 2015 and orientation to 2030 and encourages both domestic and international investors on developing tourism of culture and original spirit, ecological – beauty of nature tourism, tourism of resorts and health care, ect.</s>
<s id="d1p1s10">Phu Tho province warmly welcomes and will be your companion in the investment process.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<head>TOURISM AREAS</head>
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Investment project to build Southern Hung King Temple Tourism and Service area - Hung King Temple historical monument:</s>
<s id="d2p1s2">Project’s name: Investing to build Southern Hung King Temple Tourism and Service area</s>
<s id="d2p1s3">Location: At Hung King Temple historical monument, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d2p1s4">Description: the project is executed on total land area at 235.026 ha, including two functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p1s5">Hung King culture tourism village: 80.02 ha, including following work items:</s>
<s id="d2p1s6">Reception area, technical infrastructure and common works; total land area for building is at 28.69 ha; building area is at 21,352 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s7">Area for building of patriotic-war-dead memorial: total land area for building is at 5.91 ha, building area is at 7000 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s8">Area of Hung King culture and exhibition: total land area for building is at 45.42 ha, building area is at 48,523 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s9">Forest at South: 155.01 ha, including:</s>
<s id="d2p1s10">Reception area and supplying common service; total land area for building is at 6.54 ha, building area is at 13,900 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s11">Forest of odd and strange flowers and plants: total land area for building is at 14.09 ha, building area is at 16,167 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s12">Mountainous and beautiful view area: total land area for building is at 34.55 ha, building area is at 22,142 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s13">Resort with future house: total land area for building is at 36.12 ha, building area is at 38,136 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s14">Complex area of service and forest structure with season color changing: total land area for building is at 23.38 ha, building area is at 37,283 m2.</s>
<s id="d2p1s15">Area of project management Board and common works: total land area for building is at 37.32 ha, building area is at 23,839 m2.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p2">
<s id="d2p2s1">Investment project to build service and tourism area of Xuan Son National Park:</s>
<s id="d2p2s2">Project’s name: Investing to build Tourism and Service area of Xuan Son National Park</s>
<s id="d2p2s3">Location: Xuan Son National Park, Tan Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d2p2s4">Description: total land area for building is at 43.791 ha, including four functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p2s5">Tourism area of creature and landscape (core area of Xuan Son National Park) with total area at 15,890.43ha, including all area of Xuan Son commune, a part of Tan Phu, Dong Son, Lai Dong, Tan Son, Xuan Dai and Kim Thuong communes.</s>
<s id="d2p2s6">Area of tourism, service and trade of Thach Kiet – Tan Phu is 7,056.49ha consists of all area of Tan Phu, Thach Kiet and Xuan Dai communes.</s>
<s id="d2p2s7">Area of urban, culture, and sport of Minh Dai – Van Luong with land area at 4,364.75ha including Minh Dai and Van Luong communes.</s>
<s id="d2p2s8">Farms and feeding semi-wild animals with total area at 15,402.18ha,including a land part of Dong Son, Lai Dong, Kiet Son, Tan Son, Xuan Dai, and Kim Thuong communes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p3">
<s id="d2p3s1">Investment project to build Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area</s>
<s id="d2p3s2">Project’s name: Investing to build Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area</s>
<s id="d2p3s3">Location: Thanh Thuy district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d2p3s4">Description: total land area for building is at 4,472.54 ha, including 9 functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p3s5">Center of culture, sports, entertainment and trade: 327.70ha (including Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s6">Special tourism area: 64.01 ha (including La Phu, Son Thuy communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s7">Villas and resorts: 89.01 ha (including Thach Khoan, La Phu communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s8">Area of hot mineral water bathing and product from nature: 41.56ha (Son Thuy communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s9">Area of ecological tourism and golf: 843.70ha (including La Phu, Son Thuy and Bao Yen communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s10">Area of cinema: 410.46ha (Thach Khoan, La Phu communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s11">Resident area and new urban area: 363.29ha (including Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s12">Area of infrastructure, management and production of mineral water bottles and common works: 131.94ha (including Thach Khoan, La Phu, Son Thuy, Bao Yen, Doan Ha communes)</s>
<s id="d2p3s13">Buffer areas to maintain sites and protect water resoures, rural area and afforest: 2,075.36ha (including Thach Khoan, La Phu, Bao Yen, Doan Ha communes)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p4">
<s id="d2p4s1">Investment project to build Van Lang service and tourism area:</s>
<s id="d2p4s2">Project’s name: Investing to build Van Lang tourism and service area</s>
<s id="d2p4s3">Location: Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d2p4s4">Description: under the project’s planning, the project is executed on total land area at 116.2 ha, including 13 functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p4s5">Lac Long Quan – Au Co area: 6.64ha, including works: Gate, bar and coffee, souvenir shops, water palace, Mrs.</s>
<s id="d2p4s6">Au Co statue, statues of 54 ethnics of Vietnam people, house for rest, WC and parking.</s>
<s id="d2p4s7">Son Tinh – Thuy Tinh area: including works and items: Gate, upper floor for choosing son – in – law, house for taking photograph, bonsai pool, house for rest, statues of gifts (elephant with 9 ivories, chicken with 9 spurs), ventilation booth house, restaurant of fish, car parking, tower of fishing.</s>
<s id="d2p4s8">Area for legend of Hung King era: 5.25ha, including works and items: area of piper bithe and areca –nut history, magic rice history, Chung  and Giay cake history, WC, car parking.</s>
<s id="d2p4s9">Area of Tien Dung – Chu Dong Tu island: 0.62ha, including works and building: Tien Dung – Chu Dong Tu Palace.</s>
<s id="d2p4s10">Mai An Tiem Island: 0.21ha</s>
<s id="d2p4s11">Area of culture and art performance: 2.03ha, including works and items: communal house of Hung King, other auxiliaries works as Xoan singing performance area, service house, statue of Ms.</s>
<s id="d2p4s12">Que Hoa, flower house, house for rest, car parking.</s>
<s id="d2p4s13">Area for teenagers: 1.99ha, including works and items: square for entertainment, Thanh Giong statue, area for camping, clubs for teenagers.</s>
<s id="d2p4s14">Green tree area: 15.19ha</s>
<s id="d2p4s15">Public service area: 2.33ha, including works of management house, Van Lang bookstore, souvenir shops, flower shop, house for taking photograph, house for fine arts exhibition.</s>
<s id="d2p4s16">Area of food: 1.36ha, including: drinking and ice-cream shop, boats house, small hotel (two floors), and small restaurant.</s>
<s id="d2p4s17">Management area: 0.26ha</s>
<s id="d2p4s18">Water surface: 64.30ha, including bonsai pool, sigh-seeing, boating, ect.</s>
<s id="d2p4s19">Car parking: 1.77ha including management house, hall, kiots, house for guards.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p5">
<s id="d2p5s1">Investment project to build Ao Chau lagoon tourism area:</s>
<s id="d2p5s2">Project’s name: Investing to build Ao Chau lagoon tourism area</s>
<s id="d2p5s3">Location: Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d2p5s4">Descision of planning: No.3522/QD – UB dated 15th October 2001 by Phu Tho People’s Committee on approving the general planning of Ao Chau lagoon tourism area, Ha Hoa district.</s>
<s id="d2p5s5">Description: the project is executed on total land area at 1500 ha (of which 300ha of water surface), including the followed functional areas:</s>
<s id="d2p5s6">Center of reception and tourism controlling: 15ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s7">The main guest house and hotel (1-2 stars): 7.5ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s8">Area of park with general entertainment: 18ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s9">Area of camping and fishing: 55ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s10">Guest house for common people: 60ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s11">Green park with special plants: 120ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s12">Animal park: 95ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s13">Green park for landscape: 34.5ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s14">Area for local resident: 33ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s15">Area for development reservation: 23ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s16">Traffic (road, bus-stop): 9ha</s>
<s id="d2p5s17">Route for visit along lagoon and to functional areas</s>
<s id="d2p5s18">Protection forests and buffer area: 800ha</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<head>TOURISM DESTINATIONS</head>
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Investment project to build works of culture, technical infrastructure for tourism and service at Au Co Mother Temple:</s>
<s id="d3p1s2">Au Co Mother Temple is one of the national cultural monuments which last for more 5 centuries.</s>
<s id="d3p1s3">And now this temple is the original of Au Co Mother worship of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d3p1s4">The Au Co Mother Temple has high value on architectural art.</s>
<s id="d3p1s5">Festival of Au Co Mother Temple has also much supernatural power in sprit of Vietnamese people.</s>
<s id="d3p1s6">The temple locates near Ao Chau lagoon, Ao Gioi – Suoi Tien (Heaven Pond – Fairy stream), Van Hoi lagoon, and places on the route from Hung King Temple - Au Co Mother Temple – Yen Bai province – Lao Cai province.</s>
<s id="d3p1s7">Phu Tho is calling investors to build culture constructions and technical infrastructure for service of tourism and exploit the tourism service of spirit and culture connected with beautiful landscape.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p2">
<s id="d3p2s1">Investment project to build technical infrastructure for tourism and service at the Lang Suong Temple:</s>
<s id="d3p2s2">The historical monument – Lang Suong Temple locates at Lang Suong hamlet, Trung Nghia commune, Thanh Thuy district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d3p2s3">It is far from Thanh Thuy hot mineral water  tourism area at 5 km, and far from Ho Chi Minh historical monument (Da Chong – Ba Vi - Hanoi) at 3km and placed on tourism route of Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area – Xuan Son national park.</s>
<s id="d3p2s4">This is nominal monument for worship of mother at North Delta and the worship of Tan Vien hero at Ba Vi mountain.</s>
<s id="d3p2s5">Lang Suong Temple is planed as place of festival tourism with total area at 42,970m2, including functional places of culture, cuisine, staying facility and service.</s>
<s id="d3p2s6">Phu Tho is calling investors to build culture constructions and technical infrastructure for service of tourism to exploit the tourism service of spirit and culture.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p3">
<s id="d3p3s1">Investment project to build technical infrastructure for tourism and service at the historical and culture monument Phuc Co revolution base:</s>
<s id="d3p3s2">The Phuc Co revolution base at Minh Hoa commune, Yen Lap district is one of five famous resistance bases of Phu Tho province at time of pre-revolution.</s>
<s id="d3p3s3">It is recognized as historical and cultural monument of the province.</s>
<s id="d3p3s4">This area has unspoiled landscape with Long Chao stream and many small waterfalls that is favorable for tourism investment on services of ecology, resort, traditional culture of Muong ethnic people.</s>
<s id="d3p3s5">Under the plan,  culture and historical monument – Phuc Co revolution base will connect with community ecology tourism with total area at 330ha with functional areas as management area, area of tourism services – convalesces – entertainment with tour of crossing waterfall.</s>
<s id="d3p3s6">Phu Tho is calling investors to build culture constructions and technical infrastructure for service of tourism to exploit the tourism service of spirit and culture, ecology and beautiful landscape….</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p4">
<s id="d3p4s1">Investment project to build Hem waterfall tourism area (Cloudy Waterfall)</s>
<s id="d3p4s2">The Cloudy waterfall gets total area at 800 ha of Luoi Hai mountain, Huong Can communes, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d3p4s3">It is far from Viet Tri city at 60km on the southwest, and far from Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area at 20km on the west, near to highway 316 about 1 km.</s>
<s id="d3p4s4">This area has a beautiful and wild landscape with primeval forest, protection forest and fresh environment.</s>
<s id="d3p4s5">It contains 13 small and large falls which pour water into diversified rock making wonderful landscape.</s>
<s id="d3p4s6">Phu Tho is calling investors to build the Cloudy waterfall area as ecology tourism and resorts.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p5">
<s id="d3p5s1">Investment project to build Cu Dong waterfall (the Mo Waterfall)</s>
<s id="d3p5s2">Located on Cu Thang commune, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province, is about 15km on the west away from Thanh Thuy hot mineral water tourism area, far from Xuan Son national park about 55km and near to highway 316 about 3 km.</s>
<s id="d3p5s3">The Mo waterfall is a system of small and continuous falls, of which, there are many over 50m ones pour over steep cliffs down the beach of iridescent magic pebbles.</s>
<s id="d3p5s4">Phu Tho encourages investment to change the Mo waterfall as ecology tourism area.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p6">
<s id="d3p6s1">Investment project to build Van Hoi lagoon tourism area</s>
<s id="d3p6s2">Located in Hien Luong commune, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province, the lagoon is far from Viet Tri about 80km, far from Au Co Mother Temple about 1 km, near to Hai Phong – Ha Noi – Kunming (China) highway.</s>
<s id="d3p6s3">The lagoon has a water surface of more than 200ha and 40 islands with the largest island is 10ha of area.</s>
<s id="d3p6s4">It has the system of water open supply and drainage so it can always maintain a stable water level which is very clean and pure.</s>
<s id="d3p6s5">Surrounding the lagoon is the system of mountains, hills, forests that creates a poetic landscape.</s>
<s id="d3p6s6">Phu Tho is calling investors to build the Van Hoi lagoon area become a tourism area of convalescences and luxury entertainment.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p7">
<s id="d3p7s1">Other projects:</s>
<s id="d3p7s2">Besides these projects, Phu Tho is encouraging investment on tourism projects: hotel with 4-5 stars, project to build Ao Gioi – Suoi Tien (Ha Hoa district) as ecology tourism area; project to build archaeological site of Ca village, Mun hill, Ren hamlet as destinations of culture tourism.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d4">
<head>POLICIES AND MECHANISM</head>
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">Incentives on land use:</s>
<s id="d4p1s2">Investors have the right to select the appropriate location and land area to suit their project scale based on approved plan and the right to choose between assigning the land with land usage fee and leasing the land under the current laws.</s>
<s id="d4p1s3">Investors are exempt from land lease fees from 3 to 15 years and enjoy a reduction of land lease fees from 20 to 50% depending on types of projects and investment locations in accordance with Decree No.: 142/2005/ND-CP dated 14th November 2005; the Decree No.: 121/2010/ND-CP dated 30th December 2010.</s>
<s id="d4p1s4">Investment projects on infrastructure of industrial zones shall receive support at 10% of land rent.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p2">
<s id="d4p2s1">Tax incentives policies:</s>
<s id="d4p2s2">Incentive beneficiaries: investors in the province are entitled to incentives according to investment sectors and locations as provided by Decree No 108/2006/ND-CP dated 22nd September, 2006 by the Government to issue detailed instructions for the implementation of certain clauses and provisions of the Law on Investment.</s>
<s id="d4p2s3">Incentives on enterprise income tax, import tax are defined in Investment Law, Import Export Tax Law, Decree No 124/2008/ND-CP dated December 11th, 2008; Decree No 149/2005/ND-CP dated December 8th, 2005 and current regulations remaining in force at the time of the project.</s>
<s id="d4p2s4">Investors shall be entitled 10% to 20% of reduction of tax rates for 10 to 30 years according to types of project and investment locations.</s>
<s id="d4p2s5">Investors shall be enjoyed tax holiday from 2 to 4 years and  50% reduction of tax rates in the next 4 to 9 years depending on types of projects and investment location.</s>
<s id="d4p2s6">Investor shall be exempted from import and export tax for create fixed asset of investment project in accordance with approved lists and regulation current  in force.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p3">
<s id="d4p3s1">Other incentives policies:</s>
<s id="d4p3s2">Investors shall be:</s>
<s id="d4p3s3">Received provision of power and water supply to the boundary of the project.</s>
<s id="d4p3s4">Gained support for road construction to the boundary of the industrial zones on scale depending on kind of project and area of investment but shorter than 3km.</s>
<s id="d4p3s5">Exempted from infrastructure fees during construction period (which does not exceed a maximum of 3 years) for the special incentive project; and exempted all with the project on public service in industrial zones.</s>
<s id="d4p3s6">The special important projects for the province shall be considered for special support policies.</s>
<s id="d4p3s7">Provided free of charge with documents relating to the project.</s>
<s id="d4p3s8">Exempted from administrative fees required for project application with project licensed by the province.</s>
<s id="d4p3s9">Exempted for fees for participation in investment and trade promotion conference organized in the province.</s>
<s id="d4p3s10">Exempted from contribution fees for the province when joining the province’s team to attend other investment promotion events.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<head>INVESTMENT PROCEDURES AND PROTOCOLS</head>
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">Administrative procedure for receiving investment project.</s>
<s id="d5p1s2">Phu Tho provincial People’s Committee promulgated “One door” for all projects in Phu Tho with quick, clear, effective procedure.</s>
<s id="d5p1s3">It reduces inconvenient, cost, and time of investors.</s>
<s id="d5p1s4">Investor shall prepare documents and submit at one of two main doors:</s>
<s id="d5p1s5">Department of Investment and Planning (for projects outside of industrial zone)</s>
<s id="d5p1s6">Industrial Zones Management Board (for projects within industrial zone).</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p2">
<s id="d5p2s1">Investment approval procedures:</s>
<s id="d5p2s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d5p2s3">Application for investment Approval Award by Investor.</s>
<s id="d5p2s4">Summary of investment project.</s>
<s id="d5p2s5">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d5p2s6">Department of Investment and Planning ( evaluation and recommendation) Duration: within 07 working days.</s>
<s id="d5p2s7">Phu Tho People’s Committee (consideration for approval) Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p3">
<s id="d5p3s1">Investment Certificate Procedure:</s>
<s id="d5p3s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d5p3s3">Location acceptance Permit (approved)</s>
<s id="d5p3s4">Investment Approval Award by the Province’s People committee</s>
<s id="d5p3s5">Investment project report and other related documents (if any)</s>
<s id="d5p3s6">Environmental assessment report (or commitment for environmental protection) - approved</s>
<s id="d5p3s7">Request for Investment Certificate issuance</s>
<s id="d5p3s8">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d5p3s9">Department of Investment and Planning ( evaluation and recommendation)Duration: within 15 working days.</s>
<s id="d5p3s10">Phu Tho People’s Committee (consideration for approval) Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p4">
<s id="d5p4s1">Procedure of establishment of enterprises, branches, representative offices</s>
<s id="d5p4s2">Types of documents:</s>
<s id="d5p4s3">Application (or notice on the establishment of branches, representative offices)</s>
<s id="d5p4s4">Identify card</s>
<s id="d5p4s5">Charter of company</s>
<s id="d5p4s6">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d5p4s7">Department of Investment and Planning ( consideration for issuance)Duration: within 05 working days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p5">
<s id="d5p5s1">Procedure of applying construction Permit</s>
<s id="d5p5s2">Documents consist:</s>
<s id="d5p5s3">Application for construction permit</s>
<s id="d5p5s4">Copy of document certifying of land use as a required by the Law on land</s>
<s id="d5p5s5">Blue prints of construction plan, cross section, typical vertical cut section, foundation plan, position plan, electricity and water plan with technical connection point for electricity, water and sewage system.</s>
<s id="d5p5s6">Recipient Agency and processing duration:</s>
<s id="d5p5s7">Department of Investment and Planning (receiving records and transfer to Construction Department)Duration: within 02 working days.</s>
<s id="d5p5s8">Construction Department (consideration for issuance) Duration: within 15 working days.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<head>ADDRESS OF CONTACTING AGENCIES FOR RECEIVING, EVALUATING INVESTMENT PROJECT DOCUMENTS AND SUPPORT INVESTORS</head>
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">Investment and Planning Department</s>
<s id="d6p1s2">Address: Tran Phu roal, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d6p1s3">TeL:+84-210 3 846 581</s>
<s id="d6p1s4">Fax: +84-210 3 840 955</s>
<s id="d6p1s5">Email: pitc.phutho@gmail.com</s>
<s id="d6p1s6">Website:www.dpi.phutho.gov.vn</s>
<s id="d6p1s7">Phu Tho Investment, Trade and Tourism Promotion Center (Investors supporting and consulting agency)</s>
<s id="d6p1s8">Address: Tran Phu road, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d6p1s9">Tex:+84-210 3 993 689</s>
<s id="d6p1s10">Fax: +84-210 3 993 589</s>
<s id="d6p1s11">Email: ptic.phutho@gmail.com</s>
<s id="d6p1s12">Website:www.dpi.phutho.gov.vn</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p2">
<s id="d6p2s1">Phu Tho Culture, Sport and Tourism Department (assisting investors)</s>
<s id="d6p2s2">Division of Resource and Tourism Development</s>
<s id="d6p2s3">Address: Tran Phu road, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d6p2s4">Tex:+84-210 3 686 979</s>
<s id="d6p2s5">Fax: +84-210 3 848 545</s>
<s id="d6p2s6">Email: tainguyendulichphutho@gmail.com</s>
<s id="d6p2s7">PMU of Culture, Sport and Tourism</s>
<s id="d6p2s8">Address: Tran Phu road, Tan Dan ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d6p2s9">Tex:+84-210 3 940 531</s>
<s id="d6p2s10">Fax: +84-210 3 952 068</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>

<body id="b4">
<div id="d1">
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">LUNAR NEW YEAR 2015 ACTIVITIES</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p2">
<s id="d1p2s1">New year news paper exhibition</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p3">
<s id="d1p3s1">From 8.00 am, Feb 12th to Feb 24th 2015</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p4">
<s id="d1p4s1">Sa Pa library - Cau May street, Sapa town</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p5">
<s id="d1p5s1">Art exhibition "Sa Pa Spring"</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p6">
<s id="d1p6s1">From 8:30, Feb 14th to Feb 24th2015</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p7">
<s id="d1p7s1">Xuan vien park, Sapa town</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p8">
<s id="d1p8s1">Lunar New year 2015 opening ceremony</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p9">
<s id="d1p9s1">rom 20:00, Feb 18th 2015 (Dec 30th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p10">
<s id="d1p10s1">Culture, sport, traditonal games of ethnic minorities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p11">
<s id="d1p11s1">From 8:30, Feb 13th 2015 to Feb 23rd 2015.</s>
<s id="d1p11s2">(Dec 25th to Jan 5th -lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p12">
<s id="d1p12s1">Music performance "upland color"</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p13">
<s id="d1p13s1">From 20:00, Feb 21st 2015 (Jan 3rd - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p14">
<s id="d1p14s1">Sapa love market</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p15">
<s id="d1p15s1">Từ 21h00', ngày 21/02/2015(tức ngày 3 tháng Giêng)</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p16">
<s id="d1p16s1">Playing Tennis</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p17">
<s id="d1p17s1">Culture, sport, traditonal games of ethnic minorities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p18">
<s id="d1p18s1">From 8:00, Feb 14th to Feb 24th2015</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p19">
<s id="d1p19s1">Culture and art activities of the H'mong people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p20">
<s id="d1p20s1">From 8:00, Feb 14th to Feb 24th2015</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p21">
<s id="d1p21s1">San Sa Ho’s Cat Cat Tourism area</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Lunar new year festival</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p2">
<s id="d2p2s1">Time</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p3">
<s id="d2p3s1">Location</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p4">
<s id="d2p4s1">The H'mong flute competition</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p5">
<s id="d2p5s1">8:00, Feb 22nd 2015 (Jan 4th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p6">
<s id="d2p6s1">Xoe Festival - Tay minority.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p7">
<s id="d2p7s1">8:00, Feb 24th 2015 (Jan 6th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p8">
<s id="d2p8s1">Thanh Phu Commune, Sapa District</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p9">
<s id="d2p9s1">Giao Duyen Festival - Dao minority.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p10">
<s id="d2p10s1">8:00 am, Feb 27th 2015 (Jan 9thlunar calendar )</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p11">
<s id="d2p11s1">Ta Phin Commune, Sapa District</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p12">
<s id="d2p12s1">Gauxtao Festival - San Sa Ho commune</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p13">
<s id="d2p13s1">8:00, Feb 28th 2015 (Jan 10th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p14">
<s id="d2p14s1">San Sa Ho Commune, Sapa District</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p15">
<s id="d2p15s1">Gauxtao Festival - Ta Giang Phin commune</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p16">
<s id="d2p16s1">8:00, March 1st 2015 (Jan 11th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p17">
<s id="d2p17s1">Ta Giang Phin Commune, Sapa District</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p18">
<s id="d2p18s1">Xuong Dong Festival - Ta Van Commune</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p19">
<s id="d2p19s1">8:00, March 5th 2015 (Jan 15th - lunar calendar)</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p20">
<s id="d2p20s1">Ta Van Commune, Sapa District</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Nam Giao Royal Offering Ritual</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p2">
<s id="d3p2s1">The Nam Giao Royal Offering Ritual was a traditional ceremony during the Nguyen dynasty which aimed to wish for favorable weather conditions, prosperity, and peace.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p3">
<s id="d3p3s1">This year, the ceremony will be held in a solemn atmosphere with all traditional rites.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p4">
<s id="d3p4s1">Thanks to its good nature and sincerity, the Offering Ritual has received the support of and will include participation from the people of the Ancient Capital.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d4">
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">Nam Giao Esplanade</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p2">
<s id="d4p2s1">Grand Opening Ceremony</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p3">
<s id="d4p3s1">The Grand Opening Ceremony presents a harmonious synthesis of traditional values and the contemporary arts of Hue, thus reflecting the rich and diverse cultural heritage of Vietnam and other nations from five continents.</s>
<s id="d4p3s2">Art performances will take place on a splendid, specially designed stage that brings the audiences to a brilliant “art banquet." The event is concluded by a stunning firework spectacle that promises to satisfy onlookers.</s>
</p>
<p id="d4p4">
<s id="d4p4s1">Noon Gate Square</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">Street performances of L'Homme Debout</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p2">
<s id="d5p2s1">At Hue Festival 2016, the company L'Homme Debout will present a poetic spectacle called Shining Stars in the Night, which evokes the intimate paths in the human mind with complicated feelings of conflict, retreat, wandering, and even collapse.</s>
<s id="d5p2s2">In the performance, a giant puppet of 7 meters in height, Liédo will be animated by professional artists and 40 local people.</s>
<s id="d5p2s3">His amazing movements are accompanied by music, lights, and fireworks.</s>
</p>
<p id="d5p3">
<s id="d5p3s1">Trinh Cong Son Park</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">Ao Dai Show: “The Beginning of a Legend”</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p2">
<s id="d6p2s1">Featuring the theme “The Beginning of a Legend," the Ao Dai Show of Hue Festival 2016 will be held at Quoc Hoc Square and will inspire the audience with collections of diverse styles by designers from the northern,centrall and southern regions.</s>
<s id="d6p2s2">The show will gather beauty queens, professional models, and more than 100 well-known artists and singers such as Quang Linh, Van Khanh, Quang Hao, etc., under the artistic leadership of Director Dinh Anh Dung.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p3">
<s id="d6p3s1">Quoc Hoc Square</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d7">
<p id="d7p1">
<s id="d7p1s1">Street Parade: “Heritage and Cultural Colors”</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p2">
<s id="d7p2s1">During past Hue Festivals, Street Parades have created a joyful atmosphere and fabulously contributed to exciting the crowd.</s>
<s id="d7p2s2">With the theme “Heritage and Cultural Colors," the parade this year will be renewed with participation of member countries in the Forum of East Asia - Latin America Cooperation (FEALAC).</s>
<s id="d7p2s3">The synergy between the talents of international and Vietnamese artists and the excitement of the public will create a space of friendship at Hue Festival 2016.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p3">
<s id="d7p3s1">Provincial Center for Culture &amp; Information</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d8">
<p id="d8p1">
<s id="d8p1s1">Imperial Night Program</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p2">
<s id="d8p2s1">As one of the highlights of Hue Festival, the “Imperial Night” reveals the unparalleled, shimmering beauty of the Imperial City at night time.</s>
<s id="d8p2s2">The program features various displays of royal music and dance, royal and folk games, as well as exceptional sound, and video effects in the mystifying settings of the Citadel.</s>
<s id="d8p2s3">The royal banquet, to be taken place at Can Chanh Palace at 19:30, is definitely the heart of the Imperial Night's celebrations.</s>
<s id="d8p2s4">It is a distinctive combination between Hue royal cuisine and royal art; where participants will have a chance to taste the essence of gastronomy and enjoy the performing art of the old days.</s>
</p>
<p id="d8p3">
<s id="d8p3s1">Hue Citadel</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d9">
<p id="d9p1">
<s id="d9p1s1">Closing Ceremony</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p2">
<s id="d9p2s1">The Closing Ceremony will be meticulously staged with the participation of domestic and international art troupes.</s>
<s id="d9p2s2">It is a mixture of tradition and modernity that will create a feast of all emotions for this farewell.</s>
<s id="d9p2s3">Until the next rendezvous!</s>
</p>
<p id="d9p3">
<s id="d9p3s1">Noon Gate Square</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d10">
<p id="d10p1">
<s id="d10p1s1">Fringe Activities</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p2">
<s id="d10p2s1">"Japanese Culture and Cuisine"</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p3">
<s id="d10p3s1">3/2 Park</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p4">
<s id="d10p4s1">Festival “Diabetes and Metabolic Disorders”</s>
</p>
<p id="d10p5">
<s id="d10p5s1">Green hotel Hue</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d11">
<p id="d11p1">
<s id="d11p1s1">Hue Science Festival 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p2">
<s id="d11p2s1">Taking the theme “Medical Achievements towards Community Health”, the Hue Science Festival 2016 will be held from April 28 to May 1, with two major contents: symposia and workshops, and community-oriented activities with a variety of activities such as free health consulting, enhancing the understanding on science fields in the community, introducing and promoting the health-care achievements and information to the public.</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p3">
<s id="d11p3s1">Hue College of Medicine and Pharmacy</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d12">
<p id="d12p1">
<s id="d12p1s1">International Trade Fair</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p2">
<s id="d12p2s1">Comprising of more than 600 booths from domestic and international businesses and enterprises, the International Trade Fair at Hue Festival 2016 will be held to introduce and exchange cultures as well as specific products between the participating countries and territories.</s>
<s id="d12p2s2">This is the opportunity for domestic business circle to promote their brand names and services to foreign investors and tourists, promote trade links and cooperation with the countries in the East-West Economic Corridor in the context of the international economic integration.</s>
<s id="d12p2s3">In the Fair, many exhibitions will also be held to introduce visitors the cultural, social and economic achievements, the potentials and advantages of the domestic enterprises, the preferential investment policies as well as the development in productions of local businesses and traditional craft villages.</s>
<s id="d12p2s4">All of these activities will serve trade promotion and market development.</s>
</p>
<p id="d12p3">
<s id="d12p3s1">Thua Thien Hue Sports Center</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d13">
<p id="d13p1">
<s id="d13p1s1">Hue International Cuisine Festival 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p2">
<s id="d13p2s1">Taking place at Phu Xuan Park (Nghinh Luong Pavilion – Phu Van Lau Pavilion), the Hue International Cuisine Festival 2016 will assemble more than 100 domestic and international booths from cities and provinces nationwide and those of South East Asia and Asia such as Japan, Korea, China, Taiwan, etc.</s>
<s id="d13p2s2">The event is to honor the quintessence of Viet Nam and international culinary culture as well as to boost cultural exchange and cooperation between Viet Nam and other countries in the region and the world.</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p3">
<s id="d13p3s1">Nghinh Luong Pavilion</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p4">
<s id="d13p4s1">National Senior Golf Championship 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p5">
<s id="d13p5s1">Laguna Lang Co’s Golf Court</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p6">
<s id="d13p6s1">Book &amp; Stamp Publications Fair</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p7">
<s id="d13p7s1">Provincial Center for Culture &amp; Information</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p8">
<s id="d13p8s1">Vegetarian cuisine court “Friendly environment – Happy life”</s>
</p>
<p id="d13p9">
<s id="d13p9s1">Lieu Quan Buddhist Cultural Center</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d14">
<p id="d14p1">
<s id="d14p1s1">Hue Science Festival 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p2">
<s id="d14p2s1">Taking the theme “Medical Achievements towards Community Health”, the Hue Science Festival 2016 will be held from April 28 to May 1, with two major contents: symposia and workshops, and community-oriented activities with a variety of activities such as free health consulting, enhancing the understanding on science fields in the community, introducing and promoting the health-care achievements and information to the public.</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p3">
<s id="d14p3s1">Ly Tu Trong Park</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p4">
<s id="d14p4s1">First meeting of the project: FEALAC Network of Cultural Cities</s>
</p>
<p id="d14p5">
<s id="d14p5s1">Saigon Morin Hotel</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d15">
<p id="d15p1">
<s id="d15p1s1">Kite Flying</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p2">
<s id="d15p2s1">Since ancient times, flying kite has been considered a creative recreation.</s>
<s id="d15p2s2">It has connected closely with many Vietnamese generation’s childhood and windy sky.</s>
<s id="d15p2s3">Kite is the symbol of peace, freedom and desire.</s>
<s id="d15p2s4">It reflects the burning dream of man to reach the sky.</s>
<s id="d15p2s5">The Kite Flying Fiesta “Wings of Vietnam” in Hue Festival 2016 is an opportunity for people of Hue and tourists to enjoy the beautiful and novel kites of kite clubs from all over the country.</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p3">
<s id="d15p3s1">Phu Van Lau</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p4">
<s id="d15p4s1">Hue Beer Festival</s>
</p>
<p id="d15p5">
<s id="d15p5s1">Nghinh Luong Pavilion</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d16">
<p id="d16p1">
<s id="d16p1s1">Exhibit of Woodblock Prints from Sinh Village</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p2">
<s id="d16p2s1">Over 400 years of existence, the folk paintings of Sinh village have carried within themselves numerous precious traditional folk art values.</s>
<s id="d16p2s2">Through time and social changes, the values of Sinh paintings have gradually been faded and deformed, many paintings and printing-boards are no longer in their original forms or missing.</s>
<s id="d16p2s3">The exhibition of folk paintings of Sinh village within the framework of Hue Festival 2016 is an activity aiming to reaffirm the reputation of a famous folk painting genre.</s>
<s id="d16p2s4">It also gives locals and tourists an opportunity to directly print paintings as well as explore their meaning, contributing the conservation and promotion of the cultural and artistic values of Hue.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p3">
<s id="d16p3s1">3/2 Park</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d17">
<p id="d17p1">
<s id="d17p1s1">The festivity "Rural Market on Festive Days"</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p2">
<s id="d17p2s1">Being held every two years as a fringe activity of the Hue Festival, the “Rural Market on Festive Days” Festivity is an opportunity to promote the original attraction of Huong Thuy District and special local produces.</s>
<s id="d17p2s2">The festivity is associated with new, attractive cultural, artistic, tourist and community activities to create a driving force for local socio-economic development.</s>
<s id="d17p2s3">Joining the festivity, visitors will be immersed in a peaceful and relaxed ambience of a typical Vietnamese village, despite its busy atmosphere of a new harvest.</s>
<s id="d17p2s4">It reminds them of their beloved hometowns and brings childhood memories flooding back.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p3">
<s id="d17p3s1">http://www.huefestival.com/index.php?cat_id=631</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p4">
<s id="d17p4s1">Thanh Toan roofed bridge, Huong Thuy Town</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d18">
<p id="d18p1">
<s id="d18p1s1">Sampam Racing</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p2">
<s id="d18p2s1">Sampan racing is a traditional sport infused with the national cultural identity.</s>
<s id="d18p2s2">This activity is held every year in an effort to promote the mutual understanding, exchanging and solidarity among locals.</s>
<s id="d18p2s3">It also enhances the tradition of sport practicing among people of Thua Thien Hue province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p3">
<s id="d18p3s1">Ly Tu Trong Park</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d19">
<p id="d19p1">
<s id="d19p1s1">Children's Fiesta "Colors of Childhood"</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p2">
<s id="d19p2s1">“Colours of Childhood” is a fiesta within Hue Festival that gives children a chance to play, learn, express and discover themselves.</s>
<s id="d19p2s2">This year, the fiesta will take place from April 30 to May 2 at Hue Children’s House and Nguyen Van Troi park with a variety of activities such as painting drawing, paper torn and pasted painting themed “The Colours of the Country”, folk songs festival “The Melody of My Homeland”, costume ball and cheerleading dance program entitled “Sparkling Colours” for students of primary and secondary schools in the city of Hue.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p3">
<s id="d19p3s1">Hue Children's House</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d20">
<p id="d20p1">
<s id="d20p1s1">Hue Science Festival 2016</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p2">
<s id="d20p2s1">Taking the theme “Medical Achievements towards Community Health”, the Hue Science Festival 2016 will be held from April 28 to May 1, with two major contents: symposia and workshops, and community-oriented activities with a variety of activities such as free health consulting, enhancing the understanding on science fields in the community, introducing and promoting the health-care achievements and information to the public.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p3">
<s id="d20p3s1">Hue College of Medicine and Pharmacy</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p4">
<s id="d20p4s1">National Hiphop Festival of Urban Jam</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d21">
<p id="d21p1">
<s id="d21p1s1">“Fragrances of an Ancient Village”</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p2">
<s id="d21p2s1">Joining the “Fragrances of an Ancient Village” festivity, visitors will have a chance to enjoy the pristine beauty and tranquility of a 500-year-old village with many ancient houses and temples.</s>
<s id="d21p2s2">People can come across traditional crafts such as pottery making in Phuoc Tich, wood carving in My Xuyen, or participate in flying kites and other sport games such as soccer, volley ball and tug of war on the beach of Dien Loc village.</s>
<s id="d21p2s3">Beside Phuoc Tich and My Xuyen, visitors will have an opportunity to explore other famous traditional craft villages in Phong Dien district, for example Pho Trach village with sedge based production, Phong Hai village with fish sauce making, Phong Chuong village with rice liquor production and Phong My village with fermented young bamboo production.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p3">
<s id="d21p3s1">Phuoc Tich Village, Phong Dien District</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p4">
<s id="d21p4s1">Bike parade "Business Community with the environment and wildlife protection</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p5">
<s id="d21p5s1">Nguyen Dinh Chieu Walking Street</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d22">
<p id="d22p1">
<s id="d22p1s1">Hue Poetry Festival</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p2">
<s id="d22p2s1">Being held on the side of the Huong river, Hue Poetry Festival is an opportunity for poets of the Writers’ Association of Thua Thien Hue and other provinces to exchange and recite the lyrical poems praising the country, people and islands.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p3">
<s id="d22p3s1">Int'l workshop: Royal and common culinary art - the extraordinary feature of Hue in the development of tourism</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p4">
<s id="d22p4s1">Indochine Palace Hotel - Hue</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p5">
<s id="d22p5s1">Rock Concert "The Ancient Capital's Heat"</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p6">
<s id="d22p6s1">Hot Air Balloon Festival</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p7">
<s id="d22p7s1">Ham Nghi Yard</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d23">
<p id="d23p1">
<s id="d23p1s1">Music Programs</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p2">
<s id="d23p2s1">Street music by Hue’s clubs</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d24">
<p id="d24p1">
<s id="d24p1s1">Lang Du Band</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p2">
<s id="d24p2s1">With the great success of Lang Du’s concerts at the last Hue Festival, the band and singer Dong Lan is returning to Hue Festival 2016 with an exclusive concert of passionate flamenco music and French love songs at An Dinh Palace, and at the vibrant and improvisational street performances in the afternoons.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p3">
<s id="d24p3s1">An Dinh Palace</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p4">
<s id="d24p4s1">The State Academic Kuban Cossack Chorus, Russia</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p5">
<s id="d24p5s1">Kien Trung's Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d25">
<p id="d25p1">
<s id="d25p1s1">Della Mae Band - The U.S</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p2">
<s id="d25p2s1">Della Mea (Boston, Massachusetts) was born in 2009 from a yearning for a traditional bluegrass sound in the heart of New England.</s>
<s id="d25p2s2">When the band started, there was not a single all-women bluegrass band on the national touring scene.</s>
<s id="d25p2s3">One of the main goals of Della Mae from the start was to showcase strong women in bluegrass.</s>
<s id="d25p2s4">Their musical style seamlessly blends years of experience with traditional mountain music and modern singer-songwriter sensibilities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p3">
<s id="d25p3s1">Thai Hoa's Western Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d26">
<p id="d26p1">
<s id="d26p1s1">Paulina y el Buscapié Band – Mexico</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p2">
<s id="d26p2s1">At Hue Festival 2016, Paulina y el Buscapié will introduce to the audience their second album titled Vetanas a la Calle.</s>
<s id="d26p2s2">In this album, the band interprets new compositions, seeking to open a window between the music and the audience, inviting them to look outside to the street – the public space – and reflect with each song the multiple approaches of the diverse and complex present.</s>
</p>
<p id="d26p3">
<s id="d26p3s1">An Dinh Palace</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d27">
<p id="d27p1">
<s id="d27p1s1">Michal Milczarek Trio – Poland</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p2">
<s id="d27p2s1">Michał Milczarek Trio is one of the most interesting young bands on the Polish jazz scene.</s>
<s id="d27p2s2">The group creates instrumental music which is a combination of modern jazz, rock and electronic.</s>
<s id="d27p2s3">It is known as one of the fastest prospering groups in Polish improvised music.</s>
<s id="d27p2s4">The band is known for a very intense concert activity, and Trio performances are considered to be extremely spontaneous and presenting jazz in a decidedly rock perspective.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p3">
<s id="d27p3s1">Royal Theater</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d28">
<p id="d28p1">
<s id="d28p1s1">Giao thoi Band</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p2">
<s id="d28p2s1">Giao Thoi has been considered as a diverse group.</s>
<s id="d28p2s2">Its repertoire is blended with not only the contemporary folk music and dance but also the world intangible cultural heritage such as the “Quan ho”, “Then” singing, “Ca Tru”, Hue traditional folk songs and the Southern folk music.</s>
<s id="d28p2s3">With the ambition to bring traditional music closer to young audiences, the group has renewed their compositions and created unique remixes by integrating modern music with the timbres of traditional instruments.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p3">
<s id="d28p3s1">Thai Hoa's Western Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d29">
<p id="d29p1">
<s id="d29p1s1">Germein Sisters Band – Australia</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p2">
<s id="d29p2s1">Australia’s Germein Sisters are a young indie pop band, singing catchy songs full of sunshine and a whole lot of heart.</s>
<s id="d29p2s2">Georgia, Ella, and Clara’s harmonies blend perfectly, with an intangible closeness unique to siblings.</s>
<s id="d29p2s3">Their infectious songs and upbeat performances immediately started attracting public attention.</s>
<s id="d29p2s4">The girls released their debut album "Because You Breathe" in Australia and Europe to much celebration and critical acclaim.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d30">
<p id="d30p1">
<s id="d30p1s1">Cancer Band – Denmark</s>
</p>
<p id="d30p2">
<s id="d30p2s1">Cancer is a new duo consisting of When Saints Go Machine lead singer and producer Nikolaj Manuel Vonsild and Chorus Grant lead singer and guitarist Kristian Finne Kristensen.</s>
<s id="d30p2s2">The two songwriters and friends have been working on creating a new and unique musical universe for several years.</s>
<s id="d30p2s3">Nikolaj Manuel Vonsild is known for his characteristic, beautiful, and soulful vocals in When Saints Go Machine’s electronic music.</s>
<s id="d30p2s4">Kristian Finne is known for his warm and ever-present vocals and the analog sound of guitars, bass, and drums in Chorus Grant.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d31">
<p id="d31p1">
<s id="d31p1s1">Stealing Sheep - The U.K</s>
</p>
<p id="d31p2">
<s id="d31p2s1">Stealing Sheep are a pop band from Liverpool, England, who formed in 2010.</s>
<s id="d31p2s2">The three members are Rebecca Hawley (vocals and keyboards), Emily Lansley (vocals and guitar) and Lucy Mercer (vocals and drums).</s>
<s id="d31p2s3">Their acclaimed 2012 debut, 'Into the Diamond Sun', morphed their individual styles to create a 'medieval-kraut-folk' inspired sound.</s>
<s id="d31p2s4">They were described as an unanticipated 'pagan pop revival' and since its release, have toured around Europe.</s>
<s id="d31p2s5">For second album ‘Not Real’ they have concentrated on developing the sonic aesthetic of their music.</s>
<s id="d31p2s6">They've experimented with tuned percussion, programmed beats, trigger samples and worked with effected synths, utilising the guitar and lap steel more sparingly and introducing more processed sounds.</s>
<s id="d31p2s7">The release of ‘Not Real’ in April 2015 was met with critical acclaim in the UK and Europe and a Summer of festivals followed including a stunning set at Glastonbury.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d32">
<p id="d32p1">
<s id="d32p1s1">Paulina y el Buscapié Band – Mexico</s>
</p>
<p id="d32p2">
<s id="d32p2s1">At Hue Festival 2016, Paulina y el Buscapié will introduce to the audience their second album titled Vetanas a la Calle.</s>
<s id="d32p2s2">In this album, the band interprets new compositions, seeking to open a window between the music and the audience, inviting them to look outside to the street – the public space – and reflect with each song the multiple approaches of the diverse and complex present.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d33">
<p id="d33p1">
<s id="d33p1s1">Fuzeta Band – France</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p2">
<s id="d33p2s1">FUZETA, who recently played at the International Contemporary Music Festival (Rencontres Transmusicales) in Rennes, dreamed to be the ferrymen to bring American pop music across the ocean.</s>
<s id="d33p2s2">The Breton quartet prove to be deserving successors with their awe-inspiring performances, no matter what disclosure they made about their improvised style.</s>
<s id="d33p2s3">Despite the influences from Grandaddy and Bon Iver, FUZETA still creates its own signature sound with a fantastic harmony of its members’ unique and fresh voices.</s>
<s id="d33p2s4">They are undoubtedly one of the most sought after French groups in the indie rock scene.</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p3">
<s id="d33p3s1">Hoang Rob &amp; GEN9 Quartet</s>
</p>
<p id="d33p4">
<s id="d33p4s1">Traditional Arts</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d34">
<p id="d34p1">
<s id="d34p1s1">Okinawa Art Troupe - Takamine Hisae – Japan</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p2">
<s id="d34p2s1">The Okinawa Dance Ensemble is led by Mrs.</s>
<s id="d34p2s2">Takamine Hisae, professor at Okinawa University of Arts and chairperson of the Ryukyu Okinawa Dance Association, who has made a major contribution in training numerous generations of artists.</s>
<s id="d34p2s3">Its repertoire focuses mainly on the art of singing and dancing that was formed through the trading and development process of the Ryukyu Kingdom with other countries in the area.</s>
</p>
<p id="d34p3">
<s id="d34p3s1">Royal Theater</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d35">
<p id="d35p1">
<s id="d35p1s1">Vietnamese Timber Show</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p2">
<s id="d35p2s1">Continuing the success of the previous Hue Festivals, this year, traditional musical values of Vietnam will be glorified once again in the opulent space of Dien Tho Palace through the talents of Phu Xuan Royal Court Music &amp; Folk Singing Club together with artists, artisans from Thai Ha “Ca tru” Club (Hanoi), “Bai Choi” and “Ho” Singing Conservation &amp; Development Center (Quang Ngai) and Danang Folk Singing Club.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p3">
<s id="d35p3s1">Dien Tho Palace</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p4">
<s id="d35p4s1">Thang Long Music and Dance Theatre</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p5">
<s id="d35p5s1">Kien Trung's Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d36">
<p id="d36p1">
<s id="d36p1s1">Youth Dance Ensemble - Sri Lanka</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p2">
<s id="d36p2s1">The Youth Dance Ensemble will make every effort to help Sri Lankan youth to improve their creativity and to ensure cultural exchange programmes with other countries whilst contributing to the promotion of Sri Lankan heritage.</s>
<s id="d36p2s2">In Hue Festival 2016, the Youth Dance Ensemble will introduce three distinct indigenous dance forms with a history of over 2500 years.</s>
<s id="d36p2s3">They are identified as Kandyan, Pahatharata and Sabaragamuwa dance forms.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p3">
<s id="d36p3s1">Can Chanh Stage - Hue Citadel</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d37">
<p id="d37p1">
<s id="d37p1s1">Fundación Changó Music Group</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p2">
<s id="d37p2s1">Being founded in 2004, Changó Pacific Music Foundation (Fundación de Música del Pacifico Changó) is an organization dedicated to preserving, strengthening, and spreading traditional music from Colombia’s South Pacific Coast.</s>
<s id="d37p2s2">The group’s music, which includes pango, patacoré, and caramba, among many others, reflects the unique cultural makeup of the region, including its African influence.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d38">
<p id="d38p1">
<s id="d38p1s1">Dancing Programs</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d39">
<p id="d39p1">
<s id="d39p1s1">Halleluya Dance Group – Israel</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p2">
<s id="d39p2s1">The fresh and dazzling Halleluya dance group has swept Israel and the world, with its youthful spirit, love of dance and diversified repertoire.</s>
<s id="d39p2s2">The company was created in 1988 by Barry Avidan, the choreographer and artistic director.</s>
<s id="d39p2s3">The group has already appeared on many TV networks and many stages around the world, sharing its colorful performances to dance lovers in Israel and abroad.</s>
<s id="d39p2s4">Halleluya Dance Company is embarking on a tour with a renewed program from the latest creations of Mr.</s>
<s id="d39p2s5">Barry Avidan, full of contemporary creation with traditional ethnic influences.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p3">
<s id="d39p3s1">Thai Hoa's Eastern Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d40">
<p id="d40p1">
<s id="d40p1s1">Amurskie Zori Dance Group – Russia</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p2">
<s id="d40p2s1">Being founded in 1989 with 218 talented children aged from 16 to 18, the folk dance group Amurskie Zori was named after the folk dance “Amurskie Zori”.</s>
<s id="d40p2s2">The group’s choreographer - Kuznetsov Pavel has worked as a choreographer for over 32 years.</s>
<s id="d40p2s3">In its repertoires, the group performs Russian folk dances, traditional dances of the Far Eastern region and others.</s>
<s id="d40p2s4">In 1994, Amurskie Zori was confered the title “The National Ensemble of Russia”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p3">
<s id="d40p3s1">Phuoc Tich Village, Phong Dien District</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d41">
<p id="d41p1">
<s id="d41p1s1">Youth Dance Ensemble - Sri Lanka</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p2">
<s id="d41p2s1">The Youth Dance Ensemble will make every effort to help Sri Lankan youth to improve their creativity and to ensure cultural exchange programmes with other countries whilst contributing to the promotion of Sri Lankan heritage.</s>
<s id="d41p2s2">In Hue Festival 2016, the Youth Dance Ensemble will introduce three distinct indigenous dance forms with a history of over 2500 years.</s>
<s id="d41p2s3">They are identified as Kandyan, Pahatharata and Sabaragamuwa dance forms.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d42">
<p id="d42p1">
<s id="d42p1s1">Halleluya dance group – Israel</s>
</p>
<p id="d42p2">
<s id="d42p2s1">The fresh and dazzling Halleluya dance group has swept Israel and the world, with its youthful spirit, love of dance and diversified repertoire.</s>
<s id="d42p2s2">The company was created in 1988 by Barry Avidan the choreographer and the Artistic director.</s>
<s id="d42p2s3">The group has already appeared on many TV networks and many stages in the world, sweeping its colorful performances to dance lovers in Israel and abroad.</s>
<s id="d42p2s4">Halleluya Dance Company is embarking on a tour with a renewed program from the latest creations of Mr.</s>
<s id="d42p2s5">Barry Avidan, full of contemporary creation with traditional ethnic influences.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d43">
<p id="d43p1">
<s id="d43p1s1">Youth Dance Ensemble - Sri Lanka</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p2">
<s id="d43p2s1">The Youth Dance Ensemble will make every effort to help Sri Lankan youth to improve their creativity and to ensure cultural exchange programmes with other countries whilst contributing to the promotion of Sri Lankan heritage.</s>
<s id="d43p2s2">In Hue Festival 2016, the Youth Dance Ensemble will introduce three distinct indigenous dance forms with a history of over 2500 years.</s>
<s id="d43p2s3">They are identified as Kandyan, Pahatharata and Sabaragamuwa dance forms.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d44">
<p id="d44p1">
<s id="d44p1s1">Par Terre Dance Group – France</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p2">
<s id="d44p2s1">Autarcie is a successful piece of dance by Anne Nguyen, a Vietnamese-French choreographer who was awarded the 2013 SACD New Choreography Talent Prize.</s>
<s id="d44p2s2">Autarcie depicts a strategy game, in which four dancers engage in a frantic ritual and improvised dance.</s>
<s id="d44p2s3">By using dance techniques such as breaking, popping, and waacking as abstract body language, each artist expresses his strong personality on the stage in seeking his own territory, alliance, and position among the intense and unbridled rhythms of electronic drums.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p3">
<s id="d44p3s1">Thai Hoa's Eastern Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d45">
<p id="d45p1">
<s id="d45p1s1">Yoon Muyung Hwa Dance Ensemble – Korea</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p2">
<s id="d45p2s1">Yoon Myung Hwa Dance Ensemble was founded in 1998 in an attempt to promote Korean traditional dances and create new ones inspired by authentic dances.</s>
<s id="d45p2s2">The ensemble has consistently pursued this approach throughout its development process.</s>
<s id="d45p2s3">The ensemble has received widespread appreciation for the aesthetic value of its performances both in Korea and abroad.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p3">
<s id="d45p3s1">Can Chanh Stage - Hue Citadel</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d46">
<p id="d46p1">
<s id="d46p1s1">Amurskie Zori Dance Group – Russia</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p2">
<s id="d46p2s1">Being founded in 1989 with 218 talented children aged from 16 to 18, the folk dance group Amurskie Zori was named after the folk dance “Amurskie Zori”.</s>
<s id="d46p2s2">The group’s choreographer - Kuznetsov Pavel has worked as a choreographer for over 32 years.</s>
<s id="d46p2s3">In its repertoires, the group performs Russian folk dances, traditional dances of the Far Eastern region and others.</s>
<s id="d46p2s4">In 1994, Amurskie Zori was confered the title “The National Ensemble of Russia”.</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p3">
<s id="d46p3s1">Thanh Toan roofed bridge, Huong Thuy Town</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p4">
<s id="d46p4s1">Exhibitions, Displays, Installation Art</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d47">
<p id="d47p1">
<s id="d47p1s1">Display of "Imperial Records of Nguyen Dynasty and the administrative organization of its court</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p2">
<s id="d47p2s1">Long Roofed Corridor - Hue Citadel</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p3">
<s id="d47p3s1">Exhibition: “Painting street”</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p4">
<s id="d47p4s1">Le Ngo Cat Street</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p5">
<s id="d47p5s1">Antique exhibit: “Artistic and Cultural Heritage of Ancient Buddhism &amp; Hinduism in Southern Regions”</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p6">
<s id="d47p6s1">Lieu Quan Buddhist Cultural Center</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p7">
<s id="d47p7s1">Display of Hue Kites</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p8">
<s id="d47p8s1">Hue Cultural Museum</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p9">
<s id="d47p9s1">Display of the Nguyen Dynasty's Golden Seals and Books</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p10">
<s id="d47p10s1">Hue Museum of Royal Fine Arts</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p11">
<s id="d47p11s1">"Hue - Saigon - Hanoi" Fine Arts Exhibition</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d48">
<p id="d48p1">
<s id="d48p1s1">Hue Cultural Museum</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p2">
<s id="d48p2s1">Display of two antique collections entitled "the tale of thousand-year antiques" by Lam Du Xenh and Nguyen Huu Hoang</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p3">
<s id="d48p3s1">Photo exhibit "Forests vs Hue Cultural Heritages"</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p4">
<s id="d48p4s1">Tu Tuong Park</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p5">
<s id="d48p5s1">Display: Collections of Japanese’s Pottery and Craft Products during the 18th and 20th centuries</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d49">
<p id="d49p1">
<s id="d49p1s1">Painting exhibition "Rendezvous"</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p2">
<s id="d49p2s1">Tran Dinh Son Private Museum – Hue</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p3">
<s id="d49p3s1">Ho Chi Minh Museum</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p4">
<s id="d49p4s1">Display of the Nguyen Dynasty and Hue of the past</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p5">
<s id="d49p5s1">Long Roofed Corridor - Hue Citadel</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p6">
<s id="d49p6s1">Exhibition: “Truc Chi Art – The History of Long An Palace”</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p7">
<s id="d49p7s1">Hue Museum of Royal Fine Arts</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p8">
<s id="d49p8s1">Exhibit of Restored Pottery Wares from Ly - Tran Dynasties by Artisan Tran Do</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p9">
<s id="d49p9s1">Interior Ministry, Imperial City</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p10">
<s id="d49p10s1">Exhibition: “The Cultural Imprints of Hue – The Ancient Capital and The Red River Delta via Traditional Craft Products”</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p11">
<s id="d49p11s1">Historical and Revolutionary Museum</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p12">
<s id="d49p12s1">Bonsai exhibit: “Orchids from the three regions of Vietnam and Hue Bonsai”</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p13">
<s id="d49p13s1">Co Ha Royal Garden, Imperial City</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p14">
<s id="d49p14s1">Exhibition: “Heritage Magazine and Hue Cultural Heritage”</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p15">
<s id="d49p15s1">Kien Trung's Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d50">
<p id="d50p1">
<s id="d50p1s1">Painting exhibition on Composer Trinh Cong Son</s>
</p>
<p id="d50p2">
<s id="d50p2s1">Exhibit of “Royal confectioneries” presented by artisan Hoang Anh</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d51">
<p id="d51p1">
<s id="d51p1s1">Art Programs</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d52">
<p id="d52p1">
<s id="d52p1s1">Viet Bac Folk Ensemble</s>
</p>
<p id="d52p2">
<s id="d52p2s1">The Viet Bac Folk Ensemble was founded in 1953 with its major tasks to compile and showcase the distinctive art genres of ethnic minorities in the Northern region and promote cultural exchanges with other countries in the world.</s>
<s id="d52p2s2">With its rich repertoires which are imbued with regional identity, humanity and affections for the people and the country, the Viet Bac Folk Ensemble has contributed a great deal to the conservation and the development of Vietnamese culture.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d53">
<p id="d53p1">
<s id="d53p1s1">The Central Cultural Palace of Mongolia</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d54">
<p id="d54p1">
<s id="d54p1s1">Guangdong Multi-Arts Ensemble – China</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p2">
<s id="d54p2s1">The Guangdong’s Silk Road Ensemble is comprised of talented artists and inheritors of intangible cultural heritage from Zhanjiang Dance Troupe, Guangdong Folk Dance and Classical Opera Theatre, Guangdong and Nanchang Music and Dance Troupes, and Guangzhou Vaudeville Theatre.</s>
<s id="d54p2s2">The Guangdong’s Silk Road Ensemble will present an exclusive and diversified repertoir of colorful ethnic dances in congruence with unrivaled traditional folk music and magic tricks reflecting the beauty of Lingnan’s culture.</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p3">
<s id="d54p3s1">Thai Hoa's Eastern Stage</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d55">
<p id="d55p1">
<s id="d55p1s1">Pantomime artist Jean-Louis Danvoye</s>
</p>
<p id="d55p2">
<s id="d55p2s1">Representing the Wallonie – Bruxlles region in Hue Festival 2016, Jean-Louis Danvoye will co-operate with the Vietnamese pantomime artist Hoang Tung to present the play “To see or not to see”.</s>
<s id="d55p2s2">This humorous wordless play is a perfect combination of mime art, the romance of visison and the ashtonishing spirit of the clowns.</s>
<s id="d55p2s3">The artists will take audience into their glamorous skits with skilled techniques and endless imagination.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d56">
<p id="d56p1">
<s id="d56p1s1">Thang Long Music and Dance Theatre</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p2">
<s id="d56p2s1">Founded in 1960 with the original name of the Hanoi Music &amp; Dance Ensemble, Thang Long Music and Dance Theatre always successfully completes its tasks.</s>
<s id="d56p2s2">During its 56 years of development, the theatre has conducted over a thousand of performances in the country and abroad and positively contributed to the development of Vietnam’s culture</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d57">
<p id="d57p1">
<s id="d57p1s1">Viet Bac Folk Ensemble</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p2">
<s id="d57p2s1">The Viet Bac Folk Ensemble was founded in 1953 with its major tasks to compile and showcase the distinctive art genres of ethnic minorities in the Northern region and promote cultural exchanges with other countries in the world.</s>
<s id="d57p2s2">With its rich repertoires which are imbued with regional identity, humanity and affections for the people and the country, the Viet Bac Folk Ensemble has contributed a great deal to the conservation and the development of Vietnamese culture.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p3">
<s id="d57p3s1">Thanh Toan roofed bridge, Huong Thuy Town</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d58">
<p id="d58p1">
<s id="d58p1s1">Belly Dancer Hong Hanh &amp; Sadie Dance Group</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p2">
<s id="d58p2s1">Being the belly artist that first paved the way for Vietnam's Belly Dance community to join the international arena, Do Hong Hanh has won over 20 awards at different contests of this art form.</s>
<s id="d58p2s2">Hanh also contributes actively to the development of this genre by joining judge panels of domestic and international belly dance contests and training Vietnam’s belly dance talents to attend major international competitions held annually.Besides, she has achieved a great success with the two belly dance groups, namely Sadie (for the age of 13 years and older) and Ministars (under 12 years of age).</s>
</p>
<p id="d58p3">
<s id="d58p3s1">Taking part in Hue Festival 2016, Hong Hanh and Sadie Belly Dance Group will ignite audiences with their inspiring and alluring dances.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d59">
<p id="d59p1">
<s id="d59p1s1">Pantomime artist Jean-Louis Danvoye</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p2">
<s id="d59p2s1">Representing the Wallonie – Bruxelles region at Hue Festival 2016, Jean-Louis Danvoye will partner with the Vietnamese pantomime artist Hoang Tung to present the play “To see or not to see”.</s>
<s id="d59p2s2">This humorous wordless play is a perfect combination of mime art, the romantic visison and the astonishing spirit of the clowns.</s>
<s id="d59p2s3">The artists will invite the audience into their glamorous skits with skilled techniques and endless imagination.</s>
</p>
<p id="d59p3">
<s id="d59p3s1">The Central Cultural Palace of Mongolia</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d60">
<p id="d60p1">
<s id="d60p1s1">Bong Sen Traditional Music and Dance Theatre</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d61">
<p id="d61p1">
<s id="d61p1s1">The State Academic Kuban Cossack Chorus, Russia</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p2">
<s id="d61p2s1">The State Academic Kuban Cossack Chorus is the oldest Russian folk chorus, with a history that goes back to 1811.</s>
<s id="d61p2s2">At that time it was a military choir of the Kuban Cossack Army, based in Ekaterinodar, the capital city of the South Russian province of Kuban, performing mostly in churches during religious services.</s>
<s id="d61p2s3">Later, the Chorus started to give secular stage performances, and its repertoire got broader with classical pieces and folk songs.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p3">
<s id="d61p3s1">For over 200 years now the Chorus has been a symbol and pride of Russian folk art.</s>
<s id="d61p3s2">The Chorus received highest awards for its great contributions in Russian culture.</s>
<s id="d61p3s3">It is the only company in Russia that received an honorary title of Ambassador of “SOCHI 2014” Olympics.</s>
</p>
<p id="d61p4">
<s id="d61p4s1">The temperament, originality and superior skills of the State Academic Kuban Cossack Chorus have received enthusiastic applauses in many countries as well as much praises from the national and foreign press and prominent figures in arts.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d62">
<p id="d62p1">
<s id="d62p1s1">Yangpyeong Dance Ensemble – Korea</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>

<body id="b5">
<head>THE NATIONAL CANDIDATURE FILE FOR INSCRIPTION ON THE REPRESENTATIVE LIST OF UNESCO THE WORSHIP OF HÙNG KINGS IN PHÚ Thọ</head>
<div id="d1">
<head>REPORT ON THE SCIENTIFIC INVENTORY OF THE WORSHIP OF HÙNG KINGS IN PHÚ Thọ PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Vietnam Institute of Culture and Arts Studies</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p2">
<s id="d1p2s1">Time Period The scientific inventory was carried out during the following times:</s>
<s id="d1p2s2">Phase 1: August 25 – September 30, 2010;</s>
<s id="d1p2s3">Phases 2 and 3: October 5, 2010 – February 30, 2011.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p3">
<s id="d1p3s1">Objectives The scientific inventory had the following objectives:</s>
<s id="d1p3s2">To survey and assess the situation of the worship of Hùng Kings among Vi?t communities within Phú Thọ province, where the worship of Hùng Kings originated and whence it has been passed on;</s>
<s id="d1p3s3">To systematically collect data provided by these communities in order to assess the existing situation of material heritage and cultural-religious activities directly related to the Hùng Kings, and draw on these data in planning for the further collection, preservation and promotion of the cultural-heritage values of the worship of Hùng Kings (as it has been carried out on different scales and at different levels for many years);</s>
<s id="d1p3s4">To collect scientific evidence in accordance with UNESCO’s guidelines and criteria, and later include this evidence in the profile to be submitted to  UNESCO for inscription of the worship of Hùng Kings on the Representative List of Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p4">
<s id="d1p4s1">Locations</s>
<s id="d1p4s2">Characteristics of Residential Areas and the System of Belief Practice and Festivals Related to the Worship of Hùng Kings</s>
<s id="d1p4s3">The area comprising all the villages/hamlets in which Hùng Kings worship and festivals related to figures of the Hùng Kings period take place is very  large, covering the eastern, northern and western parts of Phú Thọ province (12 out of 13 districts, towns and cities, and 74 out of 275 communes, wards and towns with 109 villages, hamlets and residential quarters); many of these sites can be found in two central areas, consisting of the communes, wards and towns of Vi?t Trì City and Lâm Thao District.</s>
<s id="d1p4s4">A unique character is worshipped in each of the belief spaces of nearly all the villages in these 12 districts, towns, and cities of Phú Thọ province.</s>
<s id="d1p4s5">As a  first step, we focus on the worship of Hùng Kings; later other characters will be examined as additional data relevant to determining the scale of worship.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p5">
<s id="d1p5s1">Selection of Villages for the Scientific Inventory The selection of villages for the scientific inventory was made with attention to the following issues:</s>
<s id="d1p5s2">On the basis of the Hùng Kings Family Tree, legends, conferments and petition sheets currently kept in the vicinity of Hùng Kings temples and shrines in communes of Lâm Thao District, Vi?t Trì City, as well as Sino-Vietnamese documents held by the Institute of Sino Studies, Vietnam Academy of Social Sciences, where titles of Hùng Kings are granted by different feudal dynasties (mostly from the 15th century and later), villages, hamlets and residential quarters worshipping the Hùng Kings are determined by the following criteria:</s>
<s id="d1p5s3">First, villages, hamlets and residential quarters with worshipping sites dedicated to figures named as Hùng Kings;</s>
<s id="d1p5s4">Second, villages, hamlets and residential quarters with  worshipping sites dedicated to the Hùng Kings under folk names (nicknames or names used because of certain taboos, etc.) such as ?t S?n Thánh V??ng, Vi?n S?n Thánh V??ng, ??t Ng?t Cao S?n and Cao S?n Thánh V??ng;</s>
<s id="d1p5s5">Third, villages, hamlets and residential quarters with worshipping sites dedicated to the Hùng Kings following the two above-mentioned criteria which existed before 1945, although they might no longer have worshipping sites or their worshipping sites are now in ruins, are also considered in  the determination of the cultural space of Hùng Kings worship;</s>
<s id="d1p5s6">Locations where there are worshipping sites under other names (such as ??c Thánh Sa L?c, ??i V??ng Thọ?ng ??ng Thọn, Hi?n Lang ??i V??ng, Hi?n Công ??i V??ng and ?ông H?i ??i V??ng) are also seen as worshipping sites dedicated to the Hùng Kings, and are named in a separate list to be investigated later.</s>
<s id="d1p5s7">In general, villages, hamlets and residential quarters to be investigated during this inventory are located in a semi-mountainous region where the mountains drop from the southwest (Yên L?p, Thanh S?n, Thanh Thọy, Tam Nông, and C?m Khê districts) to the northeast (Lâm Thao District, Vi?t Trì City, Phù Ninh District, Phú Thọ Town, Thanh Ba, ?oan Hùng, and H? Hòa districts).</s>
<s id="d1p5s8">Around Ngh?a L?nh stand low hills at the centre of the midlands.</s>
<s id="d1p5s9">Thousands of years ago, this area played a very important economic, social and cultural role, being both the site of the natural development of a community and the site where the Hùng Kings established the capital city of V?n Lang.</s>
<s id="d1p5s10">One can see that the direction in which the mountains fall – from northwest to southeast – is also the direction in which three major rivers flow – the Thao, the Lô, and the ?à – together contributing to the creation of fertile lands along their banks where communities of farmers developed and at the same time contributing to the formation of the delta.</s>
<s id="d1p5s11">The main livelihoods of people living within this area have remained almost the same to this day – wet-rice cultivation and animal husbandry.</s>
<s id="d1p5s12">Archeological evidence collected over the past 50 years shows that people of the ancient cultures of Phùng Nguyên, ??ng ??u, Gò Mun and ?ông S?n built houses, workshops and tombs in this area.</s>
<s id="d1p5s13">From a geographical-cultural perspective, the Vi?t–M??ng people have a long history.</s>
<s id="d1p5s14">The society was animistic, worshipping mountain gods, ancestors, tutelary gods and Buddhism.</s>
<s id="d1p5s15">Historically, Phú Thọ Province lies within the area of settlement and cultural intersection between the countries of V?n Lang and Âu L?c.</s>
<s id="d1p5s16">This area also served as a gate for exchange between the delta area, with the cultures of the northwest, and part of Vi?t B?c (North of Hanoi).</s>
<s id="d1p5s17">Generations of inhabitants of this area had close political, economic, cultural and social relationships with each other.</s>
<s id="d1p5s18">The area has a long history of formation  involving   many  important  events related  to  the establishment, development and protection of the country by the ancient Vi?t people together with other ethnic groups.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p6">
<s id="d1p6s1">Research Methods</s>
<s id="d1p6s2">Research methods included interviews by questionnaire, in-depth interviews, focus-group interviews, recording oral histories, and statistics.</s>
<s id="d1p6s3">The research was carried out in a participatory way with respect for community voices, with one of its aims being preservation of history.</s>
<s id="d1p6s4">An interdisciplinary research approach (including bibliography, archeology, text studies, and museum studies) was also taken for analysis and comparison of different sources of information and determination of the subject of the investigation and inventory.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p7">
<s id="d1p7s1">Difficulties</s>
<s id="d1p7s2">Over the long history of the area's development, because of natural geological changes and social and economic changes following different administrative structures, many place names have changed with old  names being replaced by new.</s>
<s id="d1p7s3">Knowledgeable people are few, texts have not been transferred sustainably or systematically to younger generations, many administrative places have shifted or been extended, many belief practices and customs have degraded (especially in the period since 1945), and in many cases contemporary culture has supplanted traditional culture.</s>
<s id="d1p7s4">Gaps have appeared in the generational transfer of traditional culture because of war and other historical-social conditions.</s>
<s id="d1p7s5">On field trips to the localities, we noticed that many sites associated with the worship of Hùng Kings (communal halls, temples, Buddhist temples, shrines) had been destroyed or seriously damaged.</s>
<s id="d1p7s6">There are also cases where temples/communal halls have been moved to new sites for restoration, and re- built with new techniques, forms and materials, and as a result have become religiously unattractive or irrelevant to their communities.</s>
<s id="d1p7s7">In most of the places investigated, the cultural staff and commune managers are young people who have limited capacities and understandings of  traditional culture, do not understand or cannot meet standard requirements of cultural management, and are incapable of helping local people collect, investigate and preserve their heritage.</s>
<s id="d1p7s8">As a result, many valuable heritage sites which were destroyed or damaged have not received the necessary attention for development of restoration plans or submission of requests for financial support from the authorities.</s>
<s id="d1p7s9">Since 1996, most residential areas which in the past were villages and hamlets have been changed into numbered residential quarters (Residential Quarter No.1, No.2, No.3, etc.).</s>
<s id="d1p7s10">Thus, the traditional names of many villages and hamlets which had existed for thousands years, were rooted deeply in the minds of local people and were closely associated with the characteristics and origins of each village/hamlet as well as many other traditional values have been eliminated.</s>
<s id="d1p7s11">In addition, several large, densely populated villages/hamlets have also been divided into residential quarters.</s>
<s id="d1p7s12">Now, only in residential quarters where worshipping sites are situated do local people pay much  attention to or know (at differing levels) about the worship.</s>
<s id="d1p7s13">In other residential quarters, people are much less attached to the belief, and therefore their awareness and sense of responsibility have faded.</s>
<s id="d1p7s14">In many villages, sites associated with Hùng Kings worship were destroyed (for different reasons) many decades ago, and the worshipping space in some villages/hamlets has been taken over for use by local authorities or individuals.</s>
<s id="d1p7s15">Thus, in many places it is almost impossible to restore ancient belief activities – a great  loss to the culture.</s>
<s id="d1p7s16">The worship of Hùng Kings is a cultural activity originating from a dynasty passed on in legends.</s>
<s id="d1p7s17">All the figures associated with this ancient period over thousands of years of worship by common people have been molded and transformed according to diverse cultural layers and customs.</s>
<s id="d1p7s18">herefore, even when they exist in the same worshipping space, sometimes it is very difficult  to name the main worshipped figure.</s>
<s id="d1p7s19">In many places it is difficult to identify worshipped  figures  because  of  ambiguity  and transformation  (due  to hèm customs or perceptions) as well as replacement of figures (between Hùng Kings and related figures).</s>
<s id="d1p7s20">Due to the limited time allocated to the inventory and limited number of professional staff, the work of data collection together with the community showed certain shortcomings.</s>
<s id="d1p7s21">These shortcomings partly reflect in the results of the inventory and investigation, especially in the evaluation of typical expressions of the heritage and the system of ancient languages which are closely associated with the traditional festivals in particular and cultural activities of the villages/communes in general.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p8">
<s id="d1p8s1">Advantages</s>
<s id="d1p8s2">During the time carrying out the inventory, the research group received a great deal of support from local authorities, district/commune cultural staff and village heads who worked to create favorable working conditions for the group.</s>
<s id="d1p8s3">In particular, almost all the hamlet heads and commune cultural staff participated directly in organizing focus-group interviews in the localities, actively addressing issues raised during the interviews and contributing greatly to the production of results from the interviews.</s>
<s id="d1p8s4">All the local people (especially the elderly people and members of the festival management board) either directly or indirectly participated  in providing information.</s>
<s id="d1p8s5">They were enthusiastic and formed a consensus in  regard to the preservation, promotion and dissemination of Hùng Kings worship and festivals related to the Hùng Kings in their localities.</s>
<s id="d1p8s6">Many elderly people provided the research group with valuable documents which individuals had collected, complied or translated and which serve well as references for the questionnaires.</s>
<s id="d1p8s7">Support from members of the heritage site management board and association of elderly people in villages in organizing and facilitating interviews helped the research group a great deal in ensuring the quality of the inventory.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p9">
<s id="d1p9s1">Investigation–Inventory Results</s>
<s id="d1p9s2">Given the above-mentioned advantages and surmounted difficulties, the research group achieved certain results.</s>
<s id="d1p9s3">Documents and information provided  by the focus groups and by the questionnaires confirm the diversity, newness and systematicness of documentation and knowledge of Hùng Kings worship and festivals associated with the Hùng Kings in the past and the present.</s>
<s id="d1p9s4">Cultural-historical heritage sites were identified in 12 districts, towns and cities (C?m Khê, ?oan Hùng, H? Hòa, Lame Theo, Phù Ninh, Tam Nông, Thanh Ba, Thanh S?n, Thanh Thọy and Yên L?p districts, Phú Thọ Town, and Vi?t Trì City) with 109 villages, hamlets and residential quarters being investigated, among which 46 villages and hamlets (in 29 communes, wards and towns) are home to cultural activities and festivals directly related to Hùng Kings worship, and have worshipping sites under the names of the original Hùng Kings or their 18 generations of descendants.</s>
<s id="d1p9s5">These villages and hamlets with existing heritage sites directly associated with Hùng Kings worship and festivals are mostly situated in Lâm Thao District and Vi?t Trì City.</s>
<s id="d1p9s6">The existence of a number of festivals directly associated with the worship of Hùng Kings in several villages and hamlets of C?m Khê District (Kh?ng T??c village), Lam Thao District (the two villages of Tr?o and Vi) and Vi?t Trì City (Hùng Lô village) with significant remnants (ponds, drill grounds of Hùng King troops, places where the Kings stopped to visit local people, places where the Kings celebrated the New Year together with villagers, places where the Kings taught people how to cultivate rice, etc.) and a number of ancient place names have provided important data, contributing to the success of the research on the culture and beliefs of the ancient Vi?t – M??ng people.</s>
<s id="d1p9s7">Together with the above-mentioned sites, there are also 139 sites in 52 communes (76 villages or hamlets) of 12 districts worshipping Hùng Kings under names such as Cao S?n Thánh V??ng, ??t Ng?t Cao S?n, ?t S?n Thánh V??ng and Vi?n S?n Thánh V??ng.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p10">
<s id="d1p10s1">Specific Results from the Investigation-Inventory</s>
<s id="d1p10s2">The data obtained from the research contain a great deal of information which can be divided into two main groups: quantitative data (obtained using quantitative research methods such as questionnaires and statistics) and qualitative data (obtained using ethnographical methods and oral history recording, etc.)These data reflect on: a.cultural and belief activities and festivals related to the Hùng Kings which took place in the past; b/ cultural and belief activities and festivals related to the Hùng Kings which take place today; c.chief characteristics of these cultural and belief activities; d.the condition of the tangible culture associated with the belief and festival activities; and, e.issues relating to the preservation and promotion of the cultural values of the belief practices and festivals associated with the Hùng Kings in particular and figures of the Hùng King period in general.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p11">
<s id="d1p11s1">Cultural and Belief Activities and Festivals in the Past</s>
<s id="d1p11s2">Cultural and Belief Activities Places serving the belief and festival activities were gradually established in all villages and hamlets by local communities over a period of many hundreds of years, in the form of communal halls, temples and shrines, of which communal halls made up more than 90%.</s>
<s id="d1p11s3">The inventory list shows the dense distribution and establishment of worshipping places related to the worship of Hùng Kings in Phú Thọ Province.</s>
<s id="d1p11s4">In 46 villages and hamlets having worshipping sites under the direct name of the Hùng Kings there are 43 communal halls, 6 temples and 2 Buddhist temples.</s>
<s id="d1p11s5">In 76 villages/hamlets having worshipping sites under the names of Cao S?n Minh V??ng, ??t Ng?t Cao S?n, ?t S?n Thánh V??ng or Vi?n S?n Thánh V??ng there are 99 communal halls, 15 temples, 18 shrines, and 7 Buddhist temples.</s>
<s id="d1p11s6">According to the oral histories obtained from elderly people, in most villages/hamlets, before 1945, the worshipping sites dedicated to the Hùng Kings  in  particular  and  other  figures  in  Phú  Thọ  Province  in general were established  during one  or the  other of two  historical periods.</s>
<s id="d1p11s7">Before  the  10th century, most of the worshipping sites (communal halls, temples, and shrines) were made of bamboo and with thatched roofs, while some were made in the form of a house on pillars to avoid predators and flooding.</s>
<s id="d1p11s8">Since the Lý Dynasty, and especially under the Lê Dynasty (the 15th century), with the permission of local authorities and the court, people in Phú Thọ Province (as in many other places) mobilized the community to build big (both in terms of architectural structure and interior) worshipping sites in villages.</s>
<s id="d1p11s9">People also organized large-scale sacred and solemn festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p11s10">Besides paying attention to the sites through granting conferments and orders, feudal  governments  also gave permission for villages to restore worshipping sites in order to serve the belief activities, considering this a tool of the ruling apparatus  at  different levels.</s>
<s id="d1p11s11">For the period after 1945, due to the limited knowledge of local authorities, and because of the weather and natural conditions, most worshipping  sites (90%) in Phú Thọ Province were destroyed or ran to ruin.</s>
<s id="d1p11s12">The most serious destruction occurred in 1956–57, 1961 and 1975.</s>
<s id="d1p11s13">Only since the 1990s have many of these worshipping sites been restored to serve the needs of  local cultural and belief activities.</s>
<s id="d1p11s14">Due to economic conditions, most of the restored worshipping sites are smaller in scale and simpler in architecture than their originals.</s>
<s id="d1p11s15">However, about 20% of the sites in these villages/hamlets have been completely destroyed, for various objective and subjective reasons.</s>
<s id="d1p11s16">Only since the time of ??i M?i (Renovation) in Vietnam have rural communities had opportunities to improve their economy and enrich their culture by restoring traditional cultural practices.</s>
<s id="d1p11s17">Having examined the real situation of the worshipping sites and taken into account community opinions, we see that most villages associated with the worship of the Hùng Kings in particular and  cultural and belief activities in general now need higher-level policy and economic support to restore or upgrade the worshipping sites in order to meet the short and long-term needs of the communities.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p12">
<s id="d1p12s1">Worshipping Altars</s>
<s id="d1p12s2">In practice, it can be seen that of 181 communal halls and 15 Buddhist temples (of which 43 communal halls and 8 Buddhist temples are dedicated to the Hùng Kings) the focus of the altar arrangement is the worshipping tablet and the incense bowls.</s>
<s id="d1p12s3">At some worshipping sites, there is also an additional altar for all gods.</s>
<s id="d1p12s4">In general, the worshipping altars of the Hùng Kings are made in the form of ancestral altars like those which stand in the houses of most Vietnamese families.</s>
<s id="d1p12s5">Taking Ngh?a L?nh Mountain as the center of Hùng Kings worship, the farther worshipping sites are from this center, the simpler their arrangements; they are not as complicated as the worshipping sites built by feudal regimes at the end of the Post-Lê Dynasty or during the Nguy?n  Dynasty.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p13">
<s id="d1p13s1">Offerings</s>
<s id="d1p13s2">Offerings prepared for the rituals (rituals of opening the communal halls/temple gates, processions, rituals of closing the communal halls/temple gates) in most localities are quite similar to one another.</s>
<s id="d1p13s3">They include xôi (cooked sticky rice), o?n (cake from cooked sticky rice), fruits, flowers, wine, votive papers, salt, boiled chickens (ideally large, handsome roosters), raw pork (ideally from a black pig), ch?ng cake and dày cake (offered by people of Lâm Thao District and Vi?t Trì City).</s>
<s id="d1p13s4">n addition, some villages (?ào Xá village in Thanh Thọy District, B?n ?á village in C?m Khê District) include carp in their offerings.</s>
<s id="d1p13s5">In Tr?o and Vi villages (Lâm Thao District) and Hùng Lô village (Vi?t Trì City), people give whole pigs (ideally black pigs), usually already killed and cleaned, along with some of their bristles and blood, as offerings.</s>
<s id="d1p13s6">Some villages/hamlets of H? Hòa, ?oan Hùng, and Yên L?p districts require that among the offerings there should be meat from a black buffalo.</s>
<s id="d1p13s7">It is stipulated in village conventions that all participants in the preparation of offerings – for example, in the selection of roosters, pigs, leaves for the cakes, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p13s8">should be carefully chosen.</s>
<s id="d1p13s9">All the steps in making the cakes, killing the roosters or the pigs, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p13s10">should also be taken very carefully.</s>
<s id="d1p13s11">For offerings made from meat (black pigs, roosters, buffalos, etc.), strict rules apply to all steps.</s>
<s id="d1p13s12">For example, families chosen to raise the pigs should be happy, well-off, respected by other villagers and not in mourning; the pigs should be kept in open, clean pigsties; containers for their food should be clean and new (the families should buy new bowls and make new pigsties); their food should be clean and  delicious.</s>
<s id="d1p13s13">In some villages, two or three families are chosen to raise the  animals.</s>
<s id="d1p13s14">When the day of the festival draws near, the entire village will select the best of several animals for the offerings.</s>
<s id="d1p13s15">When the pigs are killed, the blood should be red; if the blood is not bright red, it is considered bad luck.</s>
<s id="d1p13s16">When the rooster is killed and cleaned, its skin should not be torn.</s>
<s id="d1p13s17">The rooster must not be put into boiling water, but hung on a stick above the pot, and people must pour boiling water over it until it is cooked.</s>
<s id="d1p13s18">In regard to fruits, in the past, villagers chose those without pips, and they could pick them only in the land where they had settled down and lived.</s>
<s id="d1p13s19">They were not allowed to take fruits from other places.</s>
<s id="d1p13s20">Villagers believe that if these unwritten rules were violated, people would have bad luck, their livestock would fall sick, their crops would fail, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p13s21">In addition to offerings common to all villages/hamlets worshipping  the Hùng Kings, unique features of offerings prepared by certain villages may also be observed.</s>
<s id="d1p13s22">For example, in the offerings prepared by C? Tích village (Hy C??ng commune, Vi?t Trì City), three branches of young rice are laid on the offering tray together with cooked sticky rice and boiled rooster, and a wish for good weather and good crops is made.</s>
<s id="d1p13s23">In the rituals of Vi and Tr?o villages of Hùng S?n Town, Lâm Thao District, among the usual offerings there must be a votive black elephant and two horses (one pink and the other white).</s>
<s id="d1p13s24">These animals are made of bamboo, covered with paper and life-size.</s>
<s id="d1p13s25">A small bamboo stick is tied to a side of each of these animals to serve as a pot where incense sticks can be kept until the last day of the festival when they are burned.</s>
<s id="d1p13s26">It is believed that these animals serve as means of transport for the Hùng Kings and the gods so that they can go to people facing difficulties such as strong winds, flood, disease, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p13s27">(See also Bùi Quang Thanh, “Offerings to Hùng Kings”.</s>
<s id="d1p13s28">Vietnam Academy of Social Sciences, 6 (146) – 2011).</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p14">
<s id="d1p14s1">Selection of the Ritual Heads</s>
<s id="d1p14s2">In the past, the ritual head for each festival was also selected very carefully.</s>
<s id="d1p14s3">In feudal times (before 1945), ritual heads were selected by local authorities.</s>
<s id="d1p14s4">Later, this position usually came to be determined by village elders and representatives of village clans.</s>
<s id="d1p14s5">A person selected to be a ritual head should meet the following criteria: male, over 50 years old, with sound knowledge of the ritual procedures, trusted and respected by his community, and not in the mourning period.</s>
<s id="d1p14s6">When a person has been selected to be the ritual head, he should observe certain unwritten rules such as avoiding participation in  funerals, avoiding hard work and avoiding sexual intercourse to keep his body clean.</s>
<s id="d1p14s7">He must practice the ritual gestures regularly so that when the  time comes he can perform them gracefully and in conformity with the ritual group.</s>
<s id="d1p14s8">If he makes a mistake, he will be punished by his village.</s>
<s id="d1p14s9">The ritual head from the year before is responsible for instructing him during his practice period.</s>
<s id="d1p14s10">In addition, the person selected to be the ritual head should be able to afford the organization of the festival, from inviting different troupes (chèo plays, ca trù singing, and xoan singing, etc.) to inviting his relatives to the festival, from the day of opening to the day of closing.</s>
<s id="d1p14s11">For the ritual group (??i t?) the criteria are less strict.</s>
<s id="d1p14s12">Ritual group members must be middle-aged, respected by the community and not in the mourning period.</s>
<s id="d1p14s13">The ritual head manages the operation of the ritual group.</s>
<s id="d1p14s14">People who know the ritual procedures well (usually from the ritual group of the year before) also help coach the ritual group for a time.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p15">
<s id="d1p15s1">The Traditional Festivals</s>
<s id="d1p15s2">According to the oral histories of elders in all 196  villages/hamlets, before 1945 villages held the festivals each year on differing scales, depending on economic and social conditions and specific village customs.</s>
<s id="d1p15s3">In the past, two types of festivals took place every year:</s>
<s id="d1p15s4">The inter-canton festival (the festival jointly organized by several villages in a canton or jointly organized by villages in a customary friendship relationship, worshipping the same communal god);</s>
<s id="d1p15s5">The festival held in each village/hamlet at a different time (in this case, the people of village divisions (giáp) played a vital role).</s>
<s id="d1p15s6">Most of the festivals took place in the first lunar month or in the eighth and ninth lunar months.</s>
<s id="d1p15s7">The organizer of the festivals: As stipulated by the feudal authorities, before 1945 the Committee of Mandarins at canton level directly organized and managed festivals in which the main worshipped figures had been recognized and given conferment by the court.</s>
<s id="d1p15s8">In regard to village festivals, various giáp in the villages cooperated in organizing the festivals, with each giáp taking responsibility for specific tasks assigned by the Committee of Village Elders.</s>
<s id="d1p15s9">Funds for festival organization came from two sources: proceeds from fields given to the temple (by local authority or by the court), and donations by men of different giáp participating in the festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p15s10">Festival procedure: Most focus-group interviews came to the conclusion that festival procedure in individual villages in particular and throughout Phú Thọ Province in general was very complicated and diverse.</s>
<s id="d1p15s11">Currently there are no written texts (epitaphs, legends, village customary laws, etc.) in any villages/hamlets stipulating festival procedure.</s>
<s id="d1p15s12">Today festivals are organized according to procedures passed down from earlier generations.</s>
<s id="d1p15s13">However, certain procedural elements are common throughout the province.</s>
<s id="d1p15s14">In  most cases, the procession goes from the shrine to the communal hall or temple; or goes from the communal hall or temple around the village and returns to the starting point.</s>
<s id="d1p15s15">The order of the procession groups is also consistent from village to village: The group of the dancing dragon comes first, then the group carrying the gods’ flags, then the palanquin, eight musical instruments, two rows of eighttreasures and weapons, the incense palanquin, the chair and tablet palanquin, the ritual group, and finally the villagers.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p16">
<s id="d1p16s1">Belief activities and folk games</s>
<s id="d1p16s2">In almost all the sacred spaces of Hùng Kings worship, local communities organize various cultural activities in which unique symbols representing specific characteristics of habitation, aesthetic style, and perceptions of nature and society are displayed.</s>
<s id="d1p16s3">These activities include:Belief activities associated with fertility rites, in which symbols of linga and yoni are worshipped and acts of sexual intercourse are mimicked in a game named tùng rí; Belief activities associated with wet-rice cultivation, in which water from the middle of a river is brought to the temple to serve as a worship object, and young rice plants are also placed on the altar; Belief activities in which the career and merits of the worshipped person are enacted: the gestures of the King when he taught people how to cultivate rice and hunt; the gestures of the Princess when she taught people how to raise silkworms and weave fabric.</s>
<s id="d1p16s4">Belief activities associated with the explanation of certain phenomena in nature and society: why people howl to call/find each other at night when lost in the forest; how the King taught people to make blood pudding when killing pigs.</s>
<s id="d1p16s5">Belief activities associated with unique inventions from the earliest days of the country’s establishment: how the King taught people how to broil meat after a hunt, perform martial arts, use the bow and arrow, and establish villages close to one another so that they could help and protect one another.</s>
<s id="d1p16s6">In most regions, especially in isolated villages, people perform similar prayer rituals, such as praying for wealth, for favorable weather, for peace, for a son, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p16s7">in their worship of the Hùng Kings.</s>
<s id="d1p16s8">In addition to rituals and belief activities performed in the sacred space of the worship of Hùng Kings and other related characters, folk games associated with national memories and the community’s perceptions of everyday life's realities and aesthetic ideals are played by participants of various ages.</s>
<s id="d1p16s9">Some of these folk games are popular and common to all villages (such as blind-man’s-buff, tug of war, flag catching, swimming competition, and catching ducks in pond or river), and some are unique and specific to certain villages in Phú Thọ Province (such as pig encirclement, trò trám, a fertility game, c??p ph?t, a game of competing to catch a ball, tùng rí, etc.).</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p17">
<s id="d1p17s1">Belief Practice and Festivals in Contemporary Society</s>
<s id="d1p17s2">From the time of the August Revolution of 1945 until the end of the 20th century, for different reasons and because of different historical circumstances, most of the places serving belief practices such as temples, communal halls and shrines were destroyed or badly damaged, and folk festivals were not organized.</s>
<s id="d1p17s3">In most villages, people quietly prepared offerings and burnt incense to worship the Hùng Kings in particular and other related characters in general at home or in their family worshipping halls.</s>
<s id="d1p17s4">Thus, serious damage was done to these communities' tangible and intangible culture.</s>
<s id="d1p17s5">A great number of valuable cultural heritages have been lost, ruined or forgotten.</s>
<s id="d1p17s6">Gaps in the passing on of traditional culture between generations have had negative impacts on Hùng Kings worshipping communities' social and cultural life.</s>
<s id="d1p17s7">From the late 1980s on, particularly from 1995 until today, in the many villages in 12 districts worshipping the Hùng Kings in Phú Thọ Province, 50% of sites have been restored (after 1990), 10% have been repaired, 20% are in danger of becoming ruins, and 20% have already become ruins.</s>
<s id="d1p17s8">Before 1945, most villages worshipping the Hùng Kings regularly organized traditional festivals at different levels.</s>
<s id="d1p17s9">After nearly half a century  of interruption, from the late 1980s on, these traditional festivals have been restored.</s>
<s id="d1p17s10">The belief and its associated cultural organizations have  been permitted to operate again.</s>
<s id="d1p17s11">In villages, the elderly (50 years and older) have played an important role in restoring and directly participating in festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p17s12">Funds for festival organization are mainly donated by local people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p18">
<s id="d1p18s1">Differences between Today's Festivals and Festivals in the Past</s>
<s id="d1p18s2">The duration of festivals today is much shorter than in the past (now they mainly take place over one or two days).</s>
<s id="d1p18s3">The processes of task assignment, budget management and organization of the festival are now discussed openly, and local people can share their opinions on all relevant matters.</s>
<s id="d1p18s4">All people of villages/hamlets where there are festivals have equal opportunity to participate in the annual or main festival (in accordance with regulations prescribed by festival management boards or local authorities), from contributing human resources to receiving material and moral benefits from the festival.</s>
<s id="d1p18s5">The festival is organized by the site management board which manages communal halls/ temples under the direct control of the local authority.</s>
<s id="d1p18s6">Funds for festival organization are partly given by the local authority if possible.</s>
<s id="d1p18s7">However, in most cases, they are donated by the community.</s>
<s id="d1p18s8">Common temple land from which benefits may be saved for festival organization as they were under feudal society no longer exists.</s>
<s id="d1p18s9">Because of issues of public security and changes in belief and other cultural practices, festivals now are not as boisterous as in the past.</s>
<s id="d1p18s10">Ritual forms and offerings have also been simplified and the meanings of the worship objects have also been lost to some extent.</s>
<s id="d1p18s11">The process of preparation of offerings has been made simpler; complicated details relating to selection and arrangement of offerings as practiced in the past are now foregone.</s>
<s id="d1p18s12">Certain parts of the ritual ceremony which are too complicated or long have been removed or shortened.</s>
<s id="d1p18s13">Belief activities with mysterious meanings and amulets are not practiced anymore.</s>
<s id="d1p18s14">Further, certain cultural activities with fertility-related meanings have not been restored.</s>
<s id="d1p18s15">All members of local communities participate in “luck food” feasts, and all are equal in festival activities.</s>
<s id="d1p18s16">During the processes of preparation and organization of the festival, the community and the local authority coordinate closely with each other to ensure security and legal issues are dealt with following guidelines from the local authority.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p19">
<s id="d1p19s1">Main Features of the Worship of Hùng Kings in Phú Thọ</s>
<s id="d1p19s2">Most Hùng Kings worshipping villages perform rituals associated with different annual festivals: Lunar New Year, First Full Moon, the festival of ploughing, the festival of harvest, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p19s3">Perhaps the most remarkable of these is the ritual praying for favorable weather, and good luck in business, life and health.</s>
<s id="d1p19s4">Offerings are very important.</s>
<s id="d1p19s5">They are carefully selected and include at least three things – a rooster, a black pig and fruits.</s>
<s id="d1p19s6">To a certain extent, ancient elements associated with the worship of the Hùng Kings remain, expressing themselves in festival performances and folk games associated with ancient legends.</s>
<s id="d1p19s7">The festival is diverse in form and sacred in content and belief practice, displaying people’s profound awareness of their origins and their history of establishing and protecting the country.</s>
<s id="d1p19s8">Roles played in the festival are strictly controlled, requiring actors to be strong both in body and in mind.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p20">
<s id="d1p20s1">The System of Cultural Heritage Sites associated with Hùng Kings Worship:</s>
<s id="d1p20s2">Tangible cultural heritage in villages: The inventory shows that most worshipping sites which are a hundred years old or older have been destroyed.</s>
<s id="d1p20s3">The few which remain are in very bad condition.</s>
<s id="d1p20s4">Most of the common land which in the past belonged to the worshipping sites has been encroached upon (for example in villages of Đoan Hùng, Hạ Hòa and Yên Lập districts).</s>
<s id="d1p20s5">The surrounding facilities have also been destroyed, changed or used for other purposes, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p20s6">Many heritage sites have not received proper attention from cultural management boards.</s>
<s id="d1p20s7">Some sites have been encroached upon or used for non- belief purposes.</s>
<s id="d1p20s8">According to the statistics of the local authority, at present, in 46 villages/hamlets directly practicing the worship of Hùng Kings, 80% of the ponds associated with this belief have been either filled up or narrowed to serve different purposes.</s>
<s id="d1p20s9">any ponds, shrines and temples associated with heritage sites have disappeared: e.g. he place believed to be the drill ground during the time of the Hùng Kings in Tiên Kiên commune (Lâm Thao), Đạng communal hall in Xuân Viên commune (Yên Lập), Đanh communal hall in Chính Công commnune, Tân Tiến communal hall in Vĩnh Chân commune (Hạ Hòa).</s>
<s id="d1p20s10">Some sites which in the past were spacious worshipping sites have been destroyed, and currently there are no fund for their restoration (e.g.Cả communal hall in Hùng Sơn town, Lâm Thao district; the cluster of sites in Đanh hamlet, Chính Công commune, Hạ Hòa).</s>
<s id="d1p20s11">Of the sites that have been restored in the last decade by local communities, none can be compared with its original in terms of scale and architecture.</s>
<s id="d1p20s12">In most of these new sites, the interior of the worshipping space is still simple and does not meet traditional requirements of worship.</s>
<s id="d1p20s13">The system of intangible cultural heritage in villages/hamlets: So far, most of the villages/hamlets in Phú Thọ Province which have sites associated with Hùng Kings worship do not keep documents of legends, festival information, folk games or activities related to this belief.</s>
<s id="d1p20s14">In some villages, elderly people try to keep records and translate the legends  and parallel sentences which have  been recorded at local heritage sites.</s>
<s id="d1p20s15">However, this source of information has yet to be properly drawn on.</s>
<s id="d1p20s16">At some sites, there are collections of books in Sino-Vietnamese which have not yet been translated into modern Vietnamese, so that a great deal of information about traditional culture is still unknown and inaccessible to younger generations of local people.</s>
<s id="d1p20s17">Passing on Heritage between Generations: Those with the best knowledge of the procedures and contents of festivals are the elderly people who have directly participated in past festivals and performances.</s>
<s id="d1p20s18">The number of these people is small; however, some of them are now members of festival management boards and heritage site management boards in villages/hamlets.</s>
<s id="d1p20s19">The largest group of people participating in the rituals is made up of middle-aged men, aged 50 and older.</s>
<s id="d1p20s20">For certain festival activities, the largest group is made up of young people, aged from 15 to 25.</s>
<s id="d1p20s21">In the inventory questionnaires, 100% of respondents confirmed that younger generations – children of families living in the villages – are enthusiastic and eager to participate in certain festival activities, but are not eager to carry out ritual practices.</s>
<s id="d1p20s22">Interviews with children participating in the festival “Procession of the Kings to the village for Tết” (Hùng Sơn town) and “Meeting the Kings for the spring in villages” (Tiên Kiên commune) at the end of 2010 and beginning of 2011, indicated that all were proud to have been selected and eager to participate in the festivals without being paid, given that they are allowed to by their families and schools.</s>
<s id="d1p20s23">However, because of modern social circumstances and time restrictions, not all young people actively look  for information about their nation’s origins or the aspects of their culture preserved and performed in local festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p20s24">Most of the legends, copies of the Kings’ family tree, epitaphs and other sources of information in Sino-Vietnamese which are kept in villages have not yet been translated or disseminated, nor have most of the parallel sentences and words inscribed on horizontal lacquered boards in communal halls, temples and Buddhist temples, or the many books in Sino-Vietnamese.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p21">
<s id="d1p21s1">Issues Relating to the Preservation and Promotion of Heritage Values</s>
<s id="d1p21s2">The Situation and Positive Impact of the Heritage</s>
<s id="d1p21s3">Most of the belief and cultural activities associated with the worship of Hùng Kings (under different names) in 12 districts/town/cities of Phú Thọ Province have	already	received attention from	local communities, and worshipping sites and festivals have been restored.</s>
<s id="d1p21s4">However, economic difficulties together with other objective and subjective circumstances have meant that the number of restored sites is still small.</s>
<s id="d1p21s5">Examples can be given in poor districts such as Hạ Hòa, Thanh Ba, Yên Lập, and Thanh Sơn.</s>
<s id="d1p21s6">Also, because the belief practice was prohibited and therefore did not receive any attention from local authorities or local people for half a century, many sites have been encroached upon to differing degrees.</s>
<s id="d1p21s7">Many of the objects used at rituals or for interior decoration are broken.</s>
<s id="d1p21s8">Meanwhile, communities need  ritual practice.</s>
<s id="d1p21s9">In most localities, costs for the restoration of worshipping sites have been covered by communities.</s>
<s id="d1p21s10">Examples can be given in Cẩm Khê and Phù Ninh districts and Việt Trì City.</s>
<s id="d1p21s11">Among villagers today, middle-aged people show the highest level of awareness of the necessity of heritage preservation, as evidenced by their contributions to preservation projects.</s>
<s id="d1p21s12">If in the second half of the 20th century elderly people were the largest group practicing Hùng Kings  worship,  then since the 1990s more and more young people have been participating in worshipping activities, both male and female.</s>
<s id="d1p21s13">Particularly in localities with many traditional festivals such as Cẩm Khê, Lâm Thao, Thanh Thuỷ, and Phù Ninh districts and Việt Trì City, people of widely different groups and backgrounds participate in festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p21s14">In the last ten years, several localities have restored festival activities worshipping the Hùng Kings (Đào Xá commune in Thanh Thuỷ district, Hùng Lô commune in Việt Trì City, Khổng Tước commune in Cẩm Khê district, Vi and Trẹo villages in Hùng Sơn town and villages in Tiên Kiên commune, Lâm Thao district, etc.), thus helping younger generations understand and learn more about traditional values, their nation’s history, and preservation of traditional values.</s>
<s id="d1p21s15">The survey of villages where festivals worshipping Hùng Kings are held in particular and village festivals in general shows that local authorities and cultural  management  boards  at  different  levels  (but  especially  at commune level) have directly participated in and taken responsibility for organizing, managing and monitoring all steps of the festivals, and that in this respect local people are satisfied with local authorities at commune and village level.</s>
<s id="d1p21s16">This is also evidence of the consensus which has created sustainable conditions for the preservation of the festivals, bringing a positive influence upon the exploitation of the festivals’ values and meanings.</s>
<s id="d1p21s17">As a first step, the local authority has co-operated with the community in accordance with the principles of socialization in management in order to preserve and exploit the heritage site’s values, and restore the heritage sites as required in each specific case, meeting the community’s needs in belief  practice.</s>
<s id="d1p21s18">90% of survey respondents agreed with the work done by the local authority during restoration and preservation of festivals associated with the worship of Hùng Kings.</s>
<s id="d1p21s19">Possible Risks for the Heritage Sites:</s>
<s id="d1p21s20">95% of survey discussion participants saw weaknesses and limitations in various aspects of the heritage preservation: namely, in collection of related information, and in historical recording of the worship and procedures of local traditional festivals.</s>
<s id="d1p21s21">The number of people who know Sino-Vietnamese has decreased significantly; in some localities today, no one knows this language.</s>
<s id="d1p21s22">Most of the knowledge of festival procedures, content, activities and performance (palanquin procession, folk games, etc.) has only been passed on orally.</s>
<s id="d1p21s23">Some elderly people have been trying to record this kind of information.</s>
<s id="d1p21s24">Mainly, however, they do it spontaneously and subjectively.</s>
<s id="d1p21s25">The information recorded has not been discussed carefully and has not been disseminated widely in the community.</s>
<s id="d1p21s26">This has led to the gradual loss of this source of intangible cultural heritage which was invented and practiced in the past and to loss of the unique local identity associated with it.</s>
<s id="d1p21s27">100% of discussion participants regarded the local authority’s weakness at various levels in managing the processes of information collection, recording and disseminating relevant information to members of the community as one of the causes of the loss of heritage site values.</s>
<s id="d1p21s28">90% of discussion participants believed that the local authority was not active enough or creative enough in widening its network and mobilizing resources in society for the preservation and exploitation of cultural heritage in the locality.</s>
<s id="d1p21s29">100% of discussion participants suggested that the local authority should improve its capacity in management so that the Law on Cultural Heritage could be implemented in practice and made to meet the needs of cultural heritage preservation in each village/hamlet.</s>
<s id="d1p21s30">As stated by some representatives of village heritage management boards, one of the reasons that heritage sites had been neglected and their ecological- human environment negatively affected was that the people tasked with taking care of the sites (temple guards, ritual heads, members of the heritage management boards, etc.) were not paid for their service.</s>
<s id="d1p21s31">Cultural management at various levels focuses largely on drawing up and disseminating  administrative guidelines and organizing activities to disseminate government policies.</s>
<s id="d1p21s32">Cultural management workers are not proactive in making long-term plans for the preservation and exploitation of cultural heritage values in the localities.</s>
<s id="d1p21s33">Most of the cultural management staff working for the Department of Culture and Information at district level or commune/ward level are young people with limited knowledge of local traditional culture.</s>
<s id="d1p21s34">Therefore, their management is not effective and cannot meet the community’s needs in preservation and exploitation of cultural heritage.</s>
<s id="d1p21s35">In practice, coordination between schools and the community in the preservation of cultural heritage in villages is weak.</s>
<s id="d1p21s36">The relevant propaganda does not seem to be very effective.</s>
<s id="d1p21s37">In the Year 6 Textbook on Linguistics and Culture, the section introducing legends and traditional festivals associated with the period of Hùng Kings and the nation’s origin is quite short.</s>
<s id="d1p21s38">In some places, the local authority and the community disagree on the values of their cultural heritage.</s>
<s id="d1p21s39">For example, in Xuân Viên commune, Yên Lập district, the local authority currently is withholding approval of the restoration of worship places which had existed in the past but were destroyed in the 1970s, arguing that it does so to fight superstition.</s>
<s id="d1p21s40">The community is willing to contribute money to restore these heritage sites which in the past were part of the grand procession in the commune’s traditional festival.</s>
<s id="d1p21s41">However, the local authority has not given its approval for the restoration, and so the people of Xuân Viên commune must practice their belief in the neighboring commune.</s>
<s id="d1p21s42">Property violation and encroachment occurs at many sites of Hùng Kings worship, due to either bad land use management or bad cultural management, illegally or with the permission of the local authority.</s>
<s id="d1p21s43">in addition, the local authority in some places also allows people to destroy heritage sites to use the land for other purposes.</s>
<s id="d1p21s44">Most discussion participants suggested that the authorities at various levels should pay more attention to groups of successful local businessmen who wish to fund the restoration of their local cultural heritage.</s>
<s id="d1p21s45">This report was written by Associate Professor, Dr.Bùi Quang Thanh Head of the Inventory group of the Worship of Hùng Kings</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<head>LIST OF VILLAGES FOR HÙNG KINGS WORSHIP IN PHÚ THỌ PROVINCE</head>
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">No.</s>
<s id="d2p1s2">Place</s>
<s id="d2p1s3">Hamlet/Village/Residential quarter</s>
<s id="d2p1s4">Commune/Ward/Township</s>
<s id="d2p1s5">District</s>
<s id="d2p1s6">Thượng Tinh Xá Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s7">Thanh Xá</s>
<s id="d2p1s8">THANH BA</s>
<s id="d2p1s9">Tinh Xá Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s10">Lăng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s11">Thái Ninh</s>
<s id="d2p1s12">Đông Thượng Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s13">Đông Thành</s>
<s id="d2p1s14">Đối Đen Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s15">Đông Lĩnh</s>
<s id="d2p1s16">2Thượng Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s17">Khải Xuân</s>
<s id="d2p1s18">Lũng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s19">Võ Lao</s>
<s id="d2p1s20">Chùa Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s21">Quản Dương Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s22">Lương Lỗ</s>
<s id="d2p1s23">Quán Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s24">Quán Lương Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s25">Residential quarter 16 (Mạo Phổ Hamlet)</s>
<s id="d2p1s26">Residential quarter 2</s>
<s id="d2p1s27">Quảng Nạp</s>
<s id="d2p1s28">Residential quarter 3</s>
<s id="d2p1s29">Residential quarter 4 (Ngoài Hamlet)</s>
<s id="d2p1s30">Võ Village (Đồng Lạn Hamlet)</s>
<s id="d2p1s31">Vũ Yển</s>
<s id="d2p1s32">Sấu Village (Hoàng Cương Hamlet)</s>
<s id="d2p1s33">Hoàng Cương</s>
<s id="d2p1s34">Giuồng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s35">Mạn Lạn</s>
<s id="d2p1s36">Vàng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s37">Yển Khê</s>
<s id="d2p1s38">Nghĩa Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s39">Ngăn Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s40">Đại An</s>
<s id="d2p1s41">Tân Thân Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s42">Yên Nội</s>
<s id="d2p1s43">Lem Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s44">Phương Trà Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s45">Liên Phương</s>
<s id="d2p1s46">Xuân Áng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s47">Hậu Bổng</s>
<s id="d2p1s48">Đan Village (Residential quarter 1).</s>
<s id="d2p1s49">Đan Hòa</s>
<s id="d2p1s50">Vô Tranh Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s51">Võ Tranh</s>
<s id="d2p1s52">Cầu Xây Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s53">Ấm Hạ</s>
<s id="d2p1s54">Phú Vĩnh Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s55">Bằng Giã</s>
<s id="d2p1s56">Bến Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s57">Đanh Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s58">Chính Công</s>
<s id="d2p1s59">Trường Thiên Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s60">Vĩnh Chân</s>
<s id="d2p1s61">Tân Tiến Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s62">Tân Lập Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s63">Minh Tiến</s>
<s id="d2p1s64">ĐOAN HÙNG</s>
<s id="d2p1s65">Phú Nham Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s66">Phú Thứ</s>
<s id="d2p1s67">Vĩnh Lại Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s68">Hùng Quan</s>
<s id="d2p1s69">Kê Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s70">Phúc Lai</s>
<s id="d2p1s71">Lê Hùng Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s72">Sóc Đăng</s>
<s id="d2p1s73">Đình Cả Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s74">Tiên Sơn</s>
<s id="d2p1s75">Đại Hộ Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s76">Đại Nghĩa</s>
<s id="d2p1s77">Đám Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s78">Chí Đám</s>
<s id="d2p1s79">Ngọc Tân Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s80">Ngọc Quan</s>
<s id="d2p1s81">Đồng Bích Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s82">Hùng Long</s>
<s id="d2p1s83">Đồng Kệ Hamlet (Đồng Kệ Village)</s>
<s id="d2p1s84">Đồng Cam</s>
<s id="d2p1s85">CẨM KHÊ</s>
<s id="d2p1s86">Vực Câu Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s87">Tiên Lương</s>
<s id="d2p1s88">Mỹ Đức Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s89">Quyết Tiến Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s90">Sâu Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s91">Tuy Lộc</s>
<s id="d2p1s92">Vực Cầu Hamlet (Residential quarter 9)</s>
<s id="d2p1s93">Sông Thao Township</s>
<s id="d2p1s94">Đông Viên Village (Residential quarter 4)</s>
<s id="d2p1s95">Gọ Village Phùng Xá</s>
<s id="d2p1s96">Cầu Ngòi Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s97">Cấp Dẫn</s>
<s id="d2p1s98">Đoài Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s99">Thanh Nga</s>
<s id="d2p1s100">Gò Làng Village (Residential quarter 4)</s>
<s id="d2p1s101">Sơn Tình</s>
<s id="d2p1s102">Gò Village (Residential quarter 6 - 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s103">Khổng Tước Hamlet – Chùa Village(Residential quarter 6)</s>
<s id="d2p1s104">Phượng Vỹ</s>
<s id="d2p1s105">Trình Khúc Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s106">Văn Khúc</s>
<s id="d2p1s107">Ô Đà Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s108">Thạch Đê Village (Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s109">Hiền Đa</s>
<s id="d2p1s110">Bến Đá Village (Residential quarter 5)</s>
<s id="d2p1s111">Chương Xá</s>
<s id="d2p1s112">Hamlet Quyết Tiến</s>
<s id="d2p1s113">Tuy Lộc</s>
<s id="d2p1s114">Đình Village (Residential quarter 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s115">Đồng Luận</s>
<s id="d2p1s116">THANH THỦY</s>
<s id="d2p1s117">Đào Xá Hamlet (Residential quarter 5)</s>
<s id="d2p1s118">Đào Xá</s>
<s id="d2p1s119">Phương Giao (Residential quarter 12-13)</s>
<s id="d2p1s120">Hạ Bì Trung</s>
<s id="d2p1s121">Xuân Lộc</s>
<s id="d2p1s122">Kim Đức Village (Residential quarter 6)</s>
<s id="d2p1s123">Kim Đức</s>
<s id="d2p1s124">VIỆT TRÌ city</s>
<s id="d2p1s125">Kim Đái Hamlet (Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s126">Thét Village (Residential quarter 8)</s>
<s id="d2p1s127">Lâu Thượng</s>
<s id="d2p1s128">Trưng Vương ward</s>
<s id="d2p1s129">Hòa Bình 1 Hamlet (Residential quarter 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s130">Bến Gót ward</s>
<s id="d2p1s131">Hòa Bình 2 Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s132">Giải Village (Hồng Hải Village)</s>
<s id="d2p1s133">Minh Nông ward</s>
<s id="d2p1s134">Village Từ Mõ (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s135">Hùng Lô Commune</s>
<s id="d2p1s136">Phú Nang (Residential quarter 4)</s>
<s id="d2p1s137">Vân Phú ward</s>
<s id="d2p1s138">Vân Luông Hamlet (Residential quarter 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s139">Lũng Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s140">Hy Cương Commune</s>
<s id="d2p1s141">Cổ Tích Village</s>
<s id="d2p1s142">Thuần Lương Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s143">Sông Lô Commune</s>
<s id="d2p1s144">Vân Khê Hamlet – Thia communal house(Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s145">Hà Lộc</s>
<s id="d2p1s146">PHÚ THỌ town</s>
<s id="d2p1s147">Hạ Hamlet</s>
<s id="d2p1s148">Thanh Minh</s>
<s id="d2p1s149">Mạo Village (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s150">Thanh Lâu Hamlet (Residential quarter 8)</s>
<s id="d2p1s151">Trẹo Village (Residential quarter 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s152">Hùng Sơn township</s>
<s id="d2p1s153">LÂM THAO</s>
<s id="d2p1s154">Hậu Lộc Village (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s155">Phường Village (Residential quarter 16)</s>
<s id="d2p1s156">Vi Cương Hamlet (Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s157">Huy Sơn Village (Residential quarter 14)</s>
<s id="d2p1s158">Vi Village (Đông communal house)–Residential quarter 3</s>
<s id="d2p1s159">Mở Village - Residential quarter 12 (Tập Lục communal house)</s>
<s id="d2p1s160">Tiên Kiên</s>
<s id="d2p1s161">Lum Village (Residential quarter 7 )</s>
<s id="d2p1s162">Cả communal house (Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s163">Đoàn Kết Village – Giã Village (Residentialquarter 4)</s>
<s id="d2p1s164">Mua Village - Quan Mạc pagoda(Residential quarter 5)</s>
<s id="d2p1s165">Khuân Dậu</s>
<s id="d2p1s166">Trung Giáp</s>
<s id="d2p1s167">PHÙ NINH</s>
<s id="d2p1s168">Đình Village Phú Nham</s>
<s id="d2p1s169">Nội Hamlet (Residential quarter 8)</s>
<s id="d2p1s170">Hạ Giáp</s>
<s id="d2p1s171">Thanh Thúy</s>
<s id="d2p1s172">Bảo Thanh</s>
<s id="d2p1s173">Vải Đạng Hamlet (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s174">Xuân Viên</s>
<s id="d2p1s175">YÊN LẬP</s>
<s id="d2p1s176">Giai Thượng</s>
<s id="d2p1s177">Thắng Sơn</s>
<s id="d2p1s178">THANH SƠN</s>
<s id="d2p1s179">Chòi  Village (Residential quarter 13)</s>
<s id="d2p1s180">Cự Thắng</s>
<s id="d2p1s181">Dẹ Hamlet (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s182">Văn Miếu</s>
<s id="d2p1s183">Ba Mỏ Township</s>
<s id="d2p1s184">Thanh Sơn Township</s>
<s id="d2p1s185">Chùa Village (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s186">Xuân Quang</s>
<s id="d2p1s187">TAM NÔNG</s>
<s id="d2p1s188">Bình Lỗ Hamlet (Residential quarter 9)</s>
<s id="d2p1s189">Thanh Uyên Hamlet (Residential quarter 3)</s>
<s id="d2p1s190">Thanh Uyên</s>
<s id="d2p1s191">Sơn Cương Hamlet (Residential quarter 1)</s>
<s id="d2p1s192">Hồng Đà</s>
<s id="d2p1s193">Hạ Nông Hamlet (Residential quarter 6)</s>
<s id="d2p1s194">Gò Dược Village (Residential quarter 2)</s>
<s id="d2p1s195">Dị Nậu</s>
<s id="d2p1s196">Gia Khảm Village (Residential quarter 6)</s>
<s id="d2p1s197">Hoàng Hanh Village (Residential quarter 7)</s>
<s id="d2p1s198">Total</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>

<body id="b6">
<head>Phu Tho Guide Book</head>
<div id="d1">
<head>Introduction</head>
<p id="d1p1">
<s id="d1p1s1">Phu Tho is a midland and mountainous province lying in the middle of Northern Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d1p1s2">It is situated at the apex of the triangular Northern plain delta, linking the Northern mountainous area and the flat plain.</s>
<s id="d1p1s3">The province is where three big rivers Thao, Lo and Da joins each other and it is surrounded by two mountains namely Ba Vi and Tam Dao.</s>
<s id="d1p1s4">Phu Tho back against the area of hills and mountains lying close to each other like upside down bowls at the end of Hoang Lien Son range.</s>
<s id="d1p1s5">It looks over the fertile Red River delta.</s>
<s id="d1p1s6">All these make Phu Tho a favorable position of “mountains gathering and rivers meeting”.</s>
<s id="d1p1s7">The nature endows Phu Tho with many beauty spots like Bach Hac crossroad, Ao Gioi Suoi Tien (God Pond - Fairy Stream), Ao Chau Lake, Van Hoi Lake, Thanh Thuy hot mineral water mine, Xuan Son National Park, etc.</s>
<s id="d1p1s8">They are very valuable natural tourism resources for the development of ecotourism, health tourism and wildlife tourism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p2">
<s id="d1p2s1">Furthermore, Phu Tho is known as the place of national origin.</s>
<s id="d1p2s2">Its historic-cultural traditions go along with the history of national construction and defense.</s>
<s id="d1p2s3">Hung Kings chose this place to start building up the nation that he named Van Lang, the first state of Vietnam.</s>
<s id="d1p2s4">The Temple of Hung Kings is there in Phu Tho being the ancestor worship place of the whole Vietnamese nation, the spot where the national strength and determination of great unity is seen and felt.</s>
<s id="d1p2s5">Well preserved in Phu Tho are thousands of historic-cultural relics, hundreds of folk festivals and folk music like Xoan and Gheo singing - traditional classical singings.</s>
<s id="d1p2s6">They are the national precious cultural relics manifesting the original identity and unique human tourism resources attracting tourists.</s>
</p>
<p id="d1p3">
<s id="d1p3s1">Phu Tho is also famous for well-know tourist attractions including the historic complex of Hung Kings’ Temple, Viet Tri-the city of festivals, Thanh Thuy hot mineral water site, Xuan Son National Park.</s>
<s id="d1p3s2">For the past years, the improvement in its tourism infrastructure with 1800 standard hotel rooms, luxurious transport means for tourists has attracted more than 3 million visits per year.</s>
<s id="d1p3s3">To provide information for managers, investors, tourism companies as well as inland and foreign visitors, Phu Tho’s Department of Culture, Sports and Tourism compiles Phu Tho Guidebook.</s>
<s id="d1p3s4">This will give tourism companies and tourists accurate and adequate information to plan the visits to Phu Tho easily and conveniently.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d2">
<head>Historic Relic Complex and Festivals at Hung Kings’ Temple</head>
<p id="d2p1">
<s id="d2p1s1">Hung Kings’ Temple is situated in Co Tich village, Hy Cuong commune, Viet Tri city Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d2p1s2">It is an architectural system dedicated to worship Hung Kings.</s>
<s id="d2p1s3">It is both a beauty spot and Vietnam’s important historic-cultural relic.</s>
<s id="d2p1s4">The temples are located on Nghia Linh Mountain at the elevation of 175m.</s>
<s id="d2p1s5">Looking from a long distance, Nghia Linh Mountain is like a dragon’s head toward The South.</s>
<s id="d2p1s6">The landscape is marvelous and impressive; the land is full supernatural power with the gathering of mountains and rivers.</s>
<s id="d2p1s7">Hung Temple relic complex has the following constructions:</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p2">
<s id="d2p2s1">Temple Gate: Built in the second reigning year of Khai Dinh (1917), the Gate is 8.5 meters high and 45 meters high and 45 meter wide, 8-small-vault shaped.</s>
<s id="d2p2s2">Its two sides are embossed with two boxers.</s>
<s id="d2p2s3">One is holding a battle-axe while the other is holding a lance.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p3">
<s id="d2p3s1">Ha Temple: It is built in 17th century in the shape of Chinese character of “Er” (means “two”) with two buildings, each of them has 3 rooms.</s>
<s id="d2p3s2">According to the legend, in this temple Mother Au Co gave birth to a pouch containing 100 eggs, which hatched into 100 children.</s>
<s id="d2p3s3">This explains the meaning of the word compatriot in Vietnamese.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p4">
<s id="d2p4s1">Thien Quang Pagoda: Located on the right of Ha Temple, the construction mainly built of wooden pillars with stone chock.</s>
<s id="d2p4s2">The pagoda was built during the Ly and Tran Dynasty and then rebuilt in Le Dynasty from 1427 to 1573.</s>
<s id="d2p4s3">It worships Mahayana Buddha.</s>
<s id="d2p4s4">In front of the pagoda is an approximately 700 year old cycad.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p5">
<s id="d2p5s1">Trung Temple (Hung King Grandfathe temple): Trung Temple was built the earliest on Nghia Linh Mountain.</s>
<s id="d2p5s2">In 17th century, it was rebuilt in the style seen today.</s>
<s id="d2p5s3">According to the legend, it is the place where Hung Kings used to talk over state affairs and Hung King the sixth ceded the throne to his son Lang Lieu, who found how to make Trung (Square shaped) and Giay (Round shaped) cakes – sticky rice cakes.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p6">
<s id="d2p6s1">Thuong Temple (Kinh Thien Linh Castle): The temple was restored in the second reigning year of Khai Dinh (1917) in the shape of Chinese character of “Wang” (means “King’).</s>
<s id="d2p6s2">In the front there are 4 pillars with the carved decorations of “two dragons flanking a moon”.</s>
<s id="d2p6s3">This is also the place where Hung Kings used to hold God of Heaven and Earth worshipping rituals to prayer for good weather, bumper crops, enough food and happiness for the people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p7">
<s id="d2p7s1">On the right of the front of Thuong Temple, there is a vowing stone pillar built by An Duong Vuong.</s>
<s id="d2p7s2">After being ceded the thrown by the 18th Hung King, An Duong Vuong constructed this pillar and vowed that “I’ll defend the nation forever”.</s>
<s id="d2p7s3">This is the place dedicated to worship Thanh Giong who defeated An invaders.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p8">
<s id="d2p8s1">Hung King's Tombs: The tomb is located on the left of the front of Thuong Temple.</s>
<s id="d2p8s2">The tomb is cuboid-shaped the pillars are integrated into the walls, and eight roofs have curved lances.</s>
<s id="d2p8s3">Inside the tomb is a cuboid.</s>
<s id="d2p8s4">According to the legend this is the sixth Hung King’s grave.</s>
</p>
<p id="d2p9">
<s id="d2p9s1">Gieng Temple: Built in the 17th century at the foot of Southern Nghia Linh Mountain, it consists of 3 rows of rooms and 2 annexes at both sides.</s>
<s id="d2p9s2">In the temple, there is Ngoc Well where according to the legend two princesses Tien Dung and Ngoc Hoa used to see their images and brush their hair.</s>
<s id="d2p9s3">The well is so pure and never dry of water.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d3">
<head>Hung King’s temple festivals</head>
<p id="d3p1">
<s id="d3p1s1">Hung Kings’ Temple Festivals are the biggest in the country.</s>
<s id="d3p1s2">It lasts from the time after New Year to March in Lunar calendar.</s>
<s id="d3p1s3">The number of visitors to the Festival is the largest from lunar March, 1st to 10th.</s>
<s id="d3p1s4">Every year, there are about more than 3 million visitors coming to Hung King’s Temple to burn incense, visit Grandfather’s grave and enjoy the Festivals.</s>
<s id="d3p1s5">The lunar tenth of March is the Hung King Grandfather’s death anniversary that was recognized as the National anniversary according to the Government’s decree of 82/2001/NDCP issued on November 6th, 2001.</s>
<s id="d3p1s6">Hung Kings’ death anniversary is held with many solemn and formal rituals at Thuong Temple.</s>
<s id="d3p1s7">The thurification ceremony is organized at national level in even years and at provincial level in odd ones.</s>
</p>
<p id="d3p2">
<s id="d3p2s1">The people in the neighborhoods like Hung Lo; Chu Hoa and Son Vi commune, Lam Thao town, Hy Cuong Commune, etc  hold the ceremony of palanquin procession to Hung Kings’ Temple.</s>
<s id="d3p2s2">The festival has traditional games like: unicorn and Hon dancing, having a tug of war, performing of four classes: scholars, farmers, workers and merchants; cultural-art activities like folk song singing, Xoan and Gheo singing; contests of rice cooking, chung cake wrapping, and Giay cake grinding; sports games tike volley ball and wrestling...</s>
<s id="d3p2s3">Ten thousands of local people and visitors from everywhere participated in the festivals.</s>
<s id="d3p2s4">During the festival, the areas close to Hung Kings’ Temple also hold many cultural activities to increase the exciting atmosphere for Hung Kings' Temple Festivals.</s>
</p>
</div>
<head>Historic Relic complex and Festivals at Au Co Mother’s Temple.</head>
<div id="d4">
<head>Au Co Mother's Temple relics</head>
<p id="d4p1">
<s id="d4p1s1">Au Co Mother's Temple is located in Hien Luong commune, Ha Hoa district; Phu Tho province, it is 80 km away from Viet Tri city and 70 km away from Hanoi’s Trung Ha Bridge.</s>
<s id="d4p1s2">It was built in 1475 on a high hillock in a large plot of a field.</s>
<s id="d4p1s3">The temple lies under the shadow of a century-old banian tree, facing towards the South.</s>
<s id="d4p1s4">On the left is Loan well, on the right is Phuong well, in the front is a spectacular mountain like a writing desk, at the back is surrounded by snaking Red River, around is verdantly luxuriant trees.</s>
<s id="d4p1s5">The temple consists of 5 Dai Bai rooms and 3 harems.</s>
<s id="d4p1s6">It has wooden carved works with high value of sculpture art; precious antiques like Au Co statue, Due Ong statue, and royal thrown, carved altar.</s>
<s id="d4p1s7">This is the place dedicated to worship The Nations Mother that is very important the system of Phu Tho’s historic relics.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d5">
<head>Au Co Mother’s Temple Festivals</head>
<p id="d5p1">
<s id="d5p1s1">The festival is officially held on the yearly lunar 7th of January.</s>
<s id="d5p1s2">Besides, there are some festivals on other days like the lunar 10th and 11th of February, 12th of March, 13th of August and 25th of December that is the day when "Fairies fly back to the heaven" Beginning the festivals is the worshipping ceremony dedicated to the Village's God, followed by the ceremony at The National Mother’s Temple from about 7 to 9 am.</s>
<s id="d5p1s3">When the procession has arrived at the yard of the Temple, the ceremony at Au Co Mother’s Temple is carried out.</s>
<s id="d5p1s4">Firstly, they hold the ceremony of thurification and offerings (including 100 kilos of cakes, 100 Pham Oan - steamed glutinous rice molded into a truncated cone, fruits and flowers).</s>
<s id="d5p1s5">After that the thurifier team of female mandarin including 12 young virgins conduct the Mother ceremony according to the traditional customs.</s>
<s id="d5p1s6">After the ceremonies, local people and visitors from everywhere come into Mothers temple to offer flowers and incense.</s>
<s id="d5p1s7">In the temple yard taking place traditional games like swinging, human chess, cock fighting, To Tom-card game using a deck of 120 cards and played by five persons, cultural activities performances, and countryside markets.</s>
<s id="d5p1s8">These add to the exciting atmosphere of the festival.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d6">
<head>Ho Chi Minh’s Historic relic site</head>
<p id="d6p1">
<s id="d6p1s1">The relic site is located in Co Tiet commune, Tam Nong distried, Phu Tho Province 6km away from Tam Nong District.</s>
<s id="d6p1s2">It was recognized as the national relic according to 65/QD-BT decree issued on the 16th of January, 1995 by the Minister of Culture and Information.</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p2">
<s id="d6p2s1">This is Mr.Hoang Van Nguyen house in Go village where Ho Chi Minh President worked from the early morning on March 4th 1947 to March 18th 1947.</s>
<s id="d6p2s2">Here he:</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p3">
<s id="d6p3s1">Wrote the letter to the whole nations fellow citizens on 05/03/1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s2">Wrote the letter to the people in the rear on 05/03/ 1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s3">Wrote the letter to French Parliament and People on 05/03/1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s4">Wrote the letter to priest La Huu Tu diocesan on 10/3/1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s5">Gave the answer to the interview about the declare of France’s Prime Minister Ramandie on 9/3/1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s6">Signed of298 Decree to clarify the foreign trade procedures and the establishment of Foreign Trade Department on 14/3/1947</s>
<s id="d6p3s7">Composed the book "New life" with the pen name of Tan Binh</s>
</p>
<p id="d6p4">
<s id="d6p4s1">In this house, he also read Tran Hung Dao’s book on warfare (Tran Hung Dao is a very talented and famous General of Vietnam in Tran Dynasty) and Ton Tu’s book on leading military force.</s>
<s id="d6p4s2">In the evening of 18/3/1947, he moved from Co Tiet to Chu Hoa, Lam Thao Province to continue with Vietnam's long-term resistance war.</s>
<s id="d6p4s3">To confirm the purpose of Vietnam’s Revolution he named his guards and assistants “Truong-Ky-Khang-Chien-Nhat-Dinh-Thang-Loi” - each person’s name is one component in the expressions meant “Long-term Resistance War definitely ends with our victory”.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d7">
<head>Xuan Son National Park</head>
<p id="d7p1">
<s id="d7p1s1">Xuan Son National Park is situated in Tan Son District, Phu Tho Province.</s>
<s id="d7p1s2">It is 33,687 hectares in total with the main part is 15,048 hectares and the bordering part covers 18.639 hectares.</s>
<s id="d7p1s3">It has the preserved biodiversity system.</s>
<s id="d7p1s4">According to the statistics, it has 1217 species of plants with 665 species of herbs, 300 species of edible plants, and vascular plants like oak, teak, and parashrea stellata.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p2">
<s id="d7p2s1">Xuan Son stellata forest is evaluated as one of three national Parks with the highest biodiversity level in Vietnam, it has many hundreds year old trees with 2m in diameter and 30m in height.</s>
<s id="d7p2s2">It has 365 species of animals with 46 species recorded in Vietnam's book of endangered species and 18 species recorded in the World's book of endangered species.</s>
<s id="d7p2s3">It also has Paramesotriton deloustali, very rare and valuable species.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p3">
<s id="d7p3s1">Xuan Son has three mounts above 1000m including Voi,Ten and Can Mount.</s>
<s id="d7p3s2">Its system of limestone caves is very diversified with many beautiful stalactites and stone pillars.</s>
<s id="d7p3s3">More than 30 caves of different sizes have been discovered like Lun, Lang, Na, Thien Nga caves or Doi (bats), Son Duong (cham ois), Chon Trang (ermines), Trang Tron (full moon), etc.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p4">
<s id="d7p4s1">Lang is the biggest cave and longest deepened into Ten mountain, its arch is 20m tall at some points and 20m wide.</s>
<s id="d7p4s2">The system of waterfalls are constituted by very beautiful streams flowing down from the mountains including the waterfalls of Xoan, Kem - 99 levels, To Brothers, Nuoc Moc.</s>
</p>
<p id="d7p5">
<s id="d7p5s1">In the National Park, people of ethnic groups including Muong and Dao residing in Lang, Du, Lap Thang, Xoan, Ong can still maintain the customs and traditions with festivals, unique dancing and singing.</s>
<s id="d7p5s1">Xuan Son is a huge and spectacular natural landscape, an attracted destination to tourists.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d8">
<head>Thanh Thuy Hot mineral water mine</head>
<p id="d8p1">
<s id="d8p1s1">Thanh Thuy Hot mineral water mine is located in La Phu and Bao Yen Commune, Thanh thuy district, Phu Tho Province, 40 kilometers away from Viet Tri city next to the expanded area of Hanoi.</s>
<s id="d8p1s2">It lies along Da River with the area of 300 ha.</s>
<s id="d8p1s3">Hot mineral water is at the depth of from 30 to 60 m, its heat ranges from 37 to 54 Celsius degrees.</s>
<s id="d8p1s4">The water has valuable elements especially Radon radiant that is good for the medical treatment and health recovery.</s>
<s id="d8p1s5">This is found in Vietnam for the first time It capacity is enough to supply visitors for long time with the 2100m3 /per day.</s>
<s id="d8p1s6">Phu tho has programmed Thanh Thuy tourism hot spring site with the projects of building the sites of healthcare and health recovery entertainment, conference...Now on holidays there are thousands of visitors to bathe in the site every day.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d9">
<head>God Pond - Fairy Stream</head>
<p id="d9p1">
<s id="d9p1s1">Ao Gioi Suoi Tien (God Pond - Fairy Stream) is located in Quan Khe commune, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d9p1s2">Suoi Tien originates from Na Mountain at the height of 1000m.</s>
<s id="d9p1s3">Flowing from the height, it makes a picturesque waterfall.</s>
<s id="d9p1s4">It pours down into the area of deep, clean water or pebbles and colorful cobbles to make mysterious beauty.</s>
<s id="d9p1s5">Now there are about 10 big and small waterfalls with the specific characteristics of height, falling down point.</s>
<s id="d9p1s6">The surrounding spots have been given very beautiful names like God Pond, Buddha Well, Green Chasm, Bottomless Cavern, Cloud waterfall, Fairy Cave, Wind waterfall, Pearl Lake.</s>
<s id="d9p1s7">Surrounding the stream are pebble field and blocks of marble with various shapes.</s>
<s id="d9p1s8">They are given special names like Elephant-on-its-knee pedestals, Tiger-lying-in- wait pedestals, God gate, Fairy wing.</s>
<s id="d9p1s9">Ao Gioi Suoi Tien is about 10km away from Au Co Mothers Temple and 3km away from Van Hoi lagoon.</s>
<s id="d9p1s10">It is an ideal destination for visitors who like beholding natural beauty spots after visiting and burning incense atAu Co Mother’s Temple.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d10">
<head>Ao Chau Lagoon</head>
<p id="d10p1">
<s id="d10p1s1">Located in Am Thuong and Yen Son Commune, Ha Hoa District, it covers water square of 300ha.</s>
<s id="d10p1s2">Ao Chau outstands in an area of midland and hills.</s>
<s id="d10p1s3">It has 99 arms deepening into a large area of hills of more than 1500 ha.</s>
<s id="d10p1s4">The water in the lagoon is always pure, blue and clean.</s>
<s id="d10p1s5">Its average depth is from 8 to 10 meters and the deepest point is 15 meters.</s>
<s id="d10p1s6">The hills emerging in the middle of the big lagoon are grown with local trees like tea plants, palm-trees and especially hills of red ripe litchi in summer.</s>
<s id="d10p1s7">They create a great painting of mountains and rivers.</s>
<s id="d10p1s8">The mountainous and hilly areas surrounding the lagoon have luxuriant plants that make poetic scenery.</s>
<s id="d10p1s9">Ao Chau lagoon has been programmed to b built into an ecotourism site with luxurious hotels, healthcare sites and entertainment resort with many games like sailing in the lagoon.</s>
<s id="d10p1s10">The lagoon is 70 km away from Viet Tri and tourists can have an enjoyable and interesting time here.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d11">
<head>Van Hoi Lagoon</head>
<p id="d11p1">
<s id="d11p1s1">Located in Hien Luong Commune, Ha Hoa District, Phu Tho Province, the lagoon lies next to Van Hoi and Viet Cuong commune, Tran Yen District, Yen Bai Province.</s>
<s id="d11p1s2">The lagoon has a water surface of more than 200 ha, the depth of from 7 to 8 m, the deepest point of 20m.</s>
<s id="d11p1s3">It has the system of water open supply and drainage so it can always maintain a stable water level.</s>
<s id="d11p1s4">The difference between the rainy and dry season is only 1.3 m.</s>
<s id="d11p1s5">The water in the lagoon is very clean and pure.</s>
<s id="d11p1s6">Surrounding it is the system of mountains hills and forests of Quan Khe, Ha Hoa district Phu Tho; Van Hoi and Viet Cuong commune,Tran Yen District Yen Bai Province.</s>
<s id="d11p1s7">This creates a poetic landscape.</s>
<s id="d11p1s8">On the lagoon surface are 40 islands, the biggest one is 10ha.</s>
<s id="d11p1s9">The rest are small ones ranging from 0.5 to 1 ha with some plant species like palm, tea trees, making a beautiful painting.</s>
</p>
<p id="d11p2">
<s id="d11p2s1">The of across - Asia highway of Hai Phong - Hanoi - Kunming (China) crosses is 700m away from the lagoon exit.</s>
<s id="d11p2s2">The distance between Viet Tri to Van Hoi lagoon is about 80 km that takes 2 hours by car.</s>
<s id="d11p2s3">The lagoon is 1 km away from Mother's Temple (Ha Hoa), 3 km from Ao Gioi Suoi Tien.</s>
<s id="d11p2s4">It has been programmed into a high quality health tourism site.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d12">
<head>Cu Thang Waterfall</head>
<p id="d12p1">
<s id="d12p1s1">The waterfall of Cu Thang in Cu Thang Commune, Thanh Son District, Phu Tho provice is about 18 km away from Vang Town of Thanh Son district.</s>
<s id="d12p1s2">It is 10 m high cascading all year round from a stream full of water down to a huge plunge pool with limpid water.</s>
<s id="d12p1s3">The area around the cascade and along the stream running from the plunge pool is covered with luxuriant vegetation and pebble plains, forming magnificent scenery.</s>
<s id="d12p1s4">Cu Thang Waterfall presents itself as an ideal tourist destination to escape the heat of summer days.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d13">
<head>Bach Hac Confluence(White Crane Confluence)</head>
<p id="d13p1">
<s id="d13p1s1">Bach Hac or White Crane is a name that has long been used.</s>
<s id="d13p1s2">It is written in Linh Nam Chich Quai (a Collection of Strange Stories in Linh Nam) that: "there was in the ancient Phong Chau a big wide shade tree called Chien Dan on which white cranes built their nests, thus this area is named Bach Hac or White Crane": The region of Bach Hac Confluence is where three big rivers namely Thao, Da and Lo meet each other.</s>
<s id="d13p1s3">Located in a convenient position, Bach Hac was a great place of residence for the ancient Vietnamese people, since it had mountains, hills and plains.</s>
<s id="d13p1s4">When the area was flooded,they moved to hills and mountains to make a living there and if the weather was good, they spead to the plains to cultivate rice.</s>
<s id="d13p1s5">Moreover, this area was chosen by Hung Kings for the establishment and construction of Van Lang State.</s>
<s id="d13p1s6">On this area still exist various legends of the time when Hung Kings founded Van Lang state such as the story of Heaven God (whose heel is still seen engraved on a stone on the edge of Bach Hac river) giving names to 100 children of Lac Long Quan, the legends of the fight between Son Tinh and Thuy Tinh, and of two brothers named Tho Lenh and Thach Khanh.</s>
<s id="d13p1s7">Bach Hac is also a place of various historical and cultural relics such as Tam Giang Pagoda, Bach Hac Communal House, Lang Dai Temple, Ha Than Shrine.</s>
<s id="d13p1s8">Coming to Bach Hac, visitors can have a chance to enjoy a number of important festivals and events such as Bach Hac Regetta Festival, Glutinuous Rice Dumpling Contest, Wrestling Competition, etc.</s>
<s id="d13p1s9">The name of each commune and village in Bach Hac is associated with one legend of Hung Kings time.</s>
<s id="d13p1s10">The land of Bach Hac Confluence has long been well-known for its charming waterways and liveliness.</s>
<s id="d13p1s11">In the afternoon, the flaming sun sets down to Ba Vi Range amid the happy folksongs sung by fishermen who are catching fish in the river.</s>
<s id="d13p1s12">All these make Bach Hac a land of picturesque landscapes with its unique and distinct tangible and intangible cultural heritages an appealing point of arrival for visitors who come here to be fully satisfied.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d14">
<head>Midland Palm Forest</head>
<p id="d14p1">
<s id="d14p1s1">Hills in the midland of Phu Tho, that look like close up-side-down bowls occupying thousands of hectares of land are all covered with palm trees, providing a picturesque and appealing landscape.</s>
<s id="d14p1s2">Lying under the shade of palm trees in summer breathing in the fragrance brought over by the wind, visitors could find no experience like this which is very stress-releasing and comfortable.</s>
<s id="d14p1s3">Anyone coming here would be impressed to look at the palm trees waving their canopies, which from a distance looks like a fearless army brandishing their swords to defend their beloved nation.</s>
<s id="d14p1s4">Like bamboos, palm trees have long been associated with the lives of agriculture-based Vietnamese people since the first days of their history.</s>
<s id="d14p1s5">Cottages with palm-leaf roof, conical peaked hats and raincoats made from the leaves of palm trees have long protected generations of Vietnamese people from hard weather conditions.</s>
<s id="d14p1s6">At present, Phu Tho provides major source of this material for the production of handicrafts and, more importantly is an ideal destination for those who come here on eco-tours, for relaxation and entertainment.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d15">
<head>Midland Tea Hills</head>
<p id="d15p1">
<s id="d15p1s1">Phu Tho has long been famous for its tea planting farms covering over 12,000 hectares of hill area and produces up to 150,000 tones of fresh tender tea a year.</s>
<s id="d15p1s2">The province each year exports 10,000 tones of dried tender tea.</s>
<s id="d15p1s3">Those who have been to Phu Tho’s midland areas of Doan Hung, Thanh Ba, Ha Hoa, Cam Khe, Phu Ninh, etc. would never forget their green tea hills which look like layers of glutinous rice trays, featuring magnificent natural landscape.</s>
<s id="d15p1s4">Midland girls are very skillful in picking tender tea leaves smiling happily and singing folksongs, which reflects the tranquil life of a rural area.</s>
<s id="d15p1s5">It would be great to take sips of strong green tea which is a little bit bitter at first, but then leave a long lasting sweet after taste.</s>
<s id="d15p1s6">It is difficult to tell the feeling of drinking the tea from the teapot of weather-beaten farmers in the tea area who will tell us many stories about the tea tree and legends of the national building era.</s>
<s id="d15p1s7">It would also be very wonderful to enjoy a bowl of green tea by the elderly here avoiding the extreme heat of summer days.</s>
<s id="d15p1s8">The picturesque scenery of tea hills, famers' happiness and optimism in labour together the tea culture of Phu Tho have made the province a right place to go on eco-tours with various and exciting local cultural identities.</s>
</p>
</div>
<head>Festival, historic-Culture relics, and archaeological sites</head>
<div id="d16">
<head>Bach Hac Regatta Festival</head>
<p id="d16p1">
<s id="d16p1s1">Place: Bach Hac Ward - Viet Tri city.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p2">
<s id="d16p2s1">Time: 10th day of the third lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p3">
<s id="d16p3s1">This festival is held on the river in commemoration of Bach Hac’s God of Soil ( God Tho Lenh), who saw off Saint Tan Vien when the latter visited Bach Hac.</s>
<s id="d16p3s2">Participating in the event are 4 giap (male teams) namely Thien Hac, Dong Nam, Than True and Bo Dau.</s>
<s id="d16p3s3">Each giap owns a boat painted differently: Thien Hac’s blue, Than True’s red, Dong Nam’s white and Bo Dau’s yellow.</s>
<s id="d16p3s4">Clothing, flags and oars must be of the same color with the boat.</s>
<s id="d16p3s5">Each boat is rowed by 50 boatmen with a steering man, a flag bearer and a person who is in charge of beating a mo (a musical instrument made of wood in the shape of a bell) to conduct the boatmen.</s>
<s id="d16p3s6">Boats sail from the gate of the Bach Hac Communal House to Bach Hac Confluence.</s>
<s id="d16p3s7">Afterwards, they are rowed backward to their starting point.</s>
<s id="d16p3s8">On the way back, all boatmen stop at Chi Cat Temple.</s>
<s id="d16p3s9">Tien Cat village - a place for worshipping Thach Khanh - to practice ceremonial rituals.</s>
</p>
<p id="d16p4">
<s id="d16p4s1">When the first regatta reaches the finish line, a great and constant cheer goes up from the crowd of spectators.</s>
<s id="d16p4s2">The festival together with the relics of Tam Giang Pagoda and Temple and beautiful landscape of Bach Hac Confluence has attracted thousands of local and foreign tourists.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d17">
<head>Hien Quan Phet Festival</head>
<p id="d17p1">
<s id="d17p1s1">Place: Hlen Quan Commune,Tam Nong District, Phu Tho Province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p2">
<s id="d17p2s1">Time: 12th and 13th days of the first lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d17p3">
<s id="d17p3s1">The first day of the festival is called festival announcing day (ngay cao hoi).</s>
<s id="d17p3s2">In the morning of the day, ceremonial procession of altar and palanquin on which there are a throne and phet balls is led from Madam Thieu Hoa Temple to the communal house.</s>
<s id="d17p3s3">After the rituals comes the ceremony called troop reviewing ceremony.</s>
<s id="d17p3s4">The main festival day is on the 13th when people lead the procession of altar and palanquin to the communal house and hold incense-burning ceremony and other rituals there.</s>
<s id="d17p3s5">In the afternoon, the game of Phet which is the most festive part of the day is held.</s>
<s id="d17p3s6">Males in village are divided into two teams.</s>
<s id="d17p3s7">Each team is comprised of 50 to 60 members who are half naked in long pants tied to a red belt holding a stick curved at one end.</s>
<s id="d17p3s8">After the rituals at the altar, several elderly persons holding flags crossed over their heads review the two lines of players who hold up the phet sticks to make the letter A, then they are directed to the playing ground.</s>
<s id="d17p3s9">In the middle of the ground, there is a master of ceremony who stands next to a phet hole and reads phet recitals.</s>
<s id="d17p3s10">Then, he throws the phet ball into the hole.</s>
<s id="d17p3s11">Next, the two persons from two teams stamp on the two sides of the hole ten times, then use the stick to pull out the ball.</s>
<s id="d17p3s12">The teams immediately charge each other fiercely.</s>
<s id="d17p3s13">If anyone snatches the phet ball, hundreds of people chase him for the bail.</s>
<s id="d17p3s14">The match is temporarily finished when one person takes the ball and goes beyond the boundary which is made of New Year’s tree hedge.</s>
<s id="d17p3s15">The second and third phet balls are then brought to the hole and the same ritual repeat.</s>
<s id="d17p3s16">There would be no prize for the winners.</s>
<s id="d17p3s17">However, players believe that they would have a profitable and lucky year if they win in a game.</s>
<s id="d17p3s18">After three matches of phet playing, the master of ceremony makes rituals of processing the three phet balls placed on a tray at the altar.</s>
<s id="d17p3s19">Then, he carries the balls to the main festival area and throw the balls to three different directions flow of the river.</s>
<s id="d17p3s20">Once again, hundreds of people jump up trying to catch the ball, as they believe that if they get the balls, they would be lucky all year around.</s>
<s id="d17p3s21">At the end of the festival, villagers are in a procession of palanquin back from the communal house to the Thieu Hoa Temple.</s>
<s id="d17p3s22">Leaving the festival, everyone gets home in good mood.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d18">
<head>Mr and Mrs.Khiu Procession Festival</head>
<p id="d18p1">
<s id="d18p1s1">Place: Thanh Dinh Commune, Viet Tri City.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p2">
<s id="d18p2s1">Time: 4th of the first lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p3">
<s id="d18p3s1">Mr. and Mrs.Khiu Procession Festival is called a Crop Praying Festival.</s>
<s id="d18p3s2">Offerings include a chung cake (square cake) of 40 cm think, a branch of in-blossom peach, a sheaf of glutinous rice and a sheaf of non-glutinous rice which are placed evenly around a tray full of corns, beans, peanuts and sesames.</s>
<s id="d18p3s3">The palanquin is decorated with flowers of reed.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p4">
<s id="d18p4s1">Playing the part of Mr.Khiu is a man between ages of 60 and 65.</s>
<s id="d18p4s2">This man, whose wife is still alive and children are both boys and girls, should be perfectly healthy.</s>
<s id="d18p4s3">He puts on blue ceremonial clothing with white pants, hats and mandarin's boots.</s>
</p>
<p id="d18p5">
<s id="d18p5s1">Mrs.Khiu is also played by a young strong full-parent man of around 12 and 17.</s>
<s id="d18p5s2">This man wears the four-panel traditional dress with a black skirt, a conical hat, a wooden clog and a small flowery bag carrying 9 small phoenix-shaped betel leaves and 9 areca-nuts.</s>
<s id="d18p5s3">The festival begins with a palanquin procession of Mr.and Mrs.Khiu from the communal house to an area called Oa Nha Nit (woman’s genital organ in the other name).</s>
<s id="d18p5s4">In Oa Nha Nit, Mr.Khiu uses a square sticky rice cake symbolizing men’s genital organ to pound at the center area for three times.</s>
<s id="d18p5s5">Mr. and Mrs.Khiu are carried back to the communal house after all rituals are done.</s>
<s id="d18p5s6">There, Mr. and Mrs.Khiu throw square sticky rice cakes and five-fruit trays at the crowd.</s>
<s id="d18p5s7">The more cakes people can grab, the more likelihood they have a son.</s>
<s id="d18p5s8">And the more cereal they grab, the better crops they will produce.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d19">
<head>Tro Tram Festival and Magic Rice Procession</head>
<p id="d19p1">
<s id="d19p1s1">Place: Tu Xa commune, Lam Thao district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p2">
<s id="d19p2s1">Time: the night of the 11th and the whole day of 12th of the first lunar month.</s>
<s id="d19p2s2">Tro Tram Festival is one of the traditional festivals organized by the ancient Vietnamese with the fertility belief and a hope for bumper crops.</s>
<s id="d19p2s3">Tro Tram Festival consists of three main parts:</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p3">
<s id="d19p3s1">Part one: The “Turning-off-the-light festival” takes place in the night-time of the 11h at Tro Shrine.</s>
<s id="d19p3s2">The officiating priest gives a son a wooden object and a girl a tortoise - shell - shaped object, which both represents the male and female sex organs.</s>
<s id="d19p3s3">On hearing the priest saying linh Tinh Tinh Phoc” - the magic words, they have to hold the things up high and then poke into each other.</s>
<s id="d19p3s4">This ritual is conducted three times.</s>
<s id="d19p3s5">Villagers believe that if in the darkness they could hit each other rightly then the year to come would be full of luck and prosperity.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p4">
<s id="d19p4s1">Part two: Magic Rice procession lasts for one hour between 8 and 9.00 am.</s>
<s id="d19p4s2">On the 12M of the first lunar month though in the previous evening, the incense-burner is brought from the shrine to the Tram Temple for sacrifices.</s>
<s id="d19p4s3">In the next morning, the magic rice procession is carried out along the way through village's fields and to Tro Shrine.</s>
</p>
<p id="d19p5">
<s id="d19p5s1">Part three: There come the performances of four classes: scholars, farmers, workers and merchants.</s>
<s id="d19p5s2">Main performers are local farmers, carpenters, fishermen, weavers, teachers...</s>
<s id="d19p5s3">Performances take place around the village and end in the yard of Tro Temple.</s>
<s id="d19p5s4">Tro Tram Festival reflects the wish and life of ancient Vietnamese residents along the sides of Red River.</s>
<s id="d19p5s5">It is known as one of the most ancient festivals that are still handed down until today.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d20">
<head>Tich Dien Festival (a festival commemorating the day Hung King taught villagers how to grow rice)</head>
<p id="d20p1">
<s id="d20p1s1">Place: Minh Nong commune, Viet Tri City, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p2">
<s id="d20p2s1">Time: 1st of the sixth lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p3">
<s id="d20p3s1">The festival is dated back to the early days of Hung King's making of the nation.</s>
<s id="d20p3s2">Legend has it that realizing that the land on the both sides of the Red River was very fertile and full of wild rice; Hung King asked villagers to build dikes and open ditches in order to keep water for these fields and harvested the wild rice.</s>
<s id="d20p3s3">Then he asked them to remove all wild rice and start to transplant rice seedlings.</s>
<s id="d20p3s4">Seeing that the villagers in Ma Lao Hill did not know how to plant rice, Hung King dismounted from his horse and performed all planting practices as a model for them.</s>
<s id="d20p3s5">Villagers then followed the instructions and worked diligently until noon.</s>
<s id="d20p3s6">Both the king and his subjects rested on the high mound of land in the middle of the field.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p4">
<s id="d20p4s1">Tich Dien praying area used to be built with laterite of 8 meters long, 7 meters wide and 1.3 meter high.</s>
<s id="d20p4s2">It was surrounded by hemps and rattans.</s>
<s id="d20p4s3">On the pedestal in the center of the altar there was a tiger-faced statue that is 1.2 meter long and 0.3 meter high.</s>
<s id="d20p4s4">Its pedestal was 1.2 meter in height,0.6 meter in length and 0.8 in width and characterized with an incense-burner surrounded by offerings.</s>
<s id="d20p4s5">The other area was grown with grass and had an area of two bed mattresses.</s>
</p>
<p id="d20p5">
<s id="d20p5s1">Offerings for Tich Dien Festival include steamed rice with chicken, betel, areca-nut, alcohol, water.</s>
<s id="d20p5s2">The sacrifice is conducted solemnly in a certain order praying for a favorable weather bumper crops and for a better life of people.</s>
<s id="d20p5s3">After all rituals are done, the officiating priest with a bunch of young paddy rice in his hands pulls up his pants, gets down to a field and transplants.</s>
<s id="d20p5s4">It is an activity that puts an end to the festival.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d21">
<head>Dao Xa Elephant Procession Festival</head>
<p id="d21p1">
<s id="d21p1s1">Place: Dao Xa commune, Thanh Thuy district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p2">
<s id="d21p2s1">Time: 27th, 28th and 29th of the first lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p3">
<s id="d21p3s1">The festival has another name as the festival of praying month.</s>
<s id="d21p3s2">According to legend, Hung King granted Hung Hai (the 19th son of Lac Long Quan) who had merit in founding the land of Tam Giang 2 elephants on seeing him off to Song Nhi in Hai Duong province for the new governance duty.</s>
<s id="d21p3s3">Before leaving the land,Hung Hai took his two elephants to Dao Xa to make offering sacrifices to the gods.</s>
<s id="d21p3s4">Not only Hung Hai but also the two elephants were so attached to Hung King that they did not want to go though they had to set off at the last minute.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p4">
<s id="d21p4s1">The festival begins on the morning of the 27th.</s>
<s id="d21p4s2">People prepare posters, flags, ceremonial decorations like swords, spears, umbrellas, etc. and offerings including three bunch of bananas, three bowls of troi (floating) cakes, three carps, rice wine.</s>
<s id="d21p4s3">They then conduct all rituals for the procession of ancestral tablet and incense-burner from Tam Cong Temple to the communal house.</s>
</p>
<p id="d21p5">
<s id="d21p5s1">In the afternoon of the 27th, elephant procession is performed.</s>
<s id="d21p5s2">On the 28lh morning, feast and offerings are supposed to be brought to the communal house and left there until the 29th.</s>
<s id="d21p5s3">Sacrifices will be conducted on the 28th together with interesting games namely elephant dancing, cooking competition, cock fighting, tugging.</s>
<s id="d21p5s4">The sculpture of two elephants is welcomed around the communal house.</s>
<s id="d21p5s5">The festival ends when the procession makes a complete round from the communal house to the temple.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d22">
<head>Dao Xa Temple Regatta Festival</head>
<p id="d22p1">
<s id="d22p1s1">Place: Dao Xa Commune, Thanh Thuy District, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p2">
<s id="d22p2s1">Time: the 10th of the seventh lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p3">
<s id="d22p3s1">Dao Xa Regatta Festival takes place on the large Dao Di Nau Lagoon.</s>
<s id="d22p3s2">The festival was originally dedicated to the three water-nymphs.</s>
<s id="d22p3s3">When General Ly Thuong Kiet stationed his troops in Dao Xa and trained his boatmen in preparation for the war against the Song there, the festival was expanded by 5 more days until the 15th of the sixth lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d22p4">
<s id="d22p4s1">There are two boats in each competition: white boat (called the female) and red boat (the male).</s>
<s id="d22p4s2">Each boat is 25 meter long and sailed by 24 boatmen.</s>
<s id="d22p4s3">The rule is very simple.</s>
<s id="d22p4s4">Each boat is supposed to row 3 rounds before flags and oars are raised.</s>
<s id="d22p4s5">Boatmen are supported and cheered by the crowd with shouts and beats of drums and gongs.</s>
<s id="d22p4s6">Dao Xa Regatta Festival is one of the festivals that beautify various features of Vietnam’s traditional culture.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d23">
<head>Princess Procession Festival</head>
<p id="d23p1">
<s id="d23p1s1">Place: Chu Hoa and Hy Cuong communes, Viet Tri City, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p2">
<s id="d23p2s1">Time: 7th and 8th of the first lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d23p3">
<s id="d23p3s1">Princess Procession Festival, or He Village Festival as the other name, depicts the legend of Saint Tan Vien bringing his bride, Ngoc Hoa princess, from Hung Temple to Tan Vien Mount.</s>
<s id="d23p3s2">Prior to the festival, Vi and Treo villages have to choose a young lady to play as the princess, who should be beautiful and charming.</s>
<s id="d23p3s3">She should also be single, between ages of 13 and 18, and is full parented with both brother and sister.</s>
<s id="d23p3s4">The procession is conducted formally according to traditional rites and customs.</s>
<s id="d23p3s5">The princess is welcomed from Dinh Ca to Treo village (Hy Cuong commune) and then to Tan Mount along the Red River.</s>
<s id="d23p3s6">During the procession, there are lots of performances to entertain Ngoc Hoa Princess, these are called “Humorous games’:</s>
<s id="d23p3s7">Wedding customs including challenging wedding presents, bringing the bride home and choosing the son-in-law in the time of Hung King is, therefore, reflected very lively and obviously through the festival.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d24">
<head>Day Cake (round sticky rice cake) Grinding Festival</head>
<p id="d24p1">
<s id="d24p1s1">Place: Truc Phe village, Hung Hoa town, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p2">
<s id="d24p2s1">Time: 7th of the first lunar month</s>
</p>
<p id="d24p3">
<s id="d24p3s1">Legend has it that the two sisters of Ho Thien Huong and Ho Thien, the two female generals under the kingship of Tan Vien, had the great merits in the war against the Shu and then the Qin.</s>
<s id="d24p3s2">To commemorate the two generals and especially their victory feast to their troops and the general Thien Huong's relief of Lord Dinh Cong Tuan, people in the village of Truc Phe hold the festival of Day cake grinding.</s>
<s id="d24p3s3">The grinding mortar is made of bamboo and is 1 meter wide.</s>
<s id="d24p3s4">It is stabilized by bamboo hem.</s>
<s id="d24p3s5">The pestle is made of timber or teakwood.</s>
<s id="d24p3s6">Sticky rice is chosen very carefully, and then cooked well before being grinded.</s>
<s id="d24p3s7">There are four people grinding at each mortar in which 2 people do the grinding and the other 2 do the shaping and cutting.</s>
<s id="d24p3s8">The grinding takes about 15 or 20 minutes.</s>
<s id="d24p3s9">Each cake is between 15 and 20 centimeters in diameter; 5 centimeters high.</s>
<s id="d24p3s10">Cakes are brought to True Phe Communal House for contemplating and mark giving.</s>
<s id="d24p3s11">The prized cake will be worshipped in the house and the winner is believed to be lucky in the year to come.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d25">
<head>The Gong Performance Festival of the Muong Ethnic People.</head>
<p id="d25p1">
<s id="d25p1s1">Place: Tat Thang Commune, Thanh Son District, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p2">
<s id="d25p2s1">Time: in the 1st lunar month.</s>
<s id="d25p2s2">Gongs are popular musical instruments in Muong’s festivals and holidays like the lunar New Year, village's festivals, wedding, funeral, etc.</s>
</p>
<p id="d25p3">
<s id="d25p3s1">The Gong is generally considered as a symbol of cultural features of Muong ethnic people.</s>
<s id="d25p3s2">It's not only a kind of musical instrument but an emblem of wealth and power.</s>
<s id="d25p3s3">Moreover, the gong is a valuable dowry that parents give to their daughter on her wedding day.</s>
<s id="d25p3s4">The musical instrument often has the diameter ranging from 20 to 60 centimeters.</s>
<s id="d25p3s5">A single set consists of 6 gongs; whist the double one consists of 12.</s>
<s id="d25p3s6">These are gongs that are arranged from small to big sizes.</s>
<s id="d25p3s7">They can be hand-held and hung on a frame when being performed.</s>
<s id="d25p3s8">Gong performances are carried out together with traditional songs such as: "Travelling" “Meeting for festivals”, "The colors of an amulet”, “Greeting”, “Toasting”.</s>
<s id="d25p3s9">Gongs are also performed with others instruments namely drums and sirens.</s>
<s id="d25p3s10">Playing gongs is considered to be highly artistic and the sound of gongs serves as background music for the singing and dancing of Muong ethnic people.</s>
<s id="d25p3s11">The Department of Phu Tho Culture, Sports and Tourism has, nowadays, been in charge of organizing Gong Performance Festivals.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d26">
<head>Xoan Singing</head>
<p id="d26p1">
<s id="d26p1s1">Xoan singing is a unique cultural product of Phu Tho.</s>
<s id="d26p1s2">The art of Xoan recital which is closely connected to the legend of Hung King dated to the early days of national building.</s>
<s id="d26p1s3">Khuc Mon Dinh (singing at the door of communal house) is known as another name of Xoan singing.</s>
<s id="d26p1s4">Performances take place in spring as an activity to welcome a new year.</s>
<s id="d26p1s5">The show is often organized in the communal house or village’s temple.</s>
<s id="d26p1s6">The show at communal houses of An Thai, Kim Duc, Phu Duc, Thet is on the first day of the lunar year.</s>
<s id="d26p1s7">From the 5th of lunar January, troupes from all the four villages have performing visits to the communal house of the village with whom they have sworn "brotherhood".</s>
<s id="d26p1s8">These teams perform from 5th of the first month till 10th of the third month in the lunar calendar.</s>
<s id="d26p1s9">A typical Xoan show must go through 3 well-established stages: ritual, dancing performance and festive singing.</s>
<s id="d26p1s10">In the ritual part, the singing involves the praise and praying performed in a ceremonial way at the communal house’s gate.</s>
<s id="d26p1s11">They are meant to show people’s feelings and serve as words of praise of saints and gods.</s>
<s id="d26p1s12">In the second part, performances reflect the life of people.</s>
<s id="d26p1s13">Therefore, the songs are often about the natural beauty or old stories.</s>
<s id="d26p1s14">Such a singing is comprised of 3 main parts: beginning, body and ending.</s>
<s id="d26p1s15">The last part is characterized with romantic performances of boys and girls singing back and forth.</s>
<s id="d26p1s16">Performers sing love songs accompanied with dances and games.</s>
<s id="d26p1s17">Xoan singing is not a mere singing practice, but known as a festival.</s>
<s id="d26p1s18">Xoan festival consists of various activities such as singing, asking for flowers, word-puzzle, dancing and many unique and interesting performances.</s>
<s id="d26p1s19">Words in Xoan songs are composed very carefully and full of art, using the both the quintessence of scholars and ordinaries.</s>
<s id="d26p1s20">Mo Ca; a rhythmical and attractive song about the love for labour; is the name of the last act in a Xoan recital.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d27">
<head>Gheo Singing (Loving singing)</head>
<p id="d27p1">
<s id="d27p1s1">Gheo singing is a kind of singing exchange between boys and girls, which is usually performed during the nights of spring and autumn festivals when the moon is bright.</s>
<s id="d27p1s2">Gheo singing takes place most in Phu Cuong and Nam Cuong villages in Thanh Uyen commune, Tam Nong district and Hung Nhi village in Hung Son commune, Thuc Luyen of Thanh Son district.</s>
<s id="d27p1s3">The name of Gheo singing differs in each area.</s>
<s id="d27p1s4">It is called as “Nuoc Nghia singing”, "Brothers and Sisters singing” in Nam Cuong and Thuc Nhi respectively.</s>
<s id="d27p1s5">It is named as ”Brothers and Sisters singing'' because in each performance boys and girls call each other not by their names but just brothers and sisters.</s>
<s id="d27p1s6">Gheo singing begins in any household rather than in the communal house, after the sacrifices finishes.</s>
<s id="d27p1s7">Gheo singing have nothing related to praying and offerings because it is not a traditional religious and free singing such as back-and-forth singing, folksong contest, but Quan Ho singing.</s>
<s id="d27p1s8">Gheo singing is performed in 2 forms: singing on the meeting bridge and singing contest.</s>
<s id="d27p1s9">In the first form, as a rule, one female elder and 12 women or girls will be selected to practice and perform the singing with another 12 men or boys invited and led by one male elder.</s>
<s id="d27p1s10">Gheo singing is performed in couples.</s>
<s id="d27p1s11">They look into each others eyes to express their feelings during the performance so that they can share the rhythm of the singing.</s>
</p>
<p id="d27p2">
<s id="d27p2s1">Singing contest is held not for prizes but to make the performances more interesting.</s>
<s id="d27p2s2">There are 2 types of contest: lyrics and voice.</s>
<s id="d27p2s3">In the lyrics contest, performers are asked to sing all well-known songs; they will lose if they fail to remember the lyrics.</s>
<s id="d27p2s4">In the voice contest, they will lose if they can’t follow different voices of this kind of singing.</s>
<s id="d27p2s5">Gheo singing often takes place from dark until the next morning.</s>
<s id="d27p2s6">After performing, performers of the village will see all the guests off.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d28">
<head>Hung Lo palanquin procession</head>
<p id="d28p1">
<s id="d28p1s1">Place: Hung Lo commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p2">
<s id="d28p2s1">Time: from 9th to 13th of the third lunar month.</s>
</p>
<p id="d28p3">
<s id="d28p3s1">The commencement of the festival is marked by the ceremony of chicken offerings at the communal house in the village on the 9th.</s>
<s id="d28p3s2">All the offered chickens are then brought to the oldest man’s house and are subject to distribution amongst the village notables and the elderly on the completion of the ceremony the villagers prepare the palanquin at the communal house and rally to start the palanquin procession into Hung Temple.</s>
<s id="d28p3s3">This palanquin procession appeals to a group ranging from 200 to 400 people in gala attire, embroidered with patterns of dragons, unicorn, turtles and flamingo, blue cone hats, leggings and shoes.</s>
<s id="d28p3s4">Standing out in the procession are four red-lacquered and gilded palanquins which have been elegantly and sophisticatedly carved.</s>
<s id="d28p3s5">The distance covered by the procession from Hung Lo to Hung Temple is as far as 9 kilometers.</s>
<s id="d28p3s6">Festival goers therefore take some breaks along the way with lion dancing.</s>
<s id="d28p3s7">At the T-junction named Hang, the whole procession groups would rest for one night before entering the temple on 10th of the month.</s>
<s id="d28p3s8">The formality and majesty of the procession, as matter of fact often create a center of attendance.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d29">
<head>Lang Suong Temple Festival</head>
<p id="d29p1">
<s id="d29p1s1">Place: Lang Suong temple, Trung Nghia commune, Thanh Thuy district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p2">
<s id="d29p2s1">Time: The festival is regularly held at on two annual occasions,i.e lunar January 15th and October 25th.</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p3">
<s id="d29p3s1">On lunar January 15th when it is Saint Tan Vien’s birthday palanquins are carried to the bank of Da River from Lang Suong temple.</s>
<s id="d29p3s2">By the river bank, the officiating priest standing in front of the praying table on which offering tray of fruits are laid; burns incense and heads towards Tan Mountain to invite the saint and his Godmother named Ma Thi to participate in the festival.</s>
<s id="d29p3s3">The palanquins are then carried back to the temple.</s>
<s id="d29p3s4">Festivities include folk games such as cock-fighting, wrestling; card games, con (a ball of clothes) throwing and singing contest.</s>
</p>
<p id="d29p4">
<s id="d29p4s1">The other festival held on lunar October 25th is to commemorate the Death of Mau (goddess mother) when villagers bring water from Da River to the Temple.</s>
<s id="d29p4s2">The lunar October 24th night is the time to pray for the Goddess.</s>
<s id="d29p4s3">On lunar October 25th, a palanquin procession is carried out, starting from Lang Suong temple to Da River with the significance of welcoming Tan God on his way back to his mom.</s>
<s id="d29p4s4">A cow offering (cow barbecue) takes place on this day.</s>
<s id="d29p4s5">Villagers then enjoy a variety of games like: earthenware pots breaking, ducks catching in the pool, swinging games, human chess, dum singing contest Boi singing (a form of traditional drama) is held at night right in front of the temple.</s>
<s id="d29p4s6">Lang Suong festival has become one of the most prominent ones in the series of festivals in the Tan Vien Mountain area with its beautiful sights and sounds.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d30">
<head>Dao Xa communal house</head>
<p id="d30p1">
<s id="d30p1s1">Built in Dao Xa commune, Thanh Thuy district, Dao Xa communal house is recognized as one of the national historical relics.</s>
<s id="d30p1s2">Built during the reign Due Nguyen (1674- 1675) of King Le Gia Tong, the communal house was designed in the shape of the Chinese letter of yi (meaning one), with 3- compartment halls and 2 annexes.</s>
<s id="d30p1s3">The communal house takes pride in 48 wooden pillars, the smallest of which has a diameter of 55 centimeters, while the cloister pillars have their sizes of about 40 centimeters in diameter.</s>
<s id="d30p1s4">The communal house measures 24 x 13.22 meters, making the overall area of 300 square meters.</s>
<s id="d30p1s5">In the main hall is the altar designed with dragons carvings, all at the height of 2 meters above the floor.</s>
<s id="d30p1s6">On top of it are four red lacquered and gilded windows, smoothly and sophisticatedly carved with images of four sacred animals and two dragons gazing at the moon.</s>
<s id="d30p1s7">Both sides of the altar are designed as the main praying area.</s>
<s id="d30p1s8">The house has 12 panels which were elegantly engraved.</s>
<s id="d30p1s9">On the roof of the building are the two dragons gazing at the moon, and each of the four corners is decorated with one lion’s whelp, while two sides of the roof was beautified with holy animals.</s>
<s id="d30p1s10">Dao Xa Communal House worships Hung Hai Cong (the 19th son of Lac Long Quan).</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d31">
<head>Hung Lo Communal House</head>
<p id="d31p1">
<s id="d31p1s1">Built in Hung Lo commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho provice Hung Lo Communal House is also called Xom Communal House.</s>
<s id="d31p1s2">It was constructed under the reign of King Le Hy Tong (1697).</s>
<s id="d31p1s3">The communal house is located next to the village temple, forming the shape of letter er (two) in Chinese.</s>
<s id="d31p1s4">Hung Lo Communal House is actually a complex comprising two smaller worshipping temples in the front and a main building at the back.</s>
<s id="d31p1s5">Between the two structures there is a dragon pavilion with the gong and drum chambers on both sides.</s>
<s id="d31p1s6">In detail, the front worshipping houses have 5 compartments and two annexes.</s>
<s id="d31p1s7">The main hall also has 5 wooden-floored compartments.</s>
<s id="d31p1s8">The ancient roofs stand out with high and bending corners.</s>
<s id="d31p1s9">Hung Lo Communal House is renowned for its impressive worshipping tools and marvelous carvings reflecting folk cultural values like the carvings of King Dinh Tien Hoang in his maneuver game with red flags or Burying in the dragon's set of teeth and Wrestling.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d32">
<head>Lau Thuong Communal House</head>
<p id="d32p1">
<s id="d32p1s1">Located in Lau Thuong village, Trung Vuong commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho provice Lau Thuong Communal House is a place of worship to four tutelary Gods namely: God of Tan Vien Mountain, two (Queen) Trung Sisters and Ly Hong Lien, who did her credits of teaching people how to read and write, how to cultivate mulberry and breed silkworm.</s>
<s id="d32p1s2">The communal house of Lau Thuong was constructed in the 17th century, designed in the shape of letter Ding in Chinese transcription.</s>
<s id="d32p1s3">The house was built in a large area including 5 compartments and two annexes of the front hall and 2 compartments of the apse, measuring 28 meters and 22 meters in width.</s>
<s id="d32p1s4">There exist 6 rows of wooden pillars, making a total of 60.</s>
<s id="d32p1s5">The diameters of a normal column and a small one are 0.75 meter and 0.56 meter respectively making the building one of the most meticulous ones in Phu Tho Province.</s>
<s id="d32p1s6">The house stills preserves 12 folk sculpture carvings, depicting the image of dragon “Quan Long Hoi Tu” (Dragons in festival), "Long Ly Quy Phuong” (four sacred animals: dragon-unicorn-tortoise-phoenix), "Luong Long chau nguyet” (Two dragons gazing at the moon).</s>
<s id="d32p1s7">The carving and intaglio techniques must have been of distinguished painstakingness and refinery.</s>
<s id="d32p1s8">Some ancient relics kept in Lau Thuong Communal House include the panel with big words, pairs of wooden panels on which are inscribed parallel sentences, 4 thrones, 4 trays and 5 ancient incense-burners made of terra-cotta.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d33">
<head>An Thai communal house</head>
<p id="d33p1">
<s id="d33p1s1">Sited in An Thai hamlet, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province, An Thai communal house is 10 kilometers from the city center towards the south east and 5 kilometers from Hung temple towards the north west.</s>
<s id="d33p1s2">Being constructed from the Hau Le’s dynasty, at the end of the 17th century and in the beginning of the 18th century, the house had once been restored from Nguyen dynasty.</s>
<s id="d33p1s3">The house performing religious services to Hung Kings was structured in the shape of the letter Yi (in Chinese alphabet), consisting of a hall, 2 compartments and 3 annexes.</s>
<s id="d33p1s4">The measurement is 18.4m in length and 13m in width.</s>
<s id="d33p1s5">The framework was like the bowels of a boat, following the rule of ancient architects, namely “thuong thu ha thach" (all supporting columns are bundled at the top, creating a stable structure).</s>
<s id="d33p1s6">The house has four rows of wooden pillars, which make up a total of 36 ones, including four major ones, 12 supporting and 20 cloisters’.</s>
<s id="d33p1s7">The four roofs create four intersectional angles, and bend upward in four tops.</s>
<s id="d33p1s8">The carvings inside were of great elegance, depicting “Dragon family” “Four sacred animals ".</s>
<s id="d33p1s9">The carving techniques in use are: intaglio or incise carvings and engraving typical of Hau Le dynasty An Thai communal house still presereves some ancient relics like: three thrones made in the eighteenth century, three pairs of wood panels, on which are inscribed parallel sentences, three hats of the Pacifying style, three incense burners and many other architectural, wooden sculptures of great value, Especially, An Thai has the traditional xoan festival.</s>
<s id="d33p1s10">The communal house was recognized as a national cultural heritage in 2006.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d34">
<head>Tam Giang Pagoda and Temple</head>
<p id="d34p1">
<s id="d34p1s1">The relics are in Bach Hac commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho Province.</s>
<s id="d34p1s2">The complex of pagoda and temple is located in a perfect site, by the river.</s>
<s id="d34p1s3">Tam Giang Temple was built to worship Tho Lenh and Thach Khanh, who had found valuable medical treatments.</s>
<s id="d34p1s4">On growing up, both men joined the army of Hung Due Vuong, fighting against the enemy, and they were assigned to be in charge of the navy.</s>
<s id="d34p1s5">After their death, they were honoured to be Bach Hac River Gods, who later helped Tran army (under the leadership of Lord Tran Nhat Duat) in the wars against the foreign invaders.</s>
<s id="d34p1s6">Tran Nhat Duat was later awarded with Bach Hac prefecture and his statue was carved and worshipped beside those of Lord Thanh Hac - Tho Lenh Dai Vuong.</s>
<s id="d34p1s7">Both the temple and pagoda have been restored and renovated with gilt pillars, beams and wood panels.</s>
<s id="d34p1s8">The architecture of the altar and statues are of significant artistic values.</s>
<s id="d34p1s9">A huge sculpture picture depicting the scenery of some pagodas in Vietnam add to the beauty of the site and its attraction.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d35">
<head>Hien Quan temple</head>
<p id="d35p1">
<s id="d35p1s1">The temple is positioned at Hien Quan commune, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d35p2">
<s id="d35p2s1">According to the legend; Hien Quan temple was built in early years, possibly the first years AD, and has gone under restoration several times.</s>
<s id="d35p2s2">Hien Quan temple is a place of worship to Thieu Hoa, a female general in Trung sisters' army who had made immense contribution to the struggle against To Dinh - the Chinese governor.</s>
<s id="d35p2s3">It is made up with two parts: the front worship hall and the apse.</s>
<s id="d35p2s4">In detail, the front worshipping chamber measures 12 meters x 4.3 meters, the major pillars is 2.8 meters high, with the diameter of 0.35 meter.</s>
<s id="d35p2s5">The main doorway measures 1.8 meters in height, 2.3 meters in width, and two side doors are 1.8 meters high and 0.9 meter wide.</s>
<s id="d35p2s6">The apse is 9.6 meters long, 4.6 meters wide, and the diameter of the column, on which the four sacred animals are carved, is also 0.35 meter.</s>
<s id="d35p2s7">The Communal House still stocks some valuable artifacts like palanquin which requires 8 people to carry on; poles, flags, phet sticks, phet balls and altar boards.</s>
<s id="d35p2s8">A prominent feature of the temple is traditional phet festival, an illuminating example of the national sportsmanship.</s>
<s id="d35p2s9">The shrine hall of Thieu Hoa is an addition to the main structure of the temple.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d36">
<head>Phuc Khanh pagoda</head>
<p id="d36p1">
<s id="d36p1s1">Phuc Khanh pagoda (or Hien Ouan pagoda) is situated in Hien Ouan commune, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p2">
<s id="d36p2s1">The time of construction of this pagoda has not been acknowledged, though, it went under restoration in 1964, 1978 and 1982.</s>
</p>
<p id="d36p3">
<s id="d36p3s1">The architecture of the pagoda follows the Noi cong ngoai quoc style; which means the inside area designed in the shape of the Chinese letter gong, and the outside border was designed like the shape of guo.</s>
<s id="d36p3s2">The house comprises a bell tower front worship hall, main praying hall, corridor and ancestors worship hall.</s>
<s id="d36p3s3">Built on a large area of land, the building was beautifully decorated with the sets of carvings: dragon- unicorn-tortoise-phoenix, apricot-lotus-chrysanthemum-ivory bamboo.</s>
<s id="d36p3s4">The pagoda worships Buddhas, with a wide range of ancient statues dating from the 17th century.</s>
<s id="d36p3s5">It also worships Thieu Hoa, a female general in Trung Sisters’ army.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d37">
<head>Hien Quan communal house</head>
<p id="d37p1">
<s id="d37p1s1">Being Sited in Hien Quan commune, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho Province.</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p2">
<s id="d37p2s1">the house is a place of worship to 4 heroes namely Son Thong, Thien Cuong, Hac Long, Ho Lan who had made great contribution to the war to protect the land and borders of Hung Kings against Thuc army.</s>
<s id="d37p2s2">The house has the shape of the Chinese letter ding and consists of two blocks: the Great Hall and the apse.</s>
<s id="d37p2s3">The present Great Hall was constructed in 1993 with 5 compartments, each has 3 doors.</s>
<s id="d37p2s4">The main doorway measures 2.7 meters in height, 3.3 meters in width while two side doors measure 2.1 meters in height and 1.6 meters in width.</s>
<s id="d37p2s5">Pairs of wood panels with letters Inscribed were hung above the doors.</s>
<s id="d37p2s6">The top roof of the house was adorned with two dragons gazing at the moon.</s>
<s id="d37p2s7">The 2-compartment apse has two annexes, with three rows of pillars, the main one of which measures 3.3 meters and the smaller ones are 2.9 meters high.</s>
<s id="d37p2s8">On the ceiling joists are other images of dragons serving the moon.</s>
<s id="d37p2s9">The house still keeps the set of high desks, measuring 2.2 meters.</s>
<s id="d37p2s10">The set comprises 3 layers, decorated with lotus, banyan leaves and gorgeous strings of Chrysanthemum, expressing the arts of Hau Le dynasty in the 18th century.</s>
</p>
<p id="d37p3">
<s id="d37p3s1">It can be said that the constructions of Hien Quan temple and pagoda together with Phet festival deserves to be an attractive tourist destination.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d38">
<head>Archaeological relics Phung Nguyen</head>
<p id="d38p1">
<s id="d38p1s1">Phung Nguyen is in Kinh Ke hamlet Lam Thao district, the relics was discovered in 1959.</s>
</p>
<p id="d38p2">
<s id="d38p2s1">Phung Nguyen culture; also called Phung Nguyen relics have marked the beginning of Dong Son culture, in the period right before Hung Kings.</s>
<s id="d38p2s2">The relics date from the prehistory of metalworking, about 3000 years ago.</s>
<s id="d38p2s3">A number of ancient relics have been excavated; the majority of them are stone tools, which have proven the skillful stone manipulation techniques.</s>
<s id="d38p2s4">These include stone tools, jewelries like bracelets, ear rings, and precious nephrite beads and long, thin stone sticks.</s>
<s id="d38p2s5">Besides, there are ceramic wares (patterns and flowered trays) together with lots of rice grains, presenting that their owners were employed in agriculture.</s>
<s id="d38p2s6">Phung Nguyen culture has inspired the blooming of Dong Don culture, and has also been a noteworthy scientific proof for the existence of a culture closely related to the arising of Van Lang State.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d39">
<head>Go Mun</head>
<p id="d39p1">
<s id="d39p1s1">Located in Tu Xa hamlet, Lam Thao district, Phu Tho provice, the relics sites was discovered 1961.</s>
<s id="d39p1s2">It was considered to be so typical that a culture was named after this relics.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p2">
<s id="d39p2s1">This archeological relic has been nationally recognized, and was excavated 1972.</s>
<s id="d39p2s2">The excavation results have proven that this used to be the habitat of Go Mun people, and the burial site of Dong Son people.</s>
<s id="d39p2s3">The relics found includes the track of cooking places, holes where posts had once been put, ceramics and bronze wares.</s>
<s id="d39p2s4">The relics also consist of household wares and bronze weapons: javelims, arrows, spears, axes and diverse chi naware like bowls, pots and jugs, jars, etc.</s>
</p>
<p id="d39p3">
<s id="d39p3s1">Go Mun relics are typical representation of Bronze Age in Vietnam.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d40">
<head>Lang Ca</head>
<p id="d40p1">
<s id="d40p1s1">Being situated in Lang Ca, Tho Son commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province, and had been discovered in 1959, the relics has been nationally recognized.</s>
</p>
<p id="d40p2">
<s id="d40p2s1">Archeological findings have revealed that this used to be the habitat, and then the burial site of old Viet people in Hung Kings' time.</s>
<s id="d40p2s2">The relics dated from the 2nd century BC to the 2nd century AD.</s>
<s id="d40p2s3">A number of 315 tombs have been discovered; relics comprise ‘Ancient Duong dynasty' (Chinese) ceramics, bronze labour tools, bronze moulds, and pouring pots.</s>
<s id="d40p2s4">The relic site have become significant in scientific and historic research on Van Lang capital under the reigns of Hung Kings.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d41">
<head>Go De</head>
<p id="d41p1">
<s id="d41p1s1">Situated in Thanh Dinh commune, Viet Tri city; Phu Tho province, the relic was first discovered in 1960 and called Thanh Dinh bronze relics, parts of Dong Son culture.</s>
<s id="d41p1s2">The relics were later excavated in 1994 and 2003, revealing the habitat and burial site of ancient Viet people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p2">
<s id="d41p2s1">The relics unearthed consists of stone tools, axes, graters and ear rings, together with ceramic wares like pots and jars..., animal fangs, and bronze weapons: battle axes, daggers, spears., and bronze tools, and wind instruments, drums, small bells and tintinnabulum.</s>
</p>
<p id="d41p3">
<s id="d41p3s1">Go De archaeological relics containing of diverse tools, conveying the development of ancient Viet indigenous civilizations of Van Lang State.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d42">
<head>Phu Tho Traditional craft village</head>
<p id="d42p1">
<s id="d42p1s1">Boasting a long history, Phu Tho is renowned as the cradle of Vietnam civilization; thus, Phu Tho people have been restoring and developing traditions and typical features of Vietnamese people.</s>
<s id="d42p1s2">The people here are famous for their creativeness, their perseverance in struggling, their kind-heartedness and artistic souls.</s>
<s id="d42p1s3">Craft villages of Phu Tho province are illuminating evidence for the observation.</s>
<s id="d42p1s4">Phu Tho's small industrial and handicrafts production have taken pride in their long history of development.</s>
<s id="d42p1s5">Perhaps, the traditional handicrafts are not highly efficient but these indigenous products create a considerably typical image for Phu Tho people.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d43">
<head>Bamboo charcoal craft village - Phu Lac com mune - Cam Khe district</head>
<p id="d43p1">
<s id="d43p1s1">Along the national highway numbered 32 by Hong riven tourists would arrive at Phu Lac, a mountainous village of Cam Khe district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
<s id="d43p1s2">It is a great chance to sink in a unique world of traditional bamboo charcoal handicrafts, ranging from sophisticated glasses, natural vases, and lovely coffee spoons to delicate blinds, and fragrant orchid baskets.</s>
<s id="d43p1s3">Bamboo charcoal with artistic beauty has become invaluable for filtering water and deodorizing, which are of great benefits for human health and the environment.</s>
</p>
<p id="d43p2">
<s id="d43p2s1">Bamboo charcoal products are of popularity among consumers in developed countries including Japan, South Korea, and China as they are capable of absorbing the harmful substance in the air and in water.</s>
<s id="d43p2s2">Bamboo charcoal is made from burning bamboo trees, with great care and lots of skills because the ending products may be burnt over into ash or otherwise into coal during a shorter period than required.</s>
<s id="d43p2s3">Temperature needs to be adjusted to harden and widen the surface of charcoal like iron.</s>
<s id="d43p2s4">However hard the job sounds, charcoal production of Phu Lac (Cam Khe) enjoys its prestige on the market share as a results of its superior quality.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d44">
<head>Do Xuyen Rattan and Bamboo Village</head>
<p id="d44p1">
<s id="d44p1s1">Although it is not as hectic as other traditional craft villages in Hong River delta region.</s>
<s id="d44p1s2">Do Xuyen has become a traditional craft village with unique products and its distinctive quietness.</s>
<s id="d44p1s3">The origin of the village’s bamboo weaving occupation is not acknowledged, though, one cannot deny that it has helped Do Xuyen people survive from a variety of flooding seasons and become an important part-time job for villagers.</s>
<s id="d44p1s4">The villages products are very simple and hardly needs any investment but skillful hands.</s>
<s id="d44p1s5">The low-profit production has to some certain extent presented the prestige villagers' culture and life in the competitiveness of market mechanism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p2">
<s id="d44p2s1">The major manufactured goods of Do Xuyen village is bamboo fiberboard for construction with various designs, meeting customers' needs: ceiling fiberboard, measuring 1 meter x 3 meters, or 1 meter x 4 meters, or bamboo containers of varied sizes and reasonable prices.</s>
<s id="d44p2s2">Do Xuyen can be named as a Bamboo mat village because its bamboo products are widely sold and have created financial resources for villagers.</s>
<s id="d44p2s3">Furthermore, another typical product is Mam Chap still in existence in spite of the market mechanism.</s>
</p>
<p id="d44p3">
<s id="d44p3s1">Nowadays, the occupation of chap bamboo production has witnessed great development up to now, thanks to the investment by Hon Ngoc Vien Dong Ltd., Company the products of Do Xuyen village including bamboo dishes, bowls, and chopsticks have been exported to foreign markets, which is of an immense support for Do Xuyen people to restore the traditional occupation and improve their life.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d45">
<head>Palm leaf conical Hat Making Profession</head>
<p id="d45p1">
<s id="d45p1s1">Being famous nationwide as the home of palm trees, Phu Tho has inevitably develops the conical hat occupation, which is of small-scale, though.</s>
<s id="d45p1s2">Unlike conical hats of Chuong village in Ha Tay province, Phu Tho conical hats’ most recognizable feature is their simplicity harmonious lines, durableness and reasonable price.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p2">
<s id="d45p2s1">A wide range of villages in Phu Tho are involved in hat production occupation; among them, there arise some prominent ones including Son Nga, Sai Nga, Thanh Nga, Dong Phu and Phu Khe.</s>
<s id="d45p2s2">The oldest craft village is Son Nga; however; its production of cone hats has now diminished as a result of their low cost-effectiveness.</s>
<s id="d45p2s3">Sai Nga is comparatively the biggest conical hat producers in the region in recent decades.</s>
<s id="d45p2s4">The village has become a large workshop bustling all day with manufacturing processes of leaf cutting, ironing, designing and hat sewing.</s>
</p>
<p id="d45p3">
<s id="d45p3s1">A good hat is defined as the one with beautiful and even sewing lines and smooth surface.</s>
<s id="d45p3s2">Interestingly the most beautiful one has a verse of romantic poem, or a picture placed in between two layers of thin leaves.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d46">
<head>Son Vy Teapot warm keeper</head>
<p id="d46p1">
<s id="d46p1s1">Have you ever stopped in a small shop in roadside to sip a cup of tea on a freezing winter day and noticed the use of a handicraft product of Viet Nam countryside to keep warm for the cup of tea?</s>
<s id="d46p1s2">It is U Am - traditional teapot warm keeper, which may be considered as the product only for nostalgic people.</s>
<s id="d46p1s3">In modern life, there are many electrical appliances but the teapot warm keeper have been conventionally used in many Vietnamese families and become a favorite souvenir for foreign tourists.</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p2">
<s id="d46p2s1">Son Vy a small village of Lam Thao district, Phu Tho province is native land of the unique product.</s>
<s id="d46p2s2">The occupation of producing teapot warm keepers has expanded in Son Vy Village for more than 100 years, despite of ups and downs in social development.</s>
<s id="d46p2s3">Villagers have skillfully and artistically created the teapot warm keeper with an exceptional design.</s>
<s id="d46p2s4">Each teapot warm keeper has turned out to be a familiar utensil of each family throughout the year.</s>
</p>
<p id="d46p3">
<s id="d46p3s1">Son Vy’teapot warm keeper was awarded silver medal in the National Handicrafts And Fine Arts Products Fair.</s>
<s id="d46p3s2">If more efforts are invested in improving its decoration and design, the cost effectiveness of Son Vy teapot warm keepers will be considerably increased, which are a considerable stimulation for the development of traditional craft village.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d47">
<head>Doan Ket food processing village</head>
<p id="d47p1">
<s id="d47p1s1">Doan Ket Hamlet of Hung Lo commune, Phu Ninh district has been well-known for processing vermicelli, rice noodle and rice sheets for hundreds of years.</s>
<s id="d47p1s2">The hamlet's products have established their brand name and won customers’ trust with their high quality.</s>
</p>
<p id="d47p2">
<s id="d47p2s1">For years, the craft village has been in humble and tenacious existence, surprising visitors with the bustling working environment of grinding workshops and many generations of Hung Lo people have grown up with the occupation.</s>
<s id="d47p2s2">Production of glass noodle and rice noodle hardly requires huge investment so any family can run the business.</s>
<s id="d47p2s3">Machinery has now replaced the manual manufacturing process, which was in use for decades.</s>
<s id="d47p2s4">A household can now produce 200-300 kilograms per day, helping Hung Lo commune to supply dozens of tons of dried foods such as vermicelli, noodle and rice paper and to market on a daily basis.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d48">
<head>Minh Duc Carpentry</head>
<p id="d48p1">
<s id="d48p1s1">Minh Duc Carpentry Village is located in Thanh Uyen commune of Tam Nong district, Phu Tho provice.</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p2">
<s id="d48p2s1">The foremost products of the village are commonly-known furniture of beds, cupboards, wardrobes.</s>
<s id="d48p2s2">Despite of their unpretentious appearance and design, the products have enjoyed popularity because of high quality which satisfy customers’ needs.</s>
<s id="d48p2s3">However; that does not necessarily mean Minh Duc carpentry is without typical splendor.</s>
<s id="d48p2s4">The origins of carpentry occupation in the village are not known, though; it has become the major of all villagers, earning an annual income of tens of billions of VNDs.</s>
</p>
<p id="d48p3">
<s id="d48p3s1">Minh Duc wooden products have widespread to every corner of the nation from rural to urban areas, though, not every user knows its origin.</s>
<s id="d48p3s2">Placing the trade mark on each product has been all villagers’ desire.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d49">
<head>Phu Tho Gastronomy</head>
<p id="d49p1">
<s id="d49p1s1">One interesting way to reach a new land and new culture is to enjoy foods there.</s>
<s id="d49p1s2">The idea is always right because gastronomy is cultural characteristics of each region.</s>
</p>
<p id="d49p2">
<s id="d49p2s1">Phu Tho, the ancestor’s land, will serve friends and guests from every corner of country with its special-but- popular dishes.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d50">
<head>Fish dishes</head>
<p id="d50p1">
<s id="d50p1s1">Lang: habitat living is wide, deep and strong current rivers.</s>
<s id="d50p1s2">The fishes live in the bed of the river and their food is small animals.</s>
<s id="d50p1s3">They only appear on the water surface when they are grown-up so fishermen can catch big fish of few kilos to dozens of kilos.</s>
<s id="d50p1s4">Lang fish is the best tasty catfish.</s>
</p>
<p id="d50p2">
<s id="d50p2s1">In the three rivers junction of Viet Tri, there is Anh Vu fish which is considered the rarest river fish.</s>
<s id="d50p2s2">Anh Vu fish also live in river bed eating mosses on stones.</s>
<s id="d50p2s3">They shelter in caves during the summer time and go out in autumn and winter seasons.</s>
<s id="d50p2s4">So Anh Vu fish can be caught only in chilled and misty days.</s>
<s id="d50p2s5">In the feudal period, Anh Vu fish were dedicated to kings only.</s>
<s id="d50p2s6">But now Anh Vu fish are so expensive that only star-classified hotels can afford.</s>
</p>
<p id="d50p3">
<s id="d50p3s1">Chay fish live in a section of Thao River of Thanh Ba district.</s>
<s id="d50p3s2">The fish has two delicious spawns.</s>
<s id="d50p3s3">Connoisseurs don’t hesitate to choose Chay fish for their meals.</s>
</p>
<p id="d50p4">
<s id="d50p4s1">In recent years, in Viet Tri city there have been some restaurants serving these fishes.</s>
<s id="d50p4s2">The most well-known and well- established one is Quan Ca Bo Song (Riverside Fish Restaurant) and following by Quan Ca Bach Hac (Bach Hac Fish Restaurant) and some others.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d51">
<head>Tai cake</head>
<p id="d51p1">
<s id="d51p1s1">In recent years, Banh Tai (Tai Cake), a special snack of Phu Tho town ship has regained its reputation.</s>
<s id="d51p1s2">Tai Cake is used in wedding and parties as substituting rice.</s>
<s id="d51p1s3">Tai Cake has been presented and become a nosh of people of Hanoi and many regions nationwide.</s>
<s id="d51p1s4">The cake cannot last longer than a day, therefore it requires great care.</s>
</p>
<p id="d51p2">
<s id="d50p2s1">Phu Tho Tai Cake has been made by Phu Tho village for long time and called Hon Cake.</s>
<s id="d50p2s2">The cake is shaped like an ear made from rice powder filled with pork.</s>
<s id="d50p2s3">In fact, the recipe and tools are not too complicated but not everyone can succeed.</s>
</p>
<p id="d51p3">
<s id="d51p3s1">Like in the old tome, choosing what rice for making cake is a decisive factor to the taste of the cake.</s>
<s id="d51p3s2">Rice must be soft and glutinous.</s>
<s id="d51p3s3">After being rinsed, rice is soaked into cold water for a period ranging from two hours to half of a day.</s>
<s id="d51p3s4">Then rice is ground into powder and made into pieces, which requires the cake makers to use his, or her strength to ensure absolute mixture After that, the powder pieces will be ground in a mortar, and modeled with hand (without any mould).</s>
<s id="d51p3s5">Skillful people can ensure cakes of same shape, like a thin ear, with pork in the middle.</s>
<s id="d51p3s6">In the next stage, cake are steamed for 30-60 minutes.</s>
<s id="d51p3s7">During the process, it is recommended not to make the powder curdle.</s>
</p>
<p id="d51p4">
<s id="d51p4s1">Tai Cake is the most delicious on being served hot.</s>
<s id="d51p4s2">Eating Tai Cake we cannot us spoon or folk but just by hands or a piece of banana leaf.</s>
<s id="d51p4s3">It is the best way you can enjoy the taste of cake completely.</s>
<s id="d51p4s4">It is well blended among glutinous, sweet taste and good smell.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d52">
<head>Dog Meat Viet Tri</head>
<p id="d52p1">
<s id="d52p1s1">Also being cooked into the 7 dishes like other regions, but Viet Tri Dog Meat has its own taste thanks to professional cooking.</s>
<s id="d52p1s2">Choosing the meat ingredient plays an important part, omitting the use of commercial fed dogs; dogs raised by mountainous minority people are favorable.</s>
<s id="d52p1s3">Preparing process and using spices are secrets handed over generation to generation within family.</s>
<s id="d52p1s4">After enjoying dishes, I just can describe as follows: the meat is soft, color is nice.</s>
<s id="d52p1s5">Sausages and grilled meat have good smell and soft.</s>
<s id="d52p1s6">And dish of steamed dog legs has unfor-gettable taste and smell.</s>
<s id="d52p1s7">Last dish o stewed bones with green papaya is really a specialty of the midland region.</s>
</p>
<p id="d52p2">
<s id="d52p2s1">Viet Tri’ people take pride in their popular gastronomy.</s>
<s id="d52p2s2">And I am sure that if you once visit Viet Tri you would be offered the delicious and special dishes.</s>
<s id="d52p2s3">Doan Ket Road is considered a center of Viet Tri Dog Meat with about 20 restaurants serving the dishes.</s>
<s id="d52p2s4">The restaurants have existed for many years but still in simple decoration.</s>
<s id="d52p2s5">The restaurant owners here confirm that well-decorated compartments and well-designed tables are unsuitable for enjoying Viet Tri Dog Meat dishes.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d53">
<head>Melientha suavis vegetable Xuan Son national park</head>
<p id="d53p1">
<s id="d53p1s1">Melientha suavis has been listed in Vietnam Red Book, and the most valuable vegetables among 300 edible ones in Xuan Son National Park.</s>
<s id="d53p1s2">Having favourable conditions of altitude, humidity and soil, Xuan Son National Park enjoys the biggest number of natural grown melientha suavis in Vietnam.</s>
</p>
<p id="d53p2">
<s id="d53p2s1">Melientha suavis is not only important in ecological diversity but also a delicious vegetable for human beings.</s>
<s id="d53p2s2">The top, leaves, flowers can be cooked in soup, while ripe fruits is edible.</s>
<s id="d53p2s3">The plants have economic values, medical usages, and also environment significance, because they can last hundreds of years, playing an essential role in reforestation procedure of the National Park.</s>
<s id="d53p2s4">Melientha suavis can be grown from seeds, or roots and introduced between and among reforested plants or spread between fruiting plants.</s>
<s id="d53p2s5">The plant is now scattered among other fruiting trees in Xuan Son National Park and neighboring villages.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d54">
<head>Doan Hung Pomelo</head>
<p id="d54p1">
<s id="d54p1s1">It is known that the all three regions of Vietnam share a common feature, i.e. possessing delicious grapefruit breeds.</s>
<s id="d54p1s2">Phuc Trach Pomelo is a specialty of sunny and windy Central region, while Nam Roi Pomelo is grown in fertilize land of South region, and Doan Hung pomelo planted in Doan Hung district of Phu Tho province is quintessence of midland area.</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p2">
<s id="d54p2s1">Doan Hung Pomelo also called "Phu Doan Pomelo" is well known with its special characteristics of small size; juiciness, sweet and soft taste and thin skin.</s>
<s id="d54p2s2">Today Doan Hung district boasts more pomelo breeds such as Bang Luan grape-fruit characterized by big size and yellow skin, hybrid plumose with big size and sour taste; La Hoang pomelo; and Suu pomelo is a rare breed and the first option of connoisseurs.</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p3">
<s id="d54p3s1">Perhaps, what makes Doan Hung pomelo special is its extraordinary fragrance.</s>
<s id="d54p3s2">During Tet holiday the fragrance of Doan Hung grape-fruit displayed in ancestors' altar can inspire a cozy family atmosphere.</s>
</p>
<p id="d54p4">
<s id="d54p4s1">Moreover, the pomelo planting has been improving people living standard.</s>
<s id="d54p4s2">Each fruit sent to every corner of the country represents the heart and soul of pomelo growers.</s>
<s id="d54p4s3">So Doan Hung Pomelo has a unique taste of simplicity but specialty.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d55">
<head>Hong Hac(Hac Persimmon)</head>
<p id="d55p1">
<s id="d55p1s1">Hong Hac (Hac Persimmon), a specialty of the ancestor land, was famous for being ranked in the first of five kinds of rare fruits dedicated to kings long ago.</s>
<s id="d55p1s2">Hong Hac is a pride of the ancestor land's people.</s>
<s id="d55p1s3">So far, many persimmon gardens in Viet Tri have life-size and hundred-year-old plants.</s>
<s id="d55p1s4">Unlike other persimmon, Hong Hac are of big size, squares shape, crispiness and sweet taste without seeds.</s>
</p>
<p id="d55p2">
<s id="d55p2s1">Newly-picked Hong Hac have first to be soaked in glazed terra-cotta jars with water taken from a stone well in Tien Cat Viet Tri city for three days to make them sweeter and crispier and more yellow.</s>
</p>
<p id="d55p3">
<s id="d55p3s1">Hong Hac is simple and natural as manner of the locals.</s>
<s id="d55p3s2">Cherishing a persimmon and peeling it with a sharp knife, one can feel the sweet fragrance, and elegant taste that seems to inspire the soul.</s>
<s id="d55p3s3">The freshness, crispiness and sweetness lasts for long time, leaving unforgettable pleasure.</s>
<s id="d55p3s4">Enjoying Hong Hac in the mid-Autumn party under the moonlight night is a wonderful and remarkable moment.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d56">
<head>Fresh Green Tea</head>
<p id="d56p1">
<s id="d56p1s1">Among dozens of tea products, Phu Tho people have choosen a simple and natural drink to serve friends and guests.</s>
<s id="d56p1s2">It is Fresh Green Tea.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p2">
<s id="d56p2s1">Talking about the fresh and tonic drink, everyone may suppose it was simply processed.</s>
<s id="d56p2s2">What you only need to do is to choose some dozens of fresh tea leaves rinsed in water and dip into in to a jar with hot water, and serve after 20 or 30 minutes.</s>
<s id="d56p2s3">It is right but not enough for the simple but elegant drink.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p3">
<s id="d56p3s1">Observing the way of enjoying fresh green tea of people here, we can under-stand the “tradition” of the gastronomy.</s>
<s id="d56p3s2">Choosing the tea plant for fresh green tea drink must be done with care.</s>
<s id="d56p3s3">To ensure the fine color and scent and sweet-harsh taste, you should choose tea plants growing in a hustle with others plants in forests.</s>
<s id="d56p3s4">The feet of trees are rough and as big as a house column, and leaves are sometimes too high to be picked.</s>
<s id="d56p3s5">If you like harsh taste, you should choose the trees growing in areas of sunlight.</s>
<s id="d56p3s6">While, if you like sweet taste, the trees under shadow is the option.</s>
<s id="d56p3s7">The best tea leaves are yellowish, with stable stems.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p4">
<s id="d56p4s1">Water making the fresh green tea is also selected proper resource.</s>
<s id="d56p4s2">There is something mysterious, each village has only one water source for making tea.</s>
<s id="d56p4s3">It is called Gieng Que (homeland well).</s>
<s id="d56p4s4">The fresh green tea connoisseurs use terra-cotta kettles to cooking tealeaves and cork the spout to avoid overflowing quintessence.</s>
</p>
<p id="d56p5">
<s id="d56p5s1">Sipping fresh green tea while chatting with friends is to ease the thirst during hard-working days, to feel home when being homesick and make the sweet-and-harsh taste in our memory forever.</s>
</p>
</div>
<div id="d57">
<head>Hotels</head>
<p id="d57p1">
<s id="d57p1s1">Hong Ngoc II Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p1s2">Address: 938 Hung Vuong Avenue, Tho Son ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p1s3">Tel: 0210.3862026</s>
<s id="d57p1s4">Conveniently located on Hung Vuong avenue, Hong Ngoc II Hotel takes pride in 100 rooms equipped with 182 comfortable beds and the best facilities.</s>
<s id="d57p1s5">Services such as massages, taxi, Karaoke, Asian and Western food, etc. are offered at the hotel.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p2">
<s id="d57p2s1">Hoang Long Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p2s2">Address: 2454 Hung Vuong Avenue, Tho Son ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p2s3">Tel: 0210 3952410</s>
<s id="d57p2s4">Also situated on Hung Vuong Avenue, Hoang Long Hotel has become one of the finest two-star hotels in Phu Tho with a total of 40 rooms, including 67 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p2s5">The hotel also provides convenient services such as: massages, Karaoke, etc.</s>
<s id="d57p2s6">A variety of food, from Western to Asian is served at four dining rooms which can accommodate 600 people.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p3">
<s id="d57p3s1">Ha Noi Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p3s2">Address: 2191 Hung Vuong Avenue, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p3s3">Tel: 0210 3849950</s>
<s id="d57p3s4">Ha Noi Hotel has diversified rooms with full modern facilities: 33 well - equipped rooms with a total of 57 beds; 2 spacious dining rooms consisting of 250 seats and one meeting room for 150 guests.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p4">
<s id="d57p4s1">Sinh Thai Hotel:</s>
<s id="d57p4s2">Address: Block 2, Van Co ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p4s3">Tel: 0210 3857324</s>
<s id="d57p4s4">Covering a total area of 13,000square meters, Sinh Thai Hotel is a perfect site for relaxation with 30 large bedrooms providing 72 enjoyable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p4s5">The hotel also boasts a large swimming pool, tennis - court, ecological lake for fishing and relaxing.</s>
<s id="d57p4s6">Western and Asian food are available.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p5">
<s id="d57p5s1">Cau Tay Hotel:</s>
<s id="d57p5s2">Address: Block 4, Van Phu ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p5s3">Tel: 0210 3954099</s>
<s id="d57p5s4">Sited in a total area of 2.000 square meters, Cau Tay Hotel features 30 spacious bedrooms set with 55 pleasant beds.</s>
<s id="d57p5s5">The hotel also provides massages services.</s>
<s id="d57p5s6">70 seats in two dining rooms are available with high quality Asian and Western food.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p6">
<s id="d57p6s1">Huong Giang Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p6s2">Add: Block 4, Van Phu, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p6s3">Tel.: (84-210) 3952 784</s>
<s id="d57p6s4">located in a total area of 10,000 square meters, Huong Giang hotel is well - equipped with 75 magnificent rooms and 135 pleasant beds.</s>
<s id="d57p6s5">A hall and a dining room are capable of housing 250 people.</s>
<s id="d57p6s6">It is also convenient for guests to enjoy messages services and taxi.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p7">
<s id="d57p7s1">Bao Chau Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p7s2">Add: Group 1A, block 1, Van Co ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p7s3">Tel.: (84-210) 3954919</s>
<s id="d57p7s4">Covering a total area of 1000 square meters, Bao Chau hotel consists of 31 spacious rooms featuring 34 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p7s5">A huge dining room and hall are spacious enough for 200 guests.</s>
<s id="d57p7s6">Massages services are available.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p8">
<s id="d57p8s1">Bai Bang Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p8s2">Add: Phong Chau town, Phu Ninh district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p8s3">Tel: (84-210) 3829351</s>
<s id="d57p8s4">Situated in an area of 56,000 square meters, Bai Bang hotel is one of the finest two - star hotels in Phu Tho.</s>
<s id="d57p8s5">It is a perfect 55-room hote with a total of 100 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p8s6">4 dining rooms are capable of housing 500 people.</s>
<s id="d57p8s7">Significantly, the hotel has separated villa satisfying the needs of relaxation for large family.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p9">
<s id="d57p9s1">BAPACO Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p9s2">Add: Phong Chau town, Phu Ninh district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p9s3">Tel: (84-210) 3829023</s>
<s id="d57p9s4">Set in a large area of 4000 square meters, BAPACO Hotel comprises 33 rooms with 46 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p9s5">The dining room and meeting room can serve a total of 200 guests, and a high standard swimming pool is in use.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p10">
<s id="d57p10s1">Hong Ngoc Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p10s2">Add: 1482 Hung Vuong Avenue, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city; Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p10s3">Tel: (84-210) 3829023</s>
<s id="d57p10s4">Hong Ngoc Hotel locates in a total area of 2000 square meters in the heart of Viet Tri city.</s>
<s id="d57p10s5">Being one of the most comfortable two - star hotels in Phu Tho, the six-storey hotel serves 75 rooms featured by 145 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p10s6">Massages and taxi service are available.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p11">
<s id="d57p11s1">Khanh Ly Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p11s2">Add: Group 33, Thanh Binh road, Thanh Mieu ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p11s3">Tel: (84-210) 3912588</s>
<s id="d57p11s4">The 7-floor hotel has been furnished with 22 spacious rooms and 41 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p11s5">The hotel's two large dining rooms can accommodate 150 people.</s>
<s id="d57p11s6">Specially, guests can enjoy music, tea and coffee as well as city overview on the 7th floor.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p12">
<s id="d57p12s1">Phuong Nam Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p12s2">Address: 1498 Hung Vuong Avenue, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p12s3">Tel: (84-210) 3845125</s>
<s id="d57p12s4">Covering a total area of 4590 square meters, Phuong Nam hotel takes pride in 39 bedrooms including 76 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p12s5">A dining room and meeting room can lodge a group of 600 people.</s>
<s id="d57p12s6">A variety of food, from Western to Asian is served.</s>
<s id="d57p12s7">Massages services are of great convenience.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p13">
<s id="d57p13s1">HoBiCo Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p13s2">Address: Group 4, Van Phu ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p13s3">Tel: (84-210) 3954089</s>
<s id="d57p13s4">The hotel consists of 22 large rooms furnished with 49 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p13s5">Especially, the hotel's house on stilts can take in 200 guests.</s>
<s id="d57p13s6">Located in a private location, the hotel can obviously ensure the relaxing and peaceful environment for guests.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p14">
<s id="d57p14s1">Dao Ngoc Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p14s2">Address: Thao River town, Cam Khe district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p14s3">Tel: (84-210) 3467829</s>
<s id="d57p14s4">Spreading over a total area of 3200 square meters.</s>
<s id="d57p14s5">Dao Ngoc hotel provides 30 bedrooms supplying 45 beds.</s>
<s id="d57p14s6">Massages service is available.</s>
<s id="d57p14s7">The hotel’s four large dining rooms can accommodate 400 guests with a variety of Western and Asian food.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p15">
<s id="d57p15s1">Minh Ngoc Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p15s2">Address: Group 1, Van Phu commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p15s3">Tel: (84-210) 3860868</s>
<s id="d57p15s4">The hotel features 20 rooms with 35 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p15s5">It also provides massages services and taxi.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p16">
<s id="d57p16s1">A Dong Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p16s2">Address: Group 1, Van Phu ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p16s3">Tel: (84-210) 3857279</s>
<s id="d57p16s4">The hotel includes 21 rooms with a total of 35 beds; it also provides massages services and taxi.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p17">
<s id="d57p17s1">Lo River Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p17s2">Address: Tran Phu Street, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p17s3">Tel: (84-210) 3843468/3846245</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p18">
<s id="d57p18s1">Labour Union Plaza Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p18s2">Address: 1594 Hung Vuong Avenue, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p18s3">Tel: (84-210) 3856567/3810888</s>
<s id="d57p18s4">The hotel was built with 11 rooms.</s>
<s id="d57p18s5">It is perfect hotel for the guests to join music clubs or enjoy coffee in an extravagant and relaxing atmosphere.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p19">
<s id="d57p19s1">Anh Dao Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p19s2">Address: Group 3, Km 5, Ha Loc commune, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p19s3">Tel: (84-210) 3760204/3760217</s>
<s id="d57p19s4">Making up an area of 5000 square meters, Anh Dao hotel provides 45 bed rooms consisting of 62 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p19s5">The hotel’s dining room and meeting room can host 160 people.</s>
<s id="d57p19s6">Massages services are available.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p20">
<s id="d57p20s1">Thien Thanh Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p20s2">Address: Thanh Son town, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p20s3">Tel: (84-210) 3611909</s>
<s id="d57p20s4">Making up an area of 5000 square meters, The hotel possesses 38 rooms featuring 49 comfortable beds.</s>
<s id="d57p20s5">4 dining rooms can accommodate 250 people.</s>
<s id="d57p20s6">Guests are welcome to enjoy natural views and fresh air; typical of mountainous area.</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p21">
<s id="d57p21s1">Thuy Tien Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p21s2">Address: Group 2, Van Phu commune, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p21s3">Tel: 0210.3210656</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p22">
<s id="d57p22s1">Tuan Hai Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p22s2">Address: Group 8, Phu Loc commune, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p22s3">Tel: 0210.3865021</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p23">
<s id="d57p23s1">Hoa Nam Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p23s2">Address: 64, Bach Hac ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p23s3">Tel: 0210.3861333</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p24">
<s id="d57p24s1">Huong Rung Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p24s2">Address: 8, Phu An street, Phong Chau ward, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho provinces.</s>
<s id="d57p24s3">Tel: 0210 3861333</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p25">
<s id="d57p25s1">Luu Thuy Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p25s2">Address: 114, Phu An street, Phong Chau ward, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p25s3">Tel: 0210 3820384</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p26">
<s id="d57p26s1">Song Vang Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p26s2">Address: Thanh Son town, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p26s3">Tel: 0210 3873378</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p27">
<s id="d57p27s1">Hai Nam Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p27s1">Address: 19/5 Bridge Group, Thuc Luyen commune, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p27s1">Tel: 0210 3611117</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p28">
<s id="d57p28s1">Van Xuan Hotel</s>
<s id="d57p28s2">Address: Group 12, Co Tiet commune, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p28s3">Tel: 0210 3794034</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p29">
<s id="d57p29s1">An Binh Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p29s2">Address: Group 8, Hy Cuong commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p29s3">Tel: 0210 2211553</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p30">
<s id="d57p30s1">Quynh Trang Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p30s2">Address: Group 6, Ha Hoa town; Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p30s3">Tel: 0915.614202</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p31">
<s id="d57p31s1">Tho Chinh Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p31s2">Address: Group 8, Ha Hoa town, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p31s3">Tel: 0915.883300</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p32">
<s id="d57p32s1">Anh Duc Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p32s2">Address: Administration area, Dau Lo, Doan Hung town, Doan Hung district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p32s3">Tel: 0210 3880558</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p33">
<s id="d57p33s1">A Dam Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p33s1">Address: Cau Dat area, Thanh Son town, Thanh Son district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p33s1">Tel: 0210 3873998</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p34">
<s id="d57p34s1">Nam Cuong Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p34s2">Address: Tan Tien area, Doan Hung town, Doan Hung district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p34s3">Tel: 0210 3881915</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p35">
<s id="d57p35s1">Ancient Hue Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p35s2">Address: Group 7, Thanh Minh commune, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p35s3">Tel: 0210 6212104</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p36">
<s id="d57p36s1">Song Thao Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p36s2">Address: La Phu commune, Thanh Th district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p36s3">Tel: 0210 3877473</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p37">
<s id="d57p37s1">Trang Anh Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p37s2">Address: Co Tiet commune, Tam Nong district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p37s3">Tel: 0210 3794002</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p38">
<s id="d57p38s1">Hong Lan Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p38s2">Address: Group 3, Ha Hoa town, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p38s3">Tel: 0210 3883242</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p39">
<s id="d57p39s1">Hoang Anh Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p39s2">Address: 76, block 4B, Hai Ba Trung Street, Tho Son ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p39s3">Tel: 0210 3911133</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p40">
<s id="d57p40s1">Hoang Loc Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p40s2">Address: Group 4, Ha Hoa town, Ha Hoa district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p40s3">Tel: 0210 3837900</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p41">
<s id="d57p41s1">Thanh Tra Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p41s1">Address: Group 9, Ninh Dan commune, Thanh Ba district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p41s1">Tel: 0210 3661040</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p42">
<s id="d57p42s1">559 Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p42s2">Address: Block 1, Bo Me group, Phong Chau town, Phu Ninh district, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p42s3">Tel: 0210 3827067</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p43">
<s id="d57p43s1">Nga Dao Guest House</s>
<s id="d57p43s2">Address: Group 4, Viet Hung Street, Ben Got ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province.</s>
<s id="d57p43s3">Tel: 0210 3862797</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p44">
<s id="d57p44s1">Hac Tri Fish Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p44s2">Address: Tien Cat ward, Viet Tri city,Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p44s3">Tel: 0210 3845 839</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p45">
<s id="d57p45s1">Hong Su Goat Meat Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p45s2">Address: Thanh Son town, Thanh Son District, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p45s3">Tel: 0210 3612600</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p46">
<s id="d57p46s1">Quang Hue Dog Meat Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p46s2">Address: Doan Ket street, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p46s3">Tel: 0210 3848616</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p47">
<s id="d57p47s1">Dai Phu Gia Sea - Food Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p47s2">Address: Thuy Van industrial zone, Van Phu ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p47s3">Tel: 0210 3954343</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p48">
<s id="d57p48s1">Xuan Tham Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p48s2">Address: Hong Ha street, Tien Cat ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province </s>
<s id="d57p48s3">Tel: 0210 3848415</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p49">
<s id="d57p49s1">Fish Restaurant Riverside</s>
<s id="d57p49s2">Address: Tien Cat ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p49s3">Tel: 0210 3846013</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p50">
<s id="d57p50s1">Hong Son Goat Meat Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p50s2">Address: Doan Ket Street, Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p50s3">Tel: 0210 3849464</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p51">
<s id="d57p51s1">Huong Bien Sea Food Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p51s2">Address: Tho Son ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p51s3">Tel: 0210 3858058</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p52">
<s id="d57p52s1">Noi Hien Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p52s2">Address: Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p52s3">Tel: 0210 3846625</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p53">
<s id="d57p53s1">Thanh Binh Dog Meat Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p53s2">Address: Gia Cam ward, Viet Tri city,Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p53s3">Tel: 0210 3847509</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p54">
<s id="d57p54s1">Phu Nam Sea Food Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p54s2">Address: Group 4, Van Phu commune, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p54s3">Tel: 0210 3955155</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p55">
<s id="d57p55s1">Huong Thuy Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p55s2">Address: Lam Thao town, Lam Thao district, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p55s3">Tel: 0210 3825014</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p56">
<s id="d57p56s1">Mountainous Trading Joint Stock Company Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p56s2">Address: Bach Dang Street, Au Co ward, Phu Tho town, Phu Tho province.</s> 
<s id="d57p56s3">Tel: 0210 3821329</s>
</p>
<p id="d57p57">
<s id="d57p57s1">Tinh Tam Vegetarian Restaurant</s>
<s id="d57p57s2">Address: Tien Cat ward, Viet Tri city, Phu Tho province</s>
<s id="d57p57s3">Tel: 0210 3840846</s>
</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>